<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport&st=text&r=0.137,0.75,0.143,0.152,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
>a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.
se metpractice is required to learn it and there
6, no incident roughness if the rules are
stictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr.
deyce is try to have other teams formed in the
symmasisme in the city and to have regular
entestn between them. It eomameade itself in
s it can be played in almost any sized room
den any had of lot. whether it be large or
mail, and that the number of player. need
only be limt. I b the size of the ground. It
bkings into play all maseles of the body. thus
being a healthy exercise, and at the same time
te a ws incidens to moet sports are want
1. The only apparatus neessary for the
oe to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball
mnd re half-bushel baskets.
movwr rT PL 6TD.
Theegh she courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Stan
aoprter witnessed a game of basket ball played
M the Carrer Institute on one of the evenings
of this week. The two baskets are attached to
th =anig strack at the opposite ends of the
gymmsam and U.s object of the game is to
Shen e heU in the opponent'e basket. The
uame consist of mine men each. made up of a
gaiheeper. two backs to assist him. a center, a
eight and left henter, two forward and a home
ma. They are arranged in this order from
Oe gnal whica they are defending. It is not
asessmry that the players thou!d remain in
teir glaces. but they should move in such a
way as to gie the forward player an oppo:
baesy Is gee a good tos at the goal or the
baecks to keep theer opponents from obtaining
so mmm by taking it from thea when they are
ghbntsto throw. It is the luty of the goal
ba~to beep the ball away fromi the vicinity.
etgoal. end it is more often neessary for
hi to bat the bail with his had tha for
e~er meambers of the seama to do so.
L. Serim. 3. leeward
4.ame.. eae...
4. Sm. .a.5
en.. ...s-....e.
The game is started by the teems lining up
ba their respseutve positions and then the
safeae tomes the ballian the air, It must not be
te.-d antal it strikes the ground. Thea the
players ean catch it. and the object of the one
who obtains it isto pass istso one of the players
ahis own sidec.who either passes itto inotherwho
msay be in a favorable position to tom f~ar goal
or else attempts to auake a goal himself. To
bee a foot bal into a basket euasiended ten feet
a cen SsA.av
beG airani eiasest lags en~t. held it.ie
net en eas messean means, end thee.
thanmy ethe at guat are madebut
as t ase -s eemtl, and e sensty
ohB~in meds. esnammty, an the
qshad esty. The haDeam be aoma
an ists with -n or beth --a-~
In bM the sesm s e 40 -a -e
e be h ss:
asmmmS he es h the det er hased
A e esms e with te hasb mUs
am thmm... ..a. a. he
Gotas o ben shile rmaI and Mas to stop
The har maw be held in ds baud The arms
Iee or bod soat not be used for blding it.
If h lb is beld for any length of time th
referee tess it into the air. as in the baegtnmg
of theam
o the5 ein, holding, J~n .trp, n
or striking b allowed. The t iafringem m
'f this rule eosnts a foal and a second dis
q"mli= a player, but, as in foot ball, a substi
tats may take his place.
IN TaN BAsKET. C
When a ball goes out of bounds it is put in
play in the same way as in a foot ball game.
The game consists of two halft of twenty
minutes each or such time as the captains may
decide on. and time is taken out for delays.
A goal counts three points and a foul one
point for the opponent. and a majority of the
points decides the game.
There are a referee and umpire, whose duties
are the same respectively as the same officials
in a foot ball game.
Any player has a right to get the ball at any
time while it is in the field of play. provided
that he handles only the ball and not the op
ponent.
ADVANTAGEs OF THE GAME.
To an observer the game seemed to be one
that will solve the problem, which has been a
knotty one for some time, of introdncing a
game which will meet the excitement incident
to most outdoor sports and at the same time
be suitable for indoor play. At present when
the outdoor season closes most of the athletes
drop tbe sports in which they have been in
terested and the benefits thev derived from
them are lost. This game is one that requires
skill and agility. but strength is not one of the
necessary factors. and, consequently. men of
all physical conditions can take part in it. It
has also been found to have been a useful
sport for girls and women, as it is especially
APTEn THE FALL.
adapted to securing good health without having
the nervous strain caused by some of the
sports now indulged in.
In its principli. it is a combination of foot
ball and lacrosse. It resembles foot ball in
most of the rulings, but in the method to be
pursued to obtain a goal the game more closely
resembles lacrosse. Although at first glance it
would hardly seem possible to have any amount
of team play in the game, still it is only by the
concerted action that a team can play to the
beet advantage. A novice in the game inva
riably feels disposed when he obtains the ball
to make a shot for the goal, which could not be
made from any distance one time in a hundred,
as in order that the ball should remain in the
basket it has to be skillfully and easily tossed,
not thrown. A good player will. when he has
the ball, quickly look for one of his own team
who is in an uncovered position to whom he
can tos it. In this way a well-drilled team
could almost entirely keep the ball from the
hands of a team made up of new men. Quick
ness of eye, hand and foot is one of the first
requisites for a good player, and he also must
keep his head about him. A moment's hesita
tion or a wrong pass may give considerable
advantage to the other side.
If an umpire is chosen who strictly follows
the rules of the game there is little chance for
any roughness, as running with the ball is
prohibited, and thus the injuries coming from
sharp tackling in foot bal are done away with.
The attention of the player is fastened on the
ball and personal feeling in the matter is lost
sight of. The object of each player when one
of his side obtains the ball is to place himself
in an uncovered position so that one of his own
team can pays it to him, while the opponents
should in this eae stick closely to the men
with whom they are paired so that a pass to
them would gave an equal opportunity for each
to catch the ball. It is in this respect that
cool-beadedt.euand quickness count. Idi
vidlual play on the part of one man will destroy
all the good work that the rest of the team may
do. If the game in played indoors in a gym
naisium the passee should be more of a toes
rather than hard straight throw.
As the game has apparently obtained a good
foothold in this city and as it is a healthful and
at the same times exciting sport it is to be
hoped that the efforts of Mr. Joyce to make the
game a popular one in this city will meet with
success, Some of the men under him are bo
conming quite proficient and before long he will
have a iirst-class team,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86088296/1893-06-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Indoor</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GAME OF BASKET BALL.
Interesting and Exciting Sport For Thos
Not Able to Exercise Kegularly.
The unnounceinent that at a woman's
educational institution not far from this
city tho students played a close and ex
citing game of "basket ball" wasperhaia
the first item which attracted public at
tention to a sport that is rapidly becom
ing very popular in this country among
those who have neither the physique nor
the taste for baseball or football. The
rules of the new sport are comparatively
simple, and the ease with which the
fundamental laws of the game can be
acquired in a few minutes' practice have
served to make it popular wherever it
has been introduced, while its freedom
from much of the roughness and intri
cacy of football has also tended to make
the devotees of basket ball enthusiastic
in their praise of its merits.
The name "basket ball" is derived from
the fact that scores are made not by car
rying the ball across the goal lines or
kicking it over the goal bar as in foot
ball, but by throwing the spheroid into I
a moderately small basket, which is hung
about 10 feet above the ground or floor.
To accomplish Buch a feat usually re
quires much practice, and as a rule tho
try at goals are far more numerous than
tho scores. Either hand or both hands
can be used in holding the ball, and it
must either he thrown or be batted with
tho open hand a punch with the fist or
arm, or a kick, constituting a foul.
The game differs from football also in
tho fact that no player is allowed to run
with the ball, but must stand where it is
caught, and a fair catch can be made
only with the hands. If the ball is held
for an unnecessarily long time, the um
pire takes possession of it and puts it
"ia play" by throwing it in the air, no
player being allowed to touch it in such
an event until it has struck the ground.
If a ball goes out of bounds, it is put in
play as in football, and no player is "off
sido," but every player has the right to
touch the ball anywhere or everywhere
in the game, provided the ball is in play.
No pushing, tripping, 6hoving or tac
kling is allowed, and every such offense
constitutes a foul, which gives one point
to the opposing nine. As a goal counts
but threo points and a foul one. there is
every incentive to avoid rough play. The
players advance the ball by tossing it to
some member of their own nine, and
there is the best opportunity for success
in personal skill combined with good
team play. The "forwards" and "cen
ters" usually toss the ball forward, but
when it gets dangerously near his own
goal, the goalkeeper often bats it with
tho open palm.
Ono advantago which basket ball has
over many other forms of popular sport
lies in tho fact that, while it allows 18
players to participate, it can be pursued
tho year round in tho open air during
tho warmer months and in the gymna
sium whilo cold weather prevails. Again,
basket ball can be played by persons
whose physique is not of tho most robust
type, although many athletes also have
found, in it a healthful form of exercise.
It has pypved of great value In furnish
ing exercise for business men, women
and children, as wpll as brawny students,
and from the general success it has al
ready attained wherever it has been in
troduced there is every probability that
basket ball will soon become a very popu
lar and widespread form of outdoor and
indoor sport. Boston Advertiser.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1894-11-25/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Sport+Game+Indoor+Outdoor&st=text&r=0.17,0.243,0.165,0.175,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text><BASKET BALL
JTHAMChGIVIXO GAlE 31ETWEEX
oPlioUORES AXD IRESllJIE
3 Iopular and Graceful Game bat
Has Foiinil Great Favor AnioiiK
Girls Some of the Rules nUll HeK
iilations Observed in PlajinK1 It
Basket ball is to tie womens col
lege what football is to the mens
The Bryn Mawr girls are particu
larly enthusiastic over this sport and
the Smith college students are in train
ing for a match game some day
Thanksgiving week
A picked nine from the sophomore
class will be pitted against a picked
nine from the freshmen class The
Smith college girl is immensely inter I
ested in basket ball which she also
calls cradle ball
1
I j
I
r
r
j
1DiUikct For IIKIOOM
Daslcct Vac Outdoor
L At Bryn Mar the students are
equally as devoted to this game in
deed their interebt in it is tremendous
and vies with 5 oclock teas and the
atricals in mitigating the ennui l of var
sity life The freshman and sopho
more classes are particularly alive to
this sport Miss Elsa Bowman is the
captain or the sophomores nine while
Miss Corlnne Putnam is the leader of
the freshman
WHY THE GAME IS POPULAR
The beauty of tne gameor one of I
I its beauties for it has manyis that II
it can be played by any number and
the more he merrier it is usually i
J
J voted The ideal number however is
nine on each side There is a goal I
keeper two backs to assist a center
a right and left center two forwards I
and a home man I e a woman in this
c1 TJ y
Tire accompanying diagram shows
the positions of the players
The end and aim of the game is to
toss a ball which is the size of a small
football into one of the two large bas
kets suspended at each end of the field
The winning side is the one that lands
the ball in the opponents basket The
basket is placed about ten feet high
When the game is played in the
gymnasium the basket Is bracketed to
tb side of the wall For outdoor use
it is supported at the same height by
au upright post The price of the bas
Jets or goals is 15 per pair for in 1
door use when supplied with a pipe
or post for outdoors the cost is some
what more The balls which are cov
ered with Jeather and about twenty
A four inches in circumference cost
about 3 each a rubbercoated ball
J can be purchased for 115 1
Basket ball can be played in a gym I
nasium in a large room or a small
b 1 HeW 01 a large field if in the latter I I
as many as thirty or fifty players may I
take part I
APPROPRIATED BY WOMEN I
The man who originated the game j
01 invented it or whatever the proper
word may be did not intend it merely
for amusement his idea was to pro i
vide a good allaround physical exer
cise and as such it cannot be im
P oyed upon combining as it does run
ning jumping bending pnd twisting
nearly every muscle and joint in the
body is brought into exercise
Mr James Naismith of Springfield i
Mass originated basket ball about
I
three years ago As soon as it became
known among the gymnasiums it
spread like an fclHdenfie Primarily
intended for young men for whom
most of the good things of life are in
tended it was soon taken up by young
women who declared that If there
was anything good in the game they
would like io become acquainted with
itThe
The girl forthwith bought a book of
rules which they masteredin very
brief order donned their gymnasium
ostumes and began playing at once
The fine points of the game however
Were only acquired by practice
I RULES OBSERVED
j The three players ivho are designat
ilL ed as forwards occupy the third of
the ground nearest the opponents
pwal the centers occupy the middle
third and the backs the defensive
third of the ground The forwards
of one team stand near the backs of
the other
Out of doors with plenty of room
the field may be 150 feet long the goal
lines running through the baskets per
pendicular to the length of the field i
the side boundaries 100 feet apart
The ball is put in play IJ by the icferee 1
throwing it up in the middle of the
field this is done at the commence
ment of the game at the beginning of
the second half after each goal and J
when a foul has been made The time
of play is two halves of twenty min I
utes each I
A goal is made when the ball is I
Yf thrown or batted from the ground into
the basket provided it stays in It is
a foul if the ball Is struck with the
I fijts or kicked
The ball must be held by the hands
fl
0
i
the arms or body may not be used for
I holding it
No pushing tripping shouldering or
striking is allowed infringements of
this rule count as a foul
The score is counted by points A
goal counts three points a foul one
point for the opponents A majority of
points decides the game/text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023253/1895-01-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Games+Sport+Baskets&r=0.354%2C0.788%2C0.735%2C0.391%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL.
Those who were interested in the
basket ball games played last winter
will be pleased to learn that the town
and school boys are tohaveonemore
battle for the supremacy. A word
about the game which has become so
popular in the past few years will
be interesting to those who enjoy
good honest sport.
Basket ball was invented in 1889 by
ames Nuismith, teacher in the interna
tional training school, Springfield. Dur
ing its first season it wasnot particularly
popular hut has gained in favor and may
now be called quite as important sport in
the Y. M. C. A. world as football and
baseball, but it is essentially an indoor
game and the interest that is excited in
an exercise confined to the gymnasium
can perhaps never equal the zest which is
thrown into a game like football, played
under the blue of heaven, in the fresh out
door atmosphere and sun's rays that seem
to penetrate the muscles ot the athlete
and impart added vivacity. However,
at the season when football bruises have
long ago healed and conquests on the
gridiron are matters for rumination, he
who sighs for the pigskin can find much
satisfaction in basket ball, it possessing
all the elements of football but, if rules
are enforced, lacking the excessive rough
ness. The ball used is perlcctly round,
made of a rubber bladder, covered with
leather and is about a foot in diameter.
Briefly outlined the game according to
official rules for 1805, is played as follows:
baskets especially constructed tor the
purpose, are placed in a vertical position
with the mouth ten feetlrom the ground,
one at each end of the field (gymnasium),
occupying much the same position in re
lation to the players as do football goals.
i ne competitive teams tane positions on
the field as in football, save that there is
no line-up, The teams are composed of
five men when the playing space is less
than 1800 square feet, seven when it is
more than 1800 and less than 3600 and
nine men when over 3600. The referee,
with a player from each side, takes posi
tion in the center. He puts the ball in
play by throwing it up. Which side has
first ball depends on which center man
secures it. The ball is not kicked or
struck with the fists but thrown or batted
with the flat of the hand and the object
is, to get it into the basket, doing which
scores a goal. On the number of goals
secured depends the victory. The net
work of rules which govern the action of
the game is quite as elaborate as football
and will not be given here. Suffice it to
say that spectators easily comprehend
its action. The putting of a ball into the
basket may seem a veryeasv thing to do
but as a matter of fact it is very difficult
to acomplish with the floor empty and,
of course, much more so when two teams
are at strife. One of the rules says that
the ball shall always be kept in motion.
Two twenty-minute halves are played
with a rest of ten minutes between "the
halves. This is the time of actual play.
Each side has itscaptain while position
is the same as in baseball. The referee is
judge of the ball. He is the superior offi
cer ot the game and decides all questions
uul ucuimciy lulling on me umpire, i lie
umpire is judge of the men, calls all fouls,
notifies the offenders and has power to
disqualify men.
The game which was to be played
on Thursdayevening of this week has
been postponed until Saturday even
ing. The two teams have been prac
tising faithfully and will be able to
play a very interesting game. It is
hoped that the public will turn out
and encourage the gymnasts, as all
the proceeds over and above the ex
penses are to go towards much need
ed new apparatus for thegymnasium.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-04-02/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Co-eds+Basket+Ball+Match+Basketball+Basket-ball+Teams+Team&st=text&r=0.651,0.558,0.294,0.313,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CO-EDS AT BASKET BALL
Secret Practice at Berkeley for
the Great Match on
Saturday.
Greek Letter Fraternities to Present
Plays Paul Revere Lodge
Was Honored.
BERKELEY, Cal., April I.â€” The Berke
ley Co-ed basket-ball team are ready for
their battle with the Stanford nine next
I Saturday. They have gone into secret
practice and are devoting their time and i
i attention to signal work and to giving
their muscles the hnal course of ex
ercise before they stand up against
the wearers of the cardinal. They
are ail on the gui vive, as are
j the other women athletes of the
i university, for the contest on Saturday
will be t*e first contest they have entered
for honors. "We have the reputation and
the athletic prestige of the university to
uphold," said one of the fairest members
of the team to-day, "and we are going into
1 the struggle with* the purpose of coming
i out victors. We realize the odds we will
have to contend against in not being in as
I good training as we might, and then the
Stanford girls are much more experienced
than we. At any rate we will do our best,
J since we have accepted Stanford's chal
i lenge."
Two or three of the young women have
the appearance of being overtrained,
judging from their pallid faces and worn
expression. This may be due, however, to
anxiety over the result of the came. Tlieir
new costumes consist of white sweaters
and blue bloomers with gold trimmings.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-12-18/ed-1/?sp=18&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+K+U+Naismith+Sport+Team&r=0.599%2C1.081%2C0.403%2C0.214%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL AT I U.
XKW BAJIE I.. CHKlT FA VII IX IX TUB
CLASSIC SHADES OF LA1VIIEACU.
How It I Plajeil The Tennis That
Ilnie Hern Formed The Fncnlty
Eiijoj- Ihe Game Clinncellur
Snow a. Crack Plnjer.
LAWRENCE. KAS.. Dec. 17.-(SpeciaU
The basket ball "fever" has broken out
In Its most violent form among Kansas
university people. Dr. Naismith. the new
physical director, brought the germs with
him, and that they were healthy specimens
is evidenced by their activity.
At first only a few of the students siw
in basket ball the diversion. But the dis
ease spread rapidly. Not only doe- eai h
class already possess its basket ball team,
but the literary and the scientific men of
the faculty are backing their "crack fives.
Eve-ry evening the gymnasium is filled with
a scrambling mass of humanity, and the
spectators who can recognlz. a friend or
acquaintance In the melee must be gifterd
with second sight.
Five men compose a team at basket ball.
The floor Is divided into three parts. Tho
center men of the plaving teams oe-upy a
space chalked off in the middle, am, the
other four dispose themselves In various
graceful attitudes in the end sections. The
referee tosses up the ball just above the
heads of the centers, who are standing
face to face. Each makes a jump and en
deavors to hit the hall, knocking it over
to his own men and toward his goal. Then,
the scramble begins. The accomplished,
and gentlemanly contortionist in the pat
ent medicine show could not rival basket
ball players In the way of tying French
knots in their corporal systems. The ma.-s
of writhing humanity turns over and over
in kaleidoscopic fashion, suddenly un
winds itself and is again resolved Into
parts. A man goes diving after the ball
and comos triumphantly up out of the
fray with his arms full of another man's
head! The aim In playing basket ball, so
it Is claimed. Is to throw the ball Into tho
round baskets, suspended at each end ot
the field, a greater number of times than
the opposing players. In reality, however,
it would seem that the cherls-hed object of
each plajer was to make as large and
choice collection of hruises as possible.
But that is basket ball from the specta
tor's point of view. To the players It Is
an all absorbing sport. Some of them
even have the audacity to assert that It Isi
a "gentle game, don't you know." Gentle,
indeed! One might as appropriately speak
of a bucking broncho as "well-mannered."
When the field Is not divided into sec
tions the game is reallr rough, but If thi
chalk lines are drawn, and fouls are faith
fully called whenever a man over-teps.
his boundaries, the bruise hunter adds to
Ills collection more slowly. It Is amusing:
to watch the players trying to remember
to have the proper respect for the bound
aries. Indeed It is truly pathetic to sej
what limitations of power a simple chalk
line can put on thee great, strong athletes.
In actual agony they har.g over the edge
and reach out helpless, longing arms to
ward the ball. Now and then an unruly
foot goes across the line, and then the
sharp whistle of the referee Is heard. A
foul entitles the players ort the otht.r side
a chance at throwing goal.
The game consists of two halves of
twenty minutes each. A twenty minute
rest is given between, and a new- team
put on to utilize the rest time. Each time
the ball goes Into the basket two points
are scored for the side whose goal Is
thrown As In baseball, a small score
Indicates a good game.
The Inventor of Ilnsket Hnll.
Dr. James Naismith Is the inventor of
basket ball. Unlike most of our games It
Is not the development of some medieval
sport. It was worked out on scientific
principles to meet a long felt want. Dr.
Naismith was physical director of a Y.
31. C. A. training school at Springfield.
Mass.. where the problem of supplying thlsj
need was brought to him for solution.
Busket ball was the result. It was In the
winter of 9I-52 that the game was intro
duced. The rules were made out and hung
In the "gym" fdr the inspection of playerj
before the game was ever tried. The men
were a little skeptical "at first about it.
but after the; ball was once thrown up no
coaxing was needed to Induce them to
Play. Basket ball came Into general favor
first through the Y. M. C. A. Having been
Introduced through the association it was
natural that it should spread through that
medium. Before long, however, colleges be
gan to investigate and adopt the game, ami
In the short .-pace of seven yeirs It has
gaimd a wide iopuhirlty. In the Eastern
colleges, both for men anil for womn.
basket ball Is the reigning favorite among
sports. The rules are not changed for tho
young women players, though doubtless the
game is played with a bit more tenderness.
Though at first sight the game appears
to be a free for all scramble. It soon be
comes evident that a number of sclentiilr?
,1'laya are iossibIe. Unfailing good judg
ment, anu goon muscular control are the
first requisites for a good player. The treat
ment of the ball Is the subject of several
rules. It can be tossed, rolled on Ihe floor
and pushed around, but must never In
kicked. There are no signals, and a play
lasts until the ball Is passed Into the basket.
Tennis In the 1'iilverslt jr.
The Kansas university men are going to
be great basket ball enthusiasts. Each
class has a picked team, and places on thei
teams are as much sought as on the var
sity eleven. Among faculty members thero
are two teams the Snow hall and tho
Frazer hall, representing the scientists and
the literary men. On the former team
Dr. WHHston. Marshall Barber. Clarenco
McClung. A. H. Clark and Dr. Naismith
hold positions. Their opponents are A.
G. Cantield. AY. H. Carruth. E. M. Hop
kins. M. W. Sterling and Archie Hogg.
On Tuesdays and Thursdays at 3 p. m. thesj
distinguished individuals lay aside their
dignity and their collars, don sweaters anil
pugilistic airs, and come forth into the
arena to dw battle. With a grace that
is acciuired only through long years of
bending over desks and laboratory tables,
they scamiier now here, now there, after
the elusive canvas sphere.
When the faculty teams met for their
last practice. Chancellor Snow- appeared.
He was Immediately besieged to play. The
chancellor protested that he was too green,
but such fetching invitations could never
be turned dotvn. The head of the universi
ty disappeared Into a dressing room, and
In a few moments, he emerged In a cos
tume of which the most noticeable feat
ures were- white canvas shoes, a seraphic:
grin, and a neutral tinted sweater. With
characteristic vigor he attacked the game,
and before long he was the champion play
er. There is nothing slow about the chan
cellor when he gets into action.
Tournament in January.
On January 13 an Indoor tournament will
be given. Basket hall will be the chief
feature of the c-xhihltlon. The old skat
ing rink on Kentucky street will probably
be rented for the occasion. Dr. Naismltii
says he enjoys working with college men
far better than with others. He believes
there is no artificiality whatever about e-ol-Iege
students. "If a man is a man they
will respect him and his endeavors in their
behalf." he says, "but they won t Stan. I
trilling a minute. When I find it yo'ing
fellow who kicks on the referee's decision-..
I just ask him n call fouls for a few mo
ments. After he has called a few and other
men have kicked on his rulings, h,. never
kicks again."
Pr. Naismith has much influence t
the young men in his charge. In Mrs. Cora
McColli,m Smith he has an able colleague.
The revolution In feeling which a few yearn
have brought about among the physical
culture students Is remarkable. When the
training was first Introduced about four
years ago and the girls lirst donned their
suits, the presence of a man within a ra
dius of three blocks wrought the most
awful consternation. Now men pass back
and forth throuch the r-vm to and from
the laboratory during the girls" cla.-aes and
ni'liing is thought ot it. Before long :hi
g.rls will trv basket ball. too. Equal suf
frage in ainietirs is one oi me cnarms of
Kansas university. Visitors to Lan-rem-o
must get a basket ball guide beforehand and
lecrn tne nngo. it tney wis.i to dd able to
converse intelligently with university peo
nle. for that is the all absorbing rnnle re
the day. It may not be a great while. Judg-
i hi; iruiii uiijjemuiii e ueioic processors
will be whistling students down in their
recitations and -allInc "foul" when thir
make mistakes in their translations, so
jreai is cue iiiuiience oi iiaoit</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92053934/1904-11-19/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Rules+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Dribble&st=text&r=0.506,0.568,0.197,0.21,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW RULES ON BASKETBALL
Changed Conditions For Championship
Contests.
Up to the present the basketball
rules have been amended each season
by additions and omissions in various
places. This year, however, the rules
have been rearranged and many rules
bear different numbers and are not
found in the same successive order.
An advantage in the new rule book
also is that at the top of the page i3
the page, so that it is no longer neccs-
indicated the rule number printed on
that page, so that it is no longer ne
cessary to turn back or forth to ascer
tain which rule is being read.
The first new feature is that the
rules became effective Nov. 1, 1904.
This settled a fixed time for everywhere
and did not leave it open for teams to
play old Ule3 because "they did not
have the new book and there is noth
ing in the rules saying when they be
come effective," In referring to the
basket, the word "basket" is not used
in contradiction to "goal."
The minimum size of playing space
(2,400 square feet) is omitted in rule 1.
section 1. Rule 3, section 1, requires
a background of wood at least three
quarters of an inch thick for the bas
kets. Screens are no longer permitted.
The paying of the officials expenses in
serial championship games is no longer
mandatory.
An important change in rule 11, sec
tion 10. prohibits more than one player
of each team from tackling the ball at
the same time. A "dribble" is now
only counted such when the player ad
vances more than two steps wtiile roll-
UDUDDDDGBD
You can eat anything, digest it and
enjoy it if you give your stomach a
thorough course of treatment with
Dr. laber's Pbpsin lompouna.
Perhaps your stomach is over
worked and accumulates undigest
ed matter whici ferments and up
sets the entire system, causing
belching and bloating, bad breath,
a languid, weary feeling, sleep
lessness, etc.
T&ESER'SIEEEMMlGOrJlFOUnD
cleans out the refuse, heals the irritated secretive linings of the stomach, stim
ulates an activity of the digestive fluids and tones up the entire tract. Blood is
pure when digestion is complete. Dr. Taber's Pepsin Compound produces
perfect, healthy digestion. 9
TABLETS, 10c, 25c, 50c. at drug stores. Uquld Form, 50c. and $1.
KTKZPMTK? To prove its merits, we will send sample
m mmwtmmm package by mail. Free, to any address.
DR. TABER MFG. CO., Poorto, Ills.
ing or bouncing the ball.
The rule that in a dribble both hands
shall not be used simultaneously more
than once is still effective. Under rule
11, section 17, a man is not out of
bounds if only one foot is outside.
Players may be changed at any time
during the game (new rule 1, section
26). Last year's rules as well as the
new rules authorizes the referee to
award one point to the man fouled by
an opponent while trying for goal.
There was some doubt formerly as to
whether the team whose player was
fouled should also have a free throw
for goal.
The uew rules add that "this shall
noi interfere with a free throw for goal
from foul line," thus making It pos
sible to secure four points on this olio
play, if while being fouled the player
throws the goal, two points are scored,
oue point is awarded by the nfere
aud the ilayer is allowed an additional
free throw for the foul giving him uu
opiiortunity of scoring one point moro
if he throws the foul goal.
Under the old rules if a player threw
for goal from outside and missed thu
basket the ball went to the center,
while under the new rules the ball con
tinues to play. r
Under rule 12, section 1 and 4. tho
referee is required to promptly dis
qualify any player using profane or
abusive language.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble&st=text&r=-0.198,-0.266,1.395,1.395,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOO MANY fOijl Fo1ftjj l
IN BASKET BASKETPresent 1 1Present
Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
l
BY ELWOOD S
BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
r
bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
etEd ujxi np
entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
cs
ginger s and In i inn
general Generl makes the thean ui uin
an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
rather than good team work l lluther
luther tem a aacular
tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
I Iblame
or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
fou
opponents opponent much more than is nee
Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
are called caled for holding tripping A
tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
fnc
offenses but tepresnt preSfnt ytm o t
ing i ng a foul on someone somenp Eo V er TV tini tinimen tn
men i touch each other evry fr tltneTj Hme tln
moves an Inch and Vnn l
every timf time timearm 1m 1marm m marm
arm arm gets part way around an uppcEeni I
dead ded wrong and Is spoiling spiing th UPJt gas ga b
gl
loge lee rules rule permit permi a great deal more f
teal moe
dom of play pIn than do the A A f TL TLto i aD
The college dribble rule
colege permitting a
to throw the ball In the th pritn air or roll k i I t tthe
the floor take ta1t any number numbfr of steps stei rol t
catch it and try for or a baskft bkft i i is isone steP M I f JM1 JM1one
one The A A I r rules rul s make it a I dl
for a man to take more than two tw i vl t i
in a dribble In regard resrd t to the therule pror
rule rle a man running at full ful speed p us r rnecessarily l lnecessariy
necessarily necessariy take an extra step spe or orand uj i1 r rand
and his momentum usually usual bring brjn brjnar bringsarm jjr
arm ar in contact contct with wih his opponent L P Pspite
spite of the fact fac that tht the opponet rules rule saylL sy say
lowance Jownce shall shal be made md for a man mancatches r rcatches
catches the ball while whie on the run ru runare f fare Etj Etjcatches e eare
are invariably called caUe If a man eve evemuch t evemuch r
much as takes a small smal extra step stepCauses 1 1much t t tt tCauses
Causes Many Fouls FoulsAnother fra fraAnother
Ie IeAnother
Another rule that causes cU trouble Sa is Iiwhich SMJ bb bbhic
1i
which hic says sas putting puthI one ant or both bothabout i1 if ifthis
about an opponent cnsttutes constitutes arc arcThe a 1
The strIct Interpretton interpretation now OW applir i
apPl
this rule Ie causes c es more fouls tojle tojlew to be bethan bethan
than other and th the
any makfS g gslow 1 1s10w
slow w and uninteresting uninteretng M Mhave Many Tfn rnet g
have been suggested suggeste by different diftrfnt b bbal bat DSL
ball bal authorities authortes and there therp is i no douWt5 doub dOUbfethat
that the next rule book bok will wi show showeffect how howffcct T1 T1effect
effect of this agitation agItaton Manager Managtr OTT OTTT O T
the Crescents suggests that in ordf ordfsave orrf orrfsave r t
save time and in order to maka the post postwon por porwon
won on fouls a less los Important Imprtant fartc fartcdeciding faC faetrdeciding p
deciding a game that a man fouled fouledhe fou1e fouledtry
tr try a tree throw ge from tht the spot on w whe t the
he was fouled arguing arging that there therebe w i I Iplayer f
be no running to a certain lne line th tbx tbxplayer tU
player would have less chance to toa ri ria 1
a free throw that the throws wouW wouWquently woWdquently
wou
quently quenty be long ones one and that this thiswould ts tswould thuwould
would lend a spectacular clement Clement ta tagame Iigame
J
game I do not favor this rule rule bK bKwhen 1wJ b bwhen
when a guard gard was fouled foulEd under IB IBponents b bi bironents
ponents onen1s basket he would ould bfi so far is isMs t this
Ms hI own basket that a successful succesful tt ttwould t ttiitz ttiitzwould 2
would be almost impossible Impslblp an4 an4would ad an anwould f3i 1 1would
would encourage forwards forwads to foul foulguards fou f fguards
guards with impunity impunityNeutral impunityNeutral impunityNeutral
Neutral Men for Officials OfclS OfficMlsThe I IThe
The Canadians Cnadians have a system irtkj irtkjsatisfactory wt0 wt0satisfactory b
satisfactory satsfactory providing the officials officialsneutral oWc iU iUneutral
neutral which is not very ver of ofen often tenths te the OH OHIn t tt ttIn
In Canada the instant a man is A Athe t iit iitthe 1
the referee blows his wnistlP wnlst tM tMkeeper t tI t tkeeper
keeper awards one point to tho oifesei oifeseiteam oKftteam
team and without further delay dela on tb t w wIs Jt JtIs t tis
Is thrown up between the te two B Ilt10opponents i iopponents ot
opponents and the game gae goes on onscheme on onscheme o oscheme
scheme would ould be good with absoBM absoBMneutral abot abotneutrl abeOneutral
neutral neutrl officials oftclals but under this systts systtsan z syltean et
an official was the uner least l ot bit bi partial partialcould partiatlo partiatlocould
to pUO pUOcould
could swing a a close game either vrtft vrtftI m s1lth s1lthI ti
swng
I favor a rule which gmo provides that thatneutral trhp trhpevery thaJb thaJbevery
every match game the oficia officials sh S1ItdS S1ItdSneutral Uls Ulsneutral
neutral men and gme shall sQl be speciflcaDrs speciflcaDrsstructed speccUS specIflcaU3tructed f
structed to use their judgment judget as aswhether 8 83whether
whether or not the foul was wa wasintentIonally comm cr t tintentionally d T TIntentionnlv
intentionally Intentionnlv This I think tink would wuld wouldthe 5T 5Tthe rthe
Tl
the situation sltuat n The T1e trouble doesnt doet doesntmuch t tmuch 1 n nmuch
much in tho rules themselves themselvCB nUb alt nUbsome r rsome 11 11some
some of them th m are too tight tght bat ba in I1ttl I1ttlpresent 11 11present t tt ttpresent
present close interpretation Interpretaton and a andgeneral it itgeneral r rgeneral
general rule rlo cose was a inserted allowing aUowmgclals e eCJUIS Ccials
clals CJUIS a a ltte little 11LUW more 1UUIO use not u of thfir their fcii ii iiment own 3 3ment
ment and providing always that OW tHJi tHJiabsolutely thtf thtfabsolutely
absolutely h neutral neutrl men the game gamebe TT TTwithout
absolut be greaty greatly ben bencfited fited I It Is impos imposplay 1mposshb 1mposshbplay go r
play a gae game as fast a as bket baskethd1 baskethd1In
in such 3 a Umled limited space 2f as 0 a gn gnwithout gynin gyninwithout
without having scores score of foulsfinato1 foulsfinato1der touls mflI mflIder
der the strict stict interpretation Interretion of mht tha thaUUl t a abut r r rbut
officials would refrain fm fromIng
but UUl 11 It uUbiaio oficials refrn w III 1 1Ing
ing fouls which in iio io o way IirJurtv IirJurtvchances h1u in1urO in1urOchances
chances for either team tem for scoriTig Bcong Bcongwould scofl8would w5 w5would
would bo dono to elmnate eliminate toul troubl</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1908-12-06/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Strategy&r=-0.02%2C0.466%2C0.631%2C0.336%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket Bail JBailStrategy Baili all allStrategy
i Strategy StrategyBy
i
By DR DRJMiES JAMES NAISMITH NAISMITHFather
Father of the Game GameCopyright GameICoprlght190S Gameicopyright
Copyright ICoprlght190S 190S bi Joseoh B IL Bowles1NEW Bowles Bowles1NEW
1 1NEW NEW ELEMENT S IN THE GAME
I was AI ar forded rded the honor of ofth ofth ofng
t
th game of basketball ba ketbal1 some somears somen somerar5 me mering
n ng
elements elementsicn
many new
ring ago
were remotest in my m mind mindno mindowr
y ten icn
owr nr into no the winter pastime PMtUnea
g field ld for effort If IfJtassarhusetts ItfrIends IfE Ifyllass
new ne
CD a
E Jtassarhusetts yllass yllassa rice friends t then had told toldien toldhe
hen he that a quarter of o a a century centuryatuetes centurati1etes centurye
atuetes would be planning planningand er erlt eft e
lt t manners of attack and on defense defenseconceiving defenseonceiV se seconceiving
conceiving onceiV ng schemes schemes of play lay to toHer toIder
Her and hoodwink opponents I Ihave It
d t have doubted but such suchcome events eventst eventscom
t come com to pass Year by year ear the theor
or for plays of new variety Is Isbring IslIng
bring stronger and the thee mortel more In Ine InIe
Ie e the better liked d by b coaches coachesI
I have pet et about aboutes to tell you youPS youhave
PS S fans and players alike alikee alll lr lrt
e f t center your our efforts how to tost tot tost
st t your plays to the best ad adage adedurlng ads
age during s the progress of plan plays playswhere plaRwhen
where to direct your our attack attackscience in ingame 10J1me
game where strategy and science scienceUidoing scienceJwiClln se sei
Uidoing i themselves themselvesthe thEmS lves lvesthe
the spectator tator who watches basketplay basket basketplay basketpIa
play pIa for the privilege of Indulging Indulgingcsasies Indulgingrstasles Indulgingrstasies
csasies over the wild movements movementsermoving movementsermoln movementsermoving
ermoving legs arms and Indoor Indoored
ed muscles the science n of f abth the theie th the e ee
ie e oustltutes itself in scoring sco scoarcuracy 1e leather leatherre abil abilarcuracy abllaNuracy
arcuracy In lodging the leather leatherre
re within the net nete
e Till 111 endeavor to demonstrate demonstrater
r t c science of this game gameability lies in inutility inabIJit
utility abIJit o M th tho guards forwards ana anaer
er to nork up to a highly em emit effipdnt e epclnt
it pcnt m the movementsede movements which whichIe
tde Ie the hl efforts at goals goalsese
ese irtKlfs lrt df les on Basketball Strat Strattherefore Stratthenfore Strattherefore
therefore will deal eal with the thea
a of the players about the floor floorsslng fioorsslng floorasing
sslng of the ball and the most mostre mostt7e mosttse
re manner of puzzling oppo oppoby oppoby oppuby
by a series of plays To start starttake starts
as s take the play which has has2e ha hae
2e e known as left forward to toforward toforwar toforward
forward In left forwards posl postof poslOf poslOf
Of course your our team must musta
a set of signals which are easily easilyed ea l1y l1yl
ed l They may be number signals signalsed
ed to the players by b the captain captainhe
he 11 e team or they the may ma be silentq silent silentjr
jr q In the rase tEl of number slg s1gtie slgtlie sl slthe
the same course Is I pursued as asused asused II IIUed
used In football For Instance Instancethe
the accompanying diagram Sup Supthat Supthat Supthat
that the series of numbers whlcn whlcnthe whlcnthe whichthe
the direction of the play Is the thed
d ottered by b your our captain Tour Touril
il I for the play pia left forward to toforward tof toforward
forward f in left forwards pos poswould poslwould post postwould
would be b 26 312 88 The cen cennamber cennumber cennumber
number being 3 the ball leaves leavesto leaveto
to go to the left forward whose whosen
n rat Is I while the last player to tove tovs
ve 1 the ball before the shot at the theIs
Is attempted Is the right forwardla forward
la o a2 a2ou 2
roJ ou may rea use us a movement of the thec th thc
c foot to Indicate n w certain play playnrtr pia playthe
nrtr 1 the th man who gives the 81 stdgnil e elsnal 81R1
lsnal R1 1 must give It unconcernedly unconcernedlyat
at It t nay 113 not be noted by b op oprts opt oprtt
rts rtt t and arc Dr made use u e of to advantage advantage1s
aftl aftlIs aftela
1s e placing of players imme immefly
fly 11 after the completion of the theKbJh thehl1 thevLh
KbJh proves especially effective effectiveIts
Its h accompanying diagram the theare theare theare
are idle Idl If the center of the therepresented tllorepresented therepresented
represented as the aggressor aggressortie o
tie t e jump on his opponent and ands
it t s the ball in the direction hull indiby Indlb hullby
by b the captains signal In this thishft thishe thisthe
the centef slaps the sphere to toeft toeft toe
e eft t Fide where the th left forward forwardes
jves es It and shoots It back to the theforward thefonard theforward
forward who ho In the mean meanhas meanhas meanhas
has taken up a position to the theff ther
ff r the basket from which he tries trlesn triesgoal
goal goaln 011
n 1 the truly tml scientific part of the theimation theinaUon theination
imation takes place The center centerJumping centerjumping
Jumping spurts for a position to togh
IgM gh side of the basket while the theoarl1 theorward
forward having handled the ball balla ballthe ballthe
a the goal tosser secured it iti it itI
i a bee line for a point directly directlysnt directl directlJnt
ant of the basket basketstudying basketstudying basketstudying
studying the accompanying dta dtayou dla1Cu dtayou
you can readily see what an ex exit
it t defense f this makes providing provldlnrlg
right rlg t forward falls In his hi effort effortii
ii the ball within the net You Toucovered YouQered YouCowered
covered every point toward which whichaU
HI uay bound as it caroms away awa
the goal It Is then up to your OU
to 0 leap into the air and again at atR atn
n R goal go L it is a noticeable fea feajjnat
jjnat that in this or any an other play for for2rertne forltter
2rertne ltter the plan Is for every ee play p1nrlose
lose his opponent and to do 110
mast aromplish a ompllsh his part partof of the thein
Ina inatlon J2A0rn Ion from a point T lnt otl other er than
in n which
he places himself at the
m the referee to tosses les es the sphere
the centers at the start of theId the thepostnjr held
ld tie e OPposing oPPOsi postnjr renter leap Into Intothan
higher than your our center thus thust t11UI t11Uthe
g the ball
toward the opponents opponrntst opponrntsItmalnl s
I it
t t mains ln for y your our ur guards flrtls to toi tosphere toSphE
the
i sphere SphE IE and follow out Ute UteI UteslgnajEd tlioEvery
as slgnajEd
Every move must mustId
I e VitI itJi the
utmost
celerity elerlt The
Id to revive rl rerelve hE the ball from the theBtinrt
Btinrt must takE ke It on n the run and the
I under thn
basket should do the theSll00t
aid shoot hoot for the goal ool before beforer b rOrp
r cress n L 1 baR R st stopped PPed and the pnr pnru pnrth pl1redgunrd i w
edgunrd guan of th the opposing team teamte
ed Wm to u
te block his hl s pass passBm past pasdiagram ar arthe s
t diagram Bm to the thear richt isthe Is Isthhe s stje
thhe the play pla ay reversed rever red that isthri Is IsIn
In thri the e right ght forward orw to left for
right gri
forwards poMtlop poMtlopcoverlnsr JJn tlo The
1es naes for covering th the bound of
i 1
following a nol THMwlbl tfbl faUiirc falllJTII
Pan pa of the
I jroalshootine for fornbseri
ree also Iso nbseri obsenet the th poMMon M c Hons of ofthe q qI qmEn
mEn used beln r l
I erte er erWI
tinat WI Jt hive f Cn cousidemi ld th the
w nho
wa srn rt the first trijght to
t at a t the t r
nt opening enln of each fac lCll CPaco RSn RSni RSnPnrnnr t
i nraTnr to ail 11 M 1 the ther pinvrr I ht
InS n
r J1ni s sfrr l11r
for a tMII rritePln Uln
ba bai 111 thr fIt T 1 e a ctrrs 111 e t1
career a TPer ends wi retn t th tht
eaylslte alslt alsltI p anti thlO
I IAltnot 11 n oy
n and 1In other I tl
1P1 manner thsn th n ht
i se nO for 1r
I L v pehns h nII 1Itt1 t u uon ts
r11tt It I
lefro Pcr H
Trio mstrlt t11 t11bap qm qmwind
bap wind n hsnt 1 env tI NJul NJulII r
season aon on onaccp t tra
bar coact
II an 1 1p 1fn n
season fn is I t
p ha5kethol thU thUntlnT1 1
ParHrlpntlnn ntlnT1 t
r en t tu
al alt6 aids In
n pot
t6 hr at t1 r
Tl d
t rsieal si a 1 rott en ait v h hn t ti rl
rhhh l hI
1 i npCIo t t to toar hr hro n
o I mAnn of t tIftlatJ
ar T t n
IftlatJ rOI11 onr plA plAaCCount
accp aCCount nt for this by b de
daring Iarin that different lffer nt sports bring dif different dtferent dlfferent
ferent sets of muscles into play pll and inconsequence In Inconsequence Inconsequenco
consequence the start of the basket
ball season finds some parts of th thplayers tile tlieplayers tilepl1ers e
players machinery maclilne weakened lay bymonths laymonths b bmonths
months of Inactivity But basketball basketballuses
uses every 6VC1 muscle of the body bod anrt anrtthat anr1that an anthat
that continuously Hence the lunsjc lunsjcand lunljand lunyand
and heart have a heavier hea Ier part to play plaIn piain k t
In purifying the blood and building up uii uiithese tr trthese
these unused muscles AX s soon u uthe aM aMthe uthe
the athlete ath etc begins to get into basket basketball baskctball basketball
ball trim these muscles are strengthened strength strengthened strengthened
ened he breathes easier when dashln dashingabout dashlnabout dashlnabout h
about the basketball floor and con constant constant constant
stant exercise puts him In shape for forhard u uhard ahard
hard season seasonThe seasonThe ea80nThe
The basketball player also needs needsa 5
a stomach which is not susceptible susceptibleto
to hard Jolts That Is a xequisttwhich requisite requisitewhich requisitewhich e
which cannot be neglected If the play player pla plaor
or intends to put forth his best ener energies ln s sgies r rgles
gies Sweet stuffs coffee alcoholic alcoholicbeverages alcol101lcbevcrages alcohollbeverages c
beverages tobacco pastry I1ast and late latehours latehours lathours e
hours must necessarily be blacklisted blacklistedAlo
Also before practice and games the theathlete theathlete th thathlete
athlete should eat lightly and of food foodswhich foodwhkh foodwhisk
which contain the largest I amount o onourishment or ornourishment ornourishment f
nourishment In the smallest buk bukIn bukIn bulkIn
In future articles we shall outline outlinemore outlinemore outlinmore P
more plays which arc absolutely es essential e eentinJ ersentiaL
sential and when len these are Impressed Impressedwill impressewill
will add what coaches recognize rcc gnlze a afeature ni nifeature aifeature
feature plays that is combinations combinationsout 5
out of the ordinary run which added addedto add lt ltto t tto
to the repertoire of teams Rive a va varied vavied n nrled
vied and complicated style of attacand attack attackand attackand k
and defense</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1913-11-30/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Basket-ball+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Code+Amended+Sport+Game+Intercollegiate&st=text&r=0.219,0.33,0.279,0.297,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET-BALL
Dr. Sharp e Takes Side of
Player at Intercollegiate
Meeting.
LEAVE OUT ROUGHNESS
Too Many Tecnnicsfities It Claim of
Coaches and Players New
Role Affects Centers.
New York, Nov. 29. Exception to the
trend of collegiate Icglsla ion was voiced
In no uncertain terms at the annual inter
pretation .neetlng of the Intercollegiate
basket-ball rules committee at the Hotel
Astor yesterday afternoon Dr. A. II.
Sharpe, coach of the Cornell football,
basket-ball, and baseball teams, took the
side cf the plajer and coach against the
rules committee, which, he said, was con
cerning itself more with ruling on tech
nicalities than on the practical issues of
the game.
The discussion arose when Dr. Joseph
E. Ray croft chairman of the rules com
mittee, and the presiding officer, called
for the consideration of Rule 11, which Is
designed to penalize blocking. The rule
had been amended over summer so that it
read: "A player is entitled to take any
position on the court but if in taking a
position he faces an opponent or makes
bodily contact with an opponent so as to
interfere with the latter's progress he
Is blocking."
Dr. Raycrott said that the change had
been made In the rule 'as part of the
general plan of the rulemakers to elim
inate all unnecessary roughness and com
pel the plajers to "play the ball and not
the man." By this rule, said Dr. Ray
croft all Illegal Interference with a play
er by his opponent resulting from the
close guarding of pla, would be deemed
a foul and penalized as such.
Dr. Sharpe carried his point because.
when the discussion had been concluded
and a vote taken on the Interpretation of
the rule Dr. It ay croft and Ralph Mor
gan, of the University of Pennsylvania,
secretary of the committee, agreed to
permit an editorial correction which sub
stituted an "and" for the "or" in the
rule in question, making it mean that
only by direct bodily contact can a player
block his opponent
The most important changes In the rules
forthe coming year have to do with the
"Jump" ball and the ball when It goes
out of bounds. In order to eliminate the
fouling that so frequently happened under
the old Jump rule, the players Jumping
for the ball now, either In the center or
on any part of the floor will have to
Jump with one hands behind the back.
The meeting ruled that b behind the
back was meant behind any part V the
back below the shoulder, with the hand
touchihg the back, rather than the strict
working of the section, which compelled
the player to have on hand behind the
back at the waistline.
The other rule regarding the Jump ball
was aimed to do away with a great many
of the "Jumps" along the sideline after
the ball has been out of bounds by giv
ing it to the opponent of the man last
touched by It The rules relating to
dribbling were also discussed, but no rul
ing was made.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1930-12-28/ed-1/?sp=6&q=basketball&r=0.095%2C0.51%2C0.774%2C0.412%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> BASKETBALL
_ PlAVS^ PLAYLPS
Fine Gyms Make Basketball Second Only To
Football In Popularity
BY EVERETT S. DEAN
Basketball ('each. Indiana l'.
Basketball is recognized in most
of the country as the second major
sport. Its progress has come about
solely on its merits. Proximity of
the crowd to the players lias made
it possible for the crowd to experi
ence thrills which go with speedy
action more than in any other
j sport.
Pine gymnasiums and field houses
in many states are real testimony
I to the popularity of basketball. De
mand for seating space has led
larger towns to build gymnasiums
With seating capacities of 4000 to
5000. F.ne field houses with seat
1 ing capacity from 8000 to 15.000
have been built to meet the college
demand. Outstanding basketball
plants of the country are the
I Palestra at the University of
Pennsylvania, and most of the field
houses of Big Ten schools. The
Indiana State High School Basket
ball Tournament is played each
i year before 20.000 fans and offers
a great spectacle to sportdom.
Schedule making and tournament
f play in high shools have been
regulated by state athletic asso
ciations to the extent that high
school basketball is on a sounder
basis than ever before. Schedules
once consisted of 35 games, which
were too many for the high school
boy. In some states 18 to 20 games
now make up the schedules. The
strain of long tournaments has
been avoided by spreading tourn
aments over a period of three weeks
j instead of two.

Uniform officiating is another
sign indicating progress. Officiating
I
North, South
Elevens Will
Meet Sunday

NEW YORK. Dec. 27â€” Dâ€” The
latest football game on record for
j an eastern field is scheduled to
be played tomorrow when all star
teams from the north and south
1 clash for the benefit of charity.
After many vicissitudes. Jack
McBride and Stumpy Thomason of
the Brooklyn Dodgers professional
team, former luminaries from
Syracuse and Georgia Tech res
pectively, have carried their plans
through to the point where their
teams are all assembled and a
waiting the kickoff at Ebbetts
Field tomorrow afternoon.
The question of just what charity
is to benefit has been in doubt
ever since the Knights of Colum
bus. original sponsors of the game
withdrew, but it is certain there
will be some beneficiary.
Chinese are taking a fanev to
hard candy, which is sold at the rate
of six large sticks for a cent.
Mrs M Swaine. Australian oldest1
colonist, died recently at Adelaide
at the age of 10&. 1
is on a higher plane now than ever
before. Basketball is the hardest
game of all to officiate for officials
have helped to standardize offi
ciating.
Basketball has gone through dif
ferent evolutionary stages and with
each succeeding one the game is
becoming more scientific.
Few people are aware of how
universally the game Is played.
During the last few' weeks I have
received requests for basketball
lessons from the following coun
tries: Alaska. Porto Rico. Mexico.
Guam, and France Our service
teams have no doubt been the
greatest medium of spreading the
game.

Basketball is played In the fol-
lowing countries that we know of:
Alaska, Canadian Provinces, Hawaii.1
China. Japan. Porto Rico and oth
er South American countries, Cuba.
Panama. San Salvador. Spain.
Greece, Persia. Guam. England, j
France, Mexico and others.
In many of these countries the
game is played outside due mostly
to the warm climate. However,
playing facilities are increasing
with the popularity of the games
as manifested by an order received
from the Mexican government bv
the Nurre Plate Glass Company of
Bloomington. Ind., for four com
plete sets of glass bank boards.
Mexico sent a team to tour the
mid-west last year and it surprised
everyone with its ability.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2023271000/1944-09-22/ed-1/?sp=7&q=basketball&r=-0.292%2C0.134%2C1.281%2C0.682%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Specialists in Each
Barracks Plan
Fall Sports Program
k
Individual, Group Sports
Begin in Barracks;
Tourneys Planned
Complete Program of Fall and Winter Sports Planned for Enlisted Men
fan ana winter sports are being planned in a big way for
enlisted men on the Depot.
Under the leadership of Lt. (jg) Rov I. Carriker, recre
ation and welfare officer, and Lt. (jg) J. C. Hickey, officer
in charge of Naval Barracks recreation, a group of
and recreation specialists are working out the details
plan, which will provide recreational opportunities
fields.
athletic
for their
in many
Specialists Arrange
Nine Tournaments, 12
Other Activities Begin
Athletic specialists and recrea
tional directors in the various bar
racks are organizing tournaments
in nine different activities.
They are bowling, pocket bil
liards, touch football, horseshoes,
table tennis, volley ball, shuffle
board, badminton and boxing.
Barracks and Depot champions
will be decided through these
tournaments, and awards will be
given to the winners.
Refinishing of the gym floor in
the temporary recreation building
is the only thing holding up the
starting of 12 activities to be held
there.
Through instructions by athletic
specialists, the following activities
will begin:
Basketball, badminton, volley
ball, shuffleboard, tumbling, box
ing, bat ball, wrestling, combative
judo, weight lifting, table tennis
and calisthenics.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1916-02-27/ed-1/?sp=15&q=basketball&st=text&r=-0.294,-0.23,1.172,1.172,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKETBALL NOW
ONE OF AMERICAâ€™S
FAVORITE INDOOR
WINTER PASTIMES
Growth of Game in Alabama
and the South Has Kept
Stride Set by Eastern and
Northern States
AVERAGE OF FIFTY
TEAMS PRODUCED
IN VARIOUS STATES
Over 100 Teams Now Play
ing Under Organized
Heads as Compared With
Ten in 1906
My FRED BODEKER
The remarkable popularity of bas
ketball during the past 10 years has
elevated the game to the position of
one of the foremast in American sports.
The past decade has witnessed a seem
ingly impossible growth In the basket
game and even experts are puzzled over
the problem.
Basketball has proven itself to be
one of the best sports in every way
that help the American people to
amuse themselvefe in,the gymnasium.
Basketball makes no uncertain de
mands on heart and lungs and on en
durance generally. Basketball is a
game. Thatâ€™s allâ€”only a game. It is
not a combat nor a battle nor a fight*
as some people would term it. It is
just a game.
Authorities have often repeated the
statement that basketball does more
to form a man's character than any
other sport. The period of adolescence
is the time when basketball and sim
ilar games are played and when lifeâ€™s
habits are formed and the character
largely determined. Politics is a game
and so is almost any business, and the
people are merely players in the game.
And so is basketballâ€”it is a game and
one of the best.
DEVELOPS THE BODY
Basketball develops many parts of
the human body. It develops alertness,
gelt-control, skill, speed and brings ev
ery part of the body into action. The
game arouses the interest and enthu
siasm of every spectator. The simplic
ity and small quantity of apparatus
required, together with other chief
qualifications of the game, make it
one of the most valuable of our com
petitive games.
Basketball belongs to the large fam-
ily of games originated to amuse the
American public. It was first started
in 1891. Dr. James A. Naismtth, now
a member of the collegiate basketball
rules committee, was an instructor at
the Springfield Y. M. C. A. Training
school and undertook to devise an in
door game which would develop man
kind. Basketball was at first very sim
ple. Since then, however, the game has
undergone complete revision; but bas
ketball lovers all over the nation owe
to Dr. Naismith the honor of â€œinvent
ingâ€™â€™ the game.
Since 1891 basketball has made mar
velous strides. The game was adopted
by colleges, high schools, athletic as
sociations in all parts of the country.
The big eastern colleges first fell in
line and soon the movement spread to
the south. Beading southern colleges
and institutions quickly adopted the
game and by 1900 basketball was a
game that was beginning to be played
by all important institutions.
GROWTH IN 1906
In 1906 the game began to grow even
more popular. Athletic clubs in all parts
of the south were producing teams and
tights were being staged for the
â€¢'championships.â€ Not only in the south
was the game popular, but the middle
west and the eastern states were far
ahead. It Is roughly estimated that
something over an average of 60 teams
were being produced in every state in
the union or over 2400 teams were
playing organized basketball to say
nothing of the innumerable grammar
schools and independent teams that
numbered as many more.
But basketball did not stop its won
derful growth. The game has some un
seen power that attracted clubs, col
leges and schools to adopt it. As the
years passed the number playing the
game increased and by 1910 the num
ber playing in 1906. which was es
timated to have been over 240Â°, was
estimated to have been doubled, or
nearly 3000 teams. This does not
elude independent teams but omy
teams as high schools, athletic clubs,
colleges and other educational institu
tion
Dr. Joseph E. Raycroft. chairman of
he joint committee on basketball
ules. is quoted as saying that the
umber of teams playing basketball
I 1910 was over 7000. This, however,
considered by many to be too large,
onsidering that six men 5s ine aver
ge number of players on one team,
ver 42,000 men were playing in or
anlzed basketball in 1910.
In Alabama in 1906, the number of
tarns playing basketball was something
he 10 or less, which Included the Bir
slngham Athletic club, Birmingham
Ugh school, Mobile, Montgomery, and a
ew others. The effects of the growth
ver the nation took effect in Alabama
nd the number in 1910 jumped to nearly
3 teams. A few hight schools were
laying the game, being seriously handt
apped by the lack of an Indoor court,
phile almost every athletic club and
M. C. A. in the state was represented
y a team.
OVER 100 TEAMS
In 1*16, the beginning of the present
eason, which Is about to come to a very
uccessful close, the number playing in
his state Jumped to over 100. Over 60
igh schools are playing basketball, with
ImoBt 40 athletic clubs and other instl
utions of this kind. The game is played
y every grammar school In the larger
itles of the state, while countless teams,
.norganlzed as in the Y. M. C. A., and
lass teams of various educational ln
tltutions, are following the same exam
Not only in Alabama but in all parts
>t the country Is the game making
apld strides toward the top of the lad
ler as an indoor sport. The number
paying In the United States at the
n-esent is estimated to go over 23,000
earns, which means that about 156,600
leople are playing organized basketball
X this number Alabama can boast of
Jmoat 700 players, which, although be
nw a majority of the statee, is well in
he advanced list.
Add so it can be seen, Alabama with
ractically every other state in the' union
fast taking to basketball, and expert
rltlcs who have watched Its growth for
he past decade predict no decline In
ts power to attract the attention of
he apart loving publle.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062224/1957-12-27/ed-1/?sp=5&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.211,0.051,0.254,0.271,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Caesar Rodney School
News
Caesar Rodney School Calendar
â€”January, February and March.
Christmas vacation until January
2
Reminder: Friday, December 27,
Glee Club Dance, 8:00-11:30. Harry
Jarman's Orchestra. Semi-formal,
alumni, students, friends, guestsâ€”
90c stag, $1.50 per couple.
January
Thursday, January 2â€”8 p. m.â€”
Program as planned for December.
Sixth grade parents will serve re
freshments.
Saturday, January 4â€”8 p. m.â€”
Sophomore record dance.
Monday, January 6:9 a. m.â€”As
sembly for grades 4-5-6, "A Jour
ney Into the Forest;" 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) election
of officers and plans for the 10th
Annual Winter Band Concert.
Tuesday, January 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls at Milford; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys vs. Milford at
C. R.; 2:50 p. m.â€”High School As
sembly, "Science Barriers."
Thursday, January 9: 4-H Ban
quet in cafeteria.
Friday, January 10: 3:45 p. m.â€”
Basketball, Jr. H. S. vs. Felton at
C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
girls at Felton.
Tuesday, January 14â€”3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Laurel at
C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at Smyrna.
Friday, January 17â€”Six weeks
marking period endsâ€”report cards
due Friday, January 24; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Sud
lersville at C. R.
Tuesday, January 21: 3 p. m.â€”
Basketball. J. C. boys at Felton; 7
p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and girls
vs. Felton at C. R.
Friday, January 24: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Fel
ton at C. R..
Tuesday, January 28: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Mid
dletown at C. R.
Friday, January 31; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Smyr
na at C. R.
February
Monday, February 3: 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) in high
school office; Industrial Arts din
ner in cafeteria.
Wednesday, February 5; 8 p. m.
â€”Tenth Annual Winter Band Con
certâ€”students 50c; adults, 75c;
family, $1.00.
Thursday, February 6: 8 p. m.â€”
PTA.
Friday, February 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls and J. V. at Sea
ford; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at St. Andrews.
Monday, February 10â€”1:30 p. m.
â€”Kent County Student Council at
C. R.
Tuesday, February 11: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls at Mid
dletown.
Wednesday, February 12: 3 p. m.
â€”Assembly, for grades 5 and 6,
band concert.
Friday, February 14: 3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Harrington.
Saturday, February 15: 7:30 p. m.
â€”7-1 and 7-2 boys in cafeteria.
Tuesday, February 18: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls and J. V. vs.
Seaford at C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basket
ball, boys and J. V. at Laurel.
Friday, February 21: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Harrington
at C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys
and J. V. at Sudlersville.
Tuesday, February 25â€”3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Laurel; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys and J. V. vs.
St. Andrews at C. R.: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys at Milford; Six
Weeks Marking Period Endsâ€”Re
port cards due March 10.
March
Monday, March S: 8 p. m.â€” B. P.
c.
Tuesday, March 4: 7 p. m.â€”Bas
ketball, boys at Milford.
Wednesday, March 5; 12:45 p. m.
â€”Assembly for grades 5 and 6.
Thursday, March 6: 8 p. m.â€”PTA.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066314/1917-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.352,0.548,0.207,0.221,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TITLE IN BASKETBALL
Kansas City Team Defeats
Warrensburg in Final
Game, 62 to 27.
FAYETTE ENDS THIRD
HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL CHAMPIONS
Singer Is Individual Star
.With 24 Points Wil
liams Makes 20.
Kansas City Central .High School
won the state high school basketball
tournament by defeating Warrensburg
62 to 27, at the Rothwell Gymnasium
court last night This is Central's
third season without a defeat. Singer.
the Blue and White star forward, took
the ball after three seconds of play
and scored, the first field goal. Central
was never headed, but the game was
harder fought than the score indi
cates. The Kansas City team was easily
the superior of any of the other eight
teams and their victory was foretold
by basketball followers when they
were first seen in action. Singer was
the highest individual point scorer in
last night's game, with 24 points to
his credit, though Williams with 20
and Duvall with 14 pushed him hard
for the honor. Giltner, the Warrens
burg captain, tossed the ball through
the ring for 19 tallies. Dorland was
the only other Warrensburg man to
break into the scoring, making the
other 8 points. The score:
enirai etc; Warrenslmrs (27)
m 3lHIBIE&Vfl9Ki afllBBH
'GET BASKETBALL LETTERS
Committee oh Intercollegiate Athlet
ics Makes Awards.
The Committee on Intercollegiate
Athletics have recommended the
following men for basketball Ms:
Captain Fred Williams, Sam Shlrkey,
Harry Viner, C. H. Slusher, Kenneth
Shenard. P. B. Vogt and Jesse L.
Campbell.
The election of Jesse L. Campbell
as captain of next year's basketball
squad was approved. It was decided
to try and arrange a track meet with
Leland Stanford University, and, if
possible, to bring the meet to Colum
bia. The baseball eligibility list was
approved with the exception of four
men who were voted ineligible. Mr.
Brewer feels that these men, while
ineligible now, can later be placed in
the list of eligibles"
CAPITOL FIXTURE FUND GIYEN
faeMS U Be Use aj CeiurissteB
Bear for Seleetfeas.
E. w. Stephens, chairman of the
State Capitol Commission Board, says
that the Board has another big problem
before It In the baying of furniture
and fixtures for the new capital. The
legislature has voted an appropriation
of 300,000 for that purpose, but states
that selections must be made by mem-
bers of the board and not by
tenor decorator or advisor.
Fam Machiaery Class Tries Tntf
The farm machinery class was g
en some experience in plowing Tesfej
day when Prof. E. W. Lehmana'tiiJtC
out one of the University tractors f"
the field west of the poultry grwaay';.
Each man was permitted to handle'tfct
tractor and gang plows by Mmtrctc,
Five acres were plowed by the
dents.
Plant peonies and Iris now.
bia Floral Co., phone 920.
Colum-C-179
FREE
Development of
Films purchased
Tn&Kri Sfore
all
at
Top Row, Left to Bight: Coach C. CHornaday; Williams, Center;. Coach
J. -U. Young. Bottom Row: DuTal, Bight Forward; Sanders, Left Guard;
Singer, Left Forward and Bamsar, Right Guard, Who Did Sot Make the
Trip to Columbia.
filth, Charleston;
Singer, If
Duval, rf
Williams, c
rg, Herm. Smith. Hankln
Webster Groves;
sixth, Sedalia.
Central will be awarded a large
bronze wall .placque and the other
teams smaller placques.
Kansas City Central and Warrens
burg qualified for the finals Satur
day morning by defeating Fayette
and Webster Groves, D scores of 51
to 7 and 24 to 14 respectively.
Charleston defeated Hannibal 2S to
Charleston at the hands of Warrens
imrg, 25 to 14. The work of Spencer
and Lincoln for Webster Groves In the
first conflict is worthy of mention,
their combined efforts netting 29 of the
35 tallies for the victors. Dorland
Hanna and Giltner starred for War
rensburg in the second game.
ALL-STATE TEAMS SELECTED
cTllerb. smith10 ln tne first consolation game played
j rf.nanna Saturday morning. Sedalia defeated
Uaskets from floor Sinrpr s Tin mi r I the Fairfax fivfl 27 in 14
"imams, ju, sanaers Dorland 4. Gilt-
Sanders, Is
isnrte. rg
ner 5. Baskets on free triali Sincer a
Giltner 9. Free trials misled Singer 4,
uiuuer i. x ouis called un Singer 3,
Duvall 3, Williams 2, Sanders 4. Burke 1,
Dorland 3, Hanna 3. Herb. Smith 2. Gilt
ner 2. Herm. Smith 3, Bankin 2.- Referee
Bryant (Missouri).
In the finals of the consolation se
ries Charleston defeated Sedalia IS
to 11. This placed Charleston in fifth
place and gave the cellar position to
Sedalia.
Third place was won by Fayette
who defeated Webster Groves, 20 to
7 in the most hotly contested game of
the series. The placing of the first
six team's in the series follows: First,
Kansas City Central; second, War
rensburg; third. Fayette; fourth.
The games Friday night brought
four learns to the semifinals in the se
ries. Kansas City Central had qual
ified for this round in the Friday aft
ernon games by defeating Fairfax In
a one-sided game, 50 to 11. Fayette1
also defeated Xeosha in the afternoon,
but was forced to beat the Sedalia five,
which had a bye in the first round,
before gding to the semifinals. This
was the last of the Friday night games.
These two teams were the leaders of
the Central District and fought a hard
game, 25 to 17.
The other games Friday night re
sulted in a victory forsWebster Groves
over Hannibal, 35 to 4, and a defeat of
3 Members of Victorious Central High
Team on First Squad.
The five officials of the state high
school basketball tournament, Fred
Williams. George Bryant and John F.
Miller, referees; Anton Stankowski,
scorekeeper; and Samuel Church.
timekeeper, have picked the following
all-state high school teams:
First Teas
Forward Singer, Central (captain)
Forward Dorland, Warrensburg.
Center Williams, Central.
Guard Sanders, Central.
Guard Giltner, Warrensburg.
Second Team
Forward Duval, Central (captain)
Forward Spencer, Webster Groves.
Center Skillman, Fayette.
Guard Burke, Central.
flnarA VTnrlo Wnhstor Clrrrrna T T
..u. W,V.J.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020422/1954-02-04/ed-1/?sp=9&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.192,0.483,0.176,0.188,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>SCHOOL
REPORTER


On Wednesday, January 20, af
ter two practices, the Smyrna
F. F. A. basketball teams met with
Caesar Rodney, Milford, Harring
ton and Felton teams at Caesar
Rodney for the first tournament of
the season. The tournament con
sisted of having three gamesâ€”two,
varsity and one J. V.â€”played at
the same time until eventually all j
were eliminated but one in each
division, Milford w i n n i ng the j
championship for both Varsity and
J. V. Smyrna's varsity was beaten!
F. F. A. Basketball

by Caesar Rodney. The Smyrna
J.V. played against Milford for theâ– 
final round. Refreshments were
served by the Caesar Rodney
Chapter.
February Calendar of Events
February 2, Basketball game at
home with Wilmington Friends, I
3:30.
February 3, Basketball game at
home with Chestertown, 7:00.
j
February 4, 1st Semester Report
Cards.
February 5, Basketball game at
home with Caesar Rodney, 7:00.
February 9, Personnel Club As
sembly 1:25.
February 9, Basketball game at
home with Harrington, 7:00.
February 11, P.T.A. meeting
high school cafeteria, 8:00.
February 12, Basketball game at
Dover, 7:00.
February 13, Kent County Queen
of Hearts Dance at Harrington
High School, 8:00.
February 16, Basketball game at
St. Andrews, 3:30.
February 19, Basketball game at
home with Middletown, 7:00.
February 22, Yearbook material
to be sent to publisher.
February 23, Basketball game at
Chestertown, 7:00.
February 26, Basketball game at
home with Milford, 7:00.
The Smyrna High School Eagles 1
basketball team will play its next
three games on the home c o u r t
which should prove advantageous
to the Red and White. The Eagles
Basketball
will play host to the Caesar Rod
ney team tomorrow night. In the*r
previous game the Riders beat the
Eagles by ten points, but Coach
Homey expects a reversal of form
on the home court.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>




  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-badminton</id>
    <results>

      <result>
	<id>/https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1886-04-04/ed-1/?sp=12&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How the Young People of New York
ltclux Strict Formality at
Badminton*
The Way in Which n Howlinjj swell
Getsilimsell Ip for the Ilariu
less Game.
New York Letter: 1 have read a heap
within a month in the society columns ot
our city dailies and weeklies, as well as in
out-of-town letters, concerning one Noa
Don. who seems to be accepted as the
spring-tide belle of Fifth avenue. Non
sense! This is too big a town, and even the
limits of the most pretentious society are
too spacious, to permit any single girl to
pet unquestioned supremacy. I have seen
this precious creature, moreover, and 1 am
telling you Cor keeps that she is no such
thing as the accounts make her out. I'm
not denying her all the wit at repartee to
iredited to her. She truly has touguc as
iliarp and quick as ever 1 heard: but what
I am impressing on you this minute- is that
a Queen of Swelldom, if we ever do crown
one. will be perfection as to dress.
Now. Noa Don is merely a traveled
and educated gill, who has been round the
world to pick up conceits that startle and
amuse us; who has come into New York
with family connections that give her en
trance to the charmed circles of wealth, and
Â«he makes her witty commentsâ€” as
nave been so extensively reported with
considerable cleverness; but when 1 have
described her as she presented herself at
the Academy of Music the other evening
yon will understand why I won't concede
that she ought to be elevated into public
view as supremely fine. She ought to huve
been arrayed in fashionable evening
costume, of course, because she sat in a box
along with women so dressed. But she ap
parently aimed to be
DISTISCTIVKLY ODD.
Her hair was loose and fluffy, and the
only ornamentation or attempt at coiifure
was a curious Bori of gilded thing not un
like a crown -set on the top of her head.
Her dress was pale amber >atm, and its cut
was not unlike that of the current morning
gown. Her anus wene completely covered
by sleeves and gloves, but her nmiapn was
law 111 a Bquariah shape, outlined by a
Btand-up frill of lace, as little in the fashion
cf Queen Elizabeth. No. no; Noa Don
can not be officially admired, no matter
how smart her sayings, until she robes her
self in accordance with strict fashiou's
rules.
What a jolly row Miss Cleveland has
been kicking up. by the way. about low
corsages. Still, she is awfully right in con
demning some of the nudity, and
you will remember that 1 have been
doing the same missionary sort of
work for several seasons. i*he makes
n special point of it that the line of bareness
shall bo high enough bo cover all of the dis
tinct feminity. He* Idea is that bare amis,
an. l so much Of the breast as happens to be
flat, are not an immodest exposure: but as I
looked up from the perusal of her letterâ€” it
was just before Starting tor B recent ion. and
a bevy of tirls were randy to goâ€” and my
eyes fell on a maiden of exceeding meager
nests in curvatures, I said to myself:
'â€¢Where would the line be dra*vn across
that creature if it were lowered in obedience
to .Miss Cleveland's proposition?''
BOUBKHOLO AIM l( I.LS
are so frequently asked about by a*ycor
respondents that I here give, by general
way of answer, a number of points. Pil
low-shams arc used in preference to fancy
trimmed slip overs. Lace curtains never
go out of fashion. They I.re used for
parlors, reception and dlning-rooma,
bedrooms, and. in fact, for all the
rooms of a houso. if preferred to the many
novelties in what is called .Madras lace.
really a muslin brocbe curtain, in various
colors to suit the furnitures of the room for
which they are intended. The moat htfh*
[onablc watch chain worn is a short fob
chain, with a ball at the end. which inavbe
plain, chased or set with Jewels. We did
not know that they were called Queen
Anne watch-chains, but that is probably
the name by which they arc known to some
fashion writers and to jewelers. Grena
dines are BOperceded by canvas or etamine
fabrics nowadays, but are still worn by a
few conservative ladies. Great variety in
form and color of upholstery, draperies and
all the pieces of furniture in a room is per
mitted by fashion at present. In fact, what
is called by some writers the eloctric room
that is. a room furnished with choice
furniture representing various modern or
medieval periods of art furnishings, and
harmoniously combining several subdued
colors with one prevailing tint or tone is
considered the height of taste. But it re
quires
OHKA.T JUDGMENT
in selecting the pieces of furniture, the cur
tains, carpets, decorations and ornaments
of such a room. There is danger of mak
ing it look like a furniture dealer's collec
tion. The rage for decorated china, or
delft, is on the wane, but when plain white
is used it is selected of the finest ware, and
is sometimes made decorative in the fluting
or waving of the pieces in dotting, scallop
hie. denting or flagreting the edges, the
handles and borders of the cups, dishes,
sauces, plates and side pieces. The most
exquisite and fanciful shapes of antique,
niediseval and modern pottery are chosen,
all done in white. Then, if color is de
manded on the table, it is supplied by flow
ers, all one color if possible, by fancy col
ored glass and open drawn work lines in
the tablecloth, showing the bright color
of the fine flannel cloth placed under
the white one. Sometime a long mat
of velvet or plush of the color of the
flowers and glass on the table is placed
down the center of the same, and on this
are placed the eperjoie, a central glass etna
for tlowers and lruit, and the little bisque.
j tiuures holding btekete t;dl of bon-bons,
candied fruits and motto ptpan, the fancy
glass tlowor receivers and flower-!
and choice pieces of silver. For a toilet set.
decorated china, or. lu'tter still, fancy cut
glass, is the correct thing.
I'Koi'i.i: Mo !maÂ».im;
that the fMMR men and women of Xew
York society are stiil and formal in their
Manners would have been somewhat sur
prised at the ciowdot vonng peoplt who
gathered before 1 O*deek feeteVdajf after
noon to play bidminton in a Â«|iucr little
Fourth avenue buildinK- Nobody wn> v,.|,.
(>us for an instant, and chaff seeniol to Ik>
tbeorderof the hour. Over in one corner
sat four maids as upricht as dolls
and as solemn as East [pitta fakirs.
The? conversed in low tones and seemed
utterly oblivious to the tfume. .So d;d
mo>t of the others for that matter, and it
didn't take a voiy shrewd observer to dis
cover that bandminton. as played" in New
York, consists ni conversation*; to a very
large extent. Interspersed with a few cur
sor, bits of hit and mi-play with the
racquets. There were no chaperones at all
at this RUM, and it amounted to a merry
tort ot frolic Cor two hours bj the middle
of the day. li wm MMuing to Hstento
the talk, tor the Kugiish accent, which bj
affeoted so laboriously by some of the so
ciety people, m picked an and dropped
pieci-Â«'ly as fancy dictated by the gor
geously attired people who made badmin
ton an excuse lor Betting without
being oppressed by the pres
ence of chaperone dnenneti Hut just
let me show \ou how superior bolles are to
beans when it comes to sightliness at play.
Tbe biggest swell of the dandies arrived an
hour before time. He was a small man
w ith prominent teeth, rather a pallid face,
and a pah* ol shadowy side whiskers. He
penneed up to the door of the liiuisy frame
structure, and nodded carelessly to a stolid
Englishman who stood by the dÂ«Â»or with a
straw in his mouth and his hands in his
pm fcete.
"Good mawnin". Fowbes." said the new-
Coiiier. screwing* a elng inlO one of
bb) weak ejea, and glaring hard at t lie at
tendant; "is any one beahf
â€¢â€¢Not yet. sir, "'^liuilK' attendant, respect
fully.
"Aw." muttered the fOUg man compla
en ly; "1 am the tirst one then."' Baring
arrived at this deep and logical conclusion,
after
AX KI.AnonATH COl*Rhe east a and transparent smile at
Forbes, and drifted through the doorway
into the barn-like structure. Here he cast
a critical view at a net which extended
across the Moor, went to one of a series of
small lockers, and took therefrom a rac
quet. Then he ascended the small >uir
way to the gallery, where there were I few
dressing- rooms, and presently emerged in
all the glory ol white llaunel knickerbock-
ers and shirt, with long red stockings, a
blue nnd white silk Norfolk jacket, and a
blue worsted Tarn O'Shanter cap perched
artfully upon his rather peculiar-looking
head. Around one of his slim wrists there
was a broad leather band clasped with four
buckles a scheme by which champion
badminton aud tennis players strengthen
wrists that have been strained by overplay.
The single glass now hung over his breast.
He danced about fora moment to limber up
his legs, and then, stepping out in the iu
closure across which the net was placed,
he slipped oflE his little cube into which was inserted a rim
of feathers and tossed it in the air. When
it came diving downward, with bullet-like
directness he caught it deftly on the end of
bin racquet and sent it into the air agate.
building and imparted the Still 1
km look to it that a conservators
midsummer. Occasionally the .in.,
car bell could be heard but nobody luliruiutl
into the Badminton club. The only signs
<Â»f life were supplied by the nimble young
swell who danced carelessly about in the
sunshine, batting the feathered toy up to
ward the roof. With the rich colors of his
costume and his nimbleness he might have
been tnistaden by a buloonist peering from
above for a huge tropical bird of some cay
but gawky sort disporting itself grotesquely
in the sun.
THE SOLITARY
young; badminton player who was romping
so joyously was a howling swell of a very
high order. He didn't look like a man of
pint importance, but socially his position 1
is enviable. A man who at the age of j
twenty-eiirht can boast of membership in
the Summerset club, of Boston; the Savage
club, of London; the Jockey club of Paris,
and the Union. Knickerbocker and Union
League clubs, of New York: has a racing
â– table of his own and spends SGO.OOO a
year without earning the reputation of
being a spendthrift or a fool, must neces
sarily amount to something in the woild of
society. lie seemed as happy as a clam at
high tide, batting away there skillfully,
when a brougham drove up to the door and
a young woman and her maid bustled in he
gave a yell of meeting that was quite un
dignified, and reminded one strongly of a
street Arab.
â€¢â€¢Late again. Miss Agatha," he chirped,
happily. "Ton me soul it is quite heart
rending for a man of my conscientiousness
and t lustful nature to receive these disap
pointments every play-day."
''Indeed, you are a paragon,"' said the
jrirl. smiling brightly, and aoastaglsÃŸf wraps
t" the maid. "It was the fault of mamma
Ibis morning. She was desperately blue
when she irot out of bed, and so she climbed
bark in again. Then she insisted upon my
rending to her until she felt more composed,
and there you are."
She had scarcely finished speaking when
there was a great chatter and bustle about,
and half a dozen people hurried in. Two
of the guls were in full tennis rig. and
when one of the men slipped off his long
ulster he revealed the fact that he. too. had
put on his play-day togs before suiting
from home.
WHAT STRUCK ME HARDEST.
However, was the fact that the belles
were so much more shapely and graceful
than the beaux. More than one bony fellow
had on what 1 believe actors call "Mats."
That is to Kay, their legs were artificially
enlarged and straightened by padding. No
till was jruilty of such deceit. But 1 don't
mind telling you just what girl; do in their
One when costuming for badminton or ten
nis. The fashion is to wear soft woolen
skirts retelling to the ankles, and presuma
bly with no petticoats underneath. The in
tention is to leave the legs clear for the ex
erciseâ€”also distinctly outlined as part of
the mend symmetry that constitutes so
much of the pleasant sightliness of the
â– port. Well, every player of good sense
puts on exactly as many flannel skirts as
will produce the desired bulk. No speota
toi can tell whether there be one or six lay
ers of the soft fabric; but anyhow he never
sees the protuberance of a knee-pan or the
sharpness of a shinboue. Clara Belle in
Cincinnati Enquirer.
AVliy a Bottton Woman Wept.
Bostou Budget.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047239/1886-10-13/ed-1/?sp=5&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PLAYING BADMINTON
A TWO HOJRS FROLIC FOR NEW
YORKS SOCIETY YOUNG FOLKS
Arrlrnl of the UlcucstHwolI of tlio Dun
silo Aflor nil ISlnbornte Cniirne of
Thought Sixty Thtinsnnil u Ycnr nutl
i llio ltesiilta Thormf
People wlio lnmglno tlmt tlio young men
and women of Now York society tiro still
mul formal In tholr manners would have
been somewhat surprised at tlio crowd of
young pcoplo who met together ono
nftornoon to play badminton In a queer
little Fourth avenue building
It didnt take a very shrowd obsorvcr
to discover that badminton as played In
Now York consists of conversation to a
very largo extent Interspersed with n fow
cursory bits of hit nnd rclsplay with tho
racquets Tlicro wore no chnperones at
nil at this gamo nnd it amounted to a
merry sort of a frolic for two hours In tho
middle of tho day It was amusing to
listen to the talk for tho English accent
which Is affected so laboriously by soino
of tho aocloty people was picked up nnd
dropped precisely as fancy dictated by tho
gorgeously attired pooplo who made bad
minton an excuse for meeting without
being oppressed by tho presence of chnpur
one duennas
A DKEP AND LOCIICAL CONCLUSION
Tlio biggest swel of tho dandlos arrived
an hour before time Ho was a small man
with prominent teeth rather n pallid face
and a pair of shadowy sldo whiskers Ho
pranced up to the door of tho flimsy frame
structure and nodded carelessly to a stolid
Englishman who stood by the door with n
straw In his mouth and his hands in his
pockets
Good mnwnln Fowbes said tho now
comcr screwing a slnglo glass Into ono of
his weak eyes and glaring hard at the at
tendant Is any ono heahf
Not yet sir said tho attendant re
spectfully
Aw muttered tho young man otm
plncently I am tho llrst ono thon Hav
ing arrived at this deep nnd logical con
clusion after an elaborate course of
thought ho cost n ghostly and transparent
sinllo at Forbes mid drifted through tho
doorway Into the burn liko structure
Hero he cast a critical view at a not which
extended across the floor went to ono
of a sorlos of small lockors and took
therefrom a racquet Then he ascended
the smidl stairway to a gallery vhoro
there were a fow dressing rooms and pres
ently emerged In all tho glory of whlto
flannel knickerbockers and shirt with long
red stockings a blue nnd whlto silk Nor
folk Jacket nnd a blue worsted Tom
OShantcr cap perched artfnlly upon his
rather peculiar looking head I Around one
of his slim wrists there was a broad leathor
band clasped with four buckles a scheme
by which champion badminton nnd tenuis
players strengthen wrists that have been
strained by overplay Tho single glass
now hung over his breast Ho dnnccd
about for a moment to limber up his legs
and then stepping out into tho Inclosuro
across which tho net was placed ho
slipped off his silk jacket produced n llttlo
cube into which was inserted a rim of
feathers and tossed it in tho air When it
came diving forward with bullet llko
directness ho caught It deftly on the end
of his racquot and scut it Into tho air
again
A HOWLINO SWELL OK IIIOII OllDCB
Tho solitary young badminton player
who was romping so joyously was a howl
ing swell of a very high order Ho didnt
look llko a man of great Importance but
socially his position Is enviable A man
who at tho agtuf 23 spends ftWOOO a year
without earning the reputation of being a
spendthrift or n fool must necessarily
amount to something in the world of
society Ho seemed as happy ns a clam at
high tldo batting away there skillfully
when a brougham drove up to tho door
and a young woman nnd her maid bustled
v in ho gave n yell of greeting that was quite
undignified nnd reminded ono strongly of
a street Arab
Late again Miss Agatha ho chirped
happily Ton me soul It is quite heart
rending for n man of my conscientious nnd
trustful nature to recolvo theso disap
pointments every plny dny
Indeed you are a paragon said tho
girl smiling brightly and tossing her
wraps to tho maid It was tho fault of
mamma tlis morning Sho was desper
ately bluo when sho got out of bed and so
she climbed back ngnln Then sho In
sisted upon my reading to her uutll sho
felt moro composed and there you nre
She had scarcely finished speaking when
thero was a great chatter and bustle about
und n halt dozen people hurried In Two
of tho girls were In full tennis rig and
when ono of tho men slipped off his long
ulster he revealed tho fact that he too
had put on his play day togs before start</text>
      </result>

            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1890-03-09/ed-1/?sp=18&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  PLAYERS OF BADMINTON.
JWO CLUBS WHER1- THE WRDS" ILV >VEB
THE NETS.
A DESCRIfTION Of THE GAJfE-IT- POPTJIiAltlTT
AS A I.KNTl-V AMUSEMI \T >*a
pkople wi llesown is
The pame of badminton, "f nli games "t akill. is
pcrhaps loast kti .wa by iho publle i.t large. It
is ncarly as mueh a game "i egilitj and quick
ncss as iciinis, and, altho igb the Mercite required
is not Tlolent, thecnjoymenl experlenced i.y tbe
playcrs in a cloaely oontested game la Jui
kcen as m tho more wldely known -istor game.
lat nn Indlfferenl player badminton i- much the
r.etter form nt sp-'M. and iho women w o go io
lor it are mdre entbuBlaatic iu it* supporl than
the most eonfirmed playcra -.i tennia The
liko it becauae it givea them an nppetite. and iu
this it nevei f.ii!-*. Cocktalla ire i t. to I c com
jiaicl with H- Sherry and bitters hecomes na
aotbing, nnd ;i good dinnei preceded bj badniin
tBadminton may be played either <-'i the lawn
or ladoors. ln Ita Indoor fonn it is. and is likely
to renniin. Sew-York'a fashionable L??nten paatime
aml n- auch ii certainly deservcs praise.
'Ih.' game aa now played i-- nol ..t greal i??
tlquity, oi il ll la, there ia no deflnlte reoord of
the lni't, lt ia "I Anglo-Indlan origln, and baa
been siii.o 1E. i u favorite with -.ngllab oJheera i"
India. The form ol game played ln Sew-York
ri..es not diffei materlallj fr..m thal played bj
tho Aiiin.ilai'i'l Badminton Club In India. and the
rulA* now adopted ure pructically tlie -ainc
Tho BBaterlala for badminton aro differcnl
iboee uaed for tei igb the gai
mlghl appeai simil r n e net la from two feel
to two feel si_ ii cl es in bre idth, ai I ln_t<
N-i.'i- sei upon tlu ng poles
nnd ia 1 ung al a distam c ol from Hve i"
j et to six fe 1 from tbe surfa. e oi Ihe court.
Inste i-l ol balls, sli ittlecocka, or bir la," oa they
nrc teehnlcally c lled, are used. Tlie racq cts
nr b it* with which l aboul are
rencrally ol a Lighter weighl and souiewli kl smaller
than the ordinory tennis i icque.,
tennla ruc<] et can be For in
door pl ig a i ird" wei ;1 i incc is
iiaed, bul oui or?, un ac. wind, i ce
weighliLg. an ounce and three-eeTered with rubber to prevenl uu urj from nio__t
urc, is I'.-fi-.
Vl_vr>'
Cil's OF THE "BIRDS
In dreaa ry for
pla- ii Iminlon. Tbe exei bi*. nol
lent. tennla Hannels cuu l*e and
even U nnis shoes re d. lf ln\v
aro woi feli aoles should bc
ctiosen. Women should wear lo"s<- t sligl tly
.liortcr tharj the invc tional aa i
af aome aofl Bes tuaterial thal will nol Intei
fciv wll "ii.
l s of the court musl be Ln a
tneas ;rc delermlned by the lize ol the Boor oi
la\\;i npon to lie 1 dd out. Oue1 w
elghl U"il ki i md twenty feel broad
but the ed by the
N< xx- ork I'
nn elevatl :i "i Iee1 it answers thi
is as geod aa ui I 11 iu.ir .--i
aat carefully with chalk lines, oi lf _
Mr::,. i and I.
Frn::i one to i ir peraona play <>n a aiie, and
t!.e ahuttlee. k or bird^ niuM in
Beturaed on a "volley" or before lo
court Burface. The "blrds" are sei ed and re
t i
cepi that if the shuttlecock falla to the eourl
gorface it ia ni <1 a nii__ to I plnyei
laila to return il and lo bia aiile. Tbe servicc is
from t!. i c ia, 1 lie
pl;iV,T bi fe within u section
?i i two i.-i t und sx, ineliea from the
earaer. Th* divisiona f the eourt* nr.- onlj oh
Berve.l on the aerve, aml the playera can Btand
wliere tliey plea>e on tbeir own si ;'ft?i it
Tlie Bhuttk I ser ed a tlu lt falla
Wlthln the lines i I cn ice c< url as in teiuiia,
0n,l ele r of tlu c! ropea and poata I tlie et
it touelied in tbe gervice and the "I'nd" falla
ovor. the Btroke ia ealled a, "lot" and docs not
connt -.r- ki er.
Iii p|ay, b< wi vi i tbe touchintj ol the :i<-i by the
glitiitlri tt g ea over counta aa a o -1
ati.. II the i ichi I I tlie racqui
nel with
tbeir racqueta, tlie st
JVo i..nli. p U hand out, and in all
?birdB lallin- upon boundary linea re re
?arded as faulta, both iu acrvice and in play.
fifteen point* eonatitnte the game. No over
liain! -i:. ia all iwcd ii the eervice. ln ja-l_
Ing wbether pl yei I re i ied over the net,
it is ajwi noticcd il the bird ia st: ick be
lote ii haa eroaaed Ihe nel aml merel> been foi
lowcl over by the raequel <>f player. Iu
this eaae il li i t ud stroke, bul il the racquet
itsolt tou il ea the nei tbe pl ia cotinti i a miss
The game ol b dmini >u introdu ed In thia
country .luiin. the xx.i.t.-r 1-1- b I'.y
ar.l t larke aad E. Langiton Wilks, and ihe nu
eleua ot the Im New-York liudunniou Club w_?
then formed.
THE OEEST OF THE CI.l'B.
The Badminton Clah was 1I10 pioneer. nnd its
luoeess has iicn much greatei than Ife
Ciarke aad Wll** dared h-iix- when they in1r>>
duced the pamo and began to Interesl othera ln
lt. The menilK-ishii) in 187*. was forty, and tho
flret gamos wcic played in the aruioiy buildin*.
nt Thii'iv-'iftl. st. and Broadway. Intereai m
the game eteadily Increased, and the memberablp
crew until 1884, when il numbered 100.
Tbe lub then disbanded, and in I tner*
was no playing. In I8S- ibe elub was
i/,-il with seventy-flve memtiers, thal nu mber
hcing the limit. The club waa governed ?y
eommittee until 18.7. when n was tbougiu au
visable to i and an executive eommit?
tee This waa done. tbe membership Umil waa
,hMt,,;,,',> veiimi,
ization haa had a regular club e-.v.-m
W en the 71si Reg.?nt nioved to _?*??
Fort\ ftfth-ftl and Broadwa
n n.oved with lt, aml th en- by game I
itional facilities for succe__.uUy playing i w
game.
  </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065075/1891-06-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A GAME FOR ALL SEASONS.
It Is Called "liadiulnton" ud Cuuie From
England.
Badminton was invented, or origin
ated, whichever you please, in England,
but owes its present rules to the Ah
medabad Badminton club of India,
Which has practically revived the sport.
It is a modification of lawn tennis, with
some important differences, as will be
seen further on, and has the advantage
that it can be, and generally is, played
in-doors. This make3 it both a suramet
and winter game.
Tho dimensions of the court must be
decided in a great measure by the capa
bilities of the room in which the game
is played. Tho best size Is one twenty
eight feet long by twenty feet broad.
The courts should bo marked off by
means of pegs and strings, or better,
when possible, by white chalk lines oe
the floor, and divided in the following
way: At each end ol the ground are
two courts, ten feet square, while the
center is formed by a piece of neutral
ground eight feet broad by twenty feet
long. On each of these outer lines of
the neutral ground and in the center
are placed tho posts which support tho
net The net, which is two feet to two
feet six inches deep, is suspended at a
height of six feet from the ground, and
firmly held by guy ropes attached to
posts.
The racquets used in Badminton, to
be easily and quickly Wielded, should
be lighter than those used in lawn ten
nis, and consequently smaller. A shut
tlecock is used instead of a ball, and
may be large or small, according to tho
wish of the players.
In its general line, Badminton is a
game played in the same fashion as
lawn tennis, with tho exception that
from one to four persons may play on a
side, and that tho shuttlecock must be
returned on the volley. Tho shuttle
cock is served and returned under tho
same provisions, except that, of course,
if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
it Is counted as a miss to the player
missing it, and to his side. The servico
shall be from the "service-corner," tho
server and receiver each standing with
both feet within their respective quad
rants until the shuttlecock is struck.
The divisions of the respective courts
are only observed in the serve or first
hit; after that, the partners may stand
where they please, on their side of tha
net The shuttlecock must be served
in such a way that it falls clear over the
net, without touching the net, ropes or
posts, and falls inside the lines of the
service-court If the net Is touched in
service and tho shuttlecock falls over,
the stroke is considered as a "let," and
does not count as a fault against the
person serving. In play, however, the
touching of the net by the shuttlecock,
when it falls over, is counted as good
stroke. If the net is touched by the
racquets of the players, or if they reach
over the net with their racquets, tho
stroke counts against them. Two faults
puts "hand out" In all cases a shuttle
Cock falling on any of the boundary
lines Is regarded as a fault, as if it had
fallen outside Of the boundary lines,
both in service and play.
Iifteen points constitute the game.
In service no overhand stroke is allow
ed. The shuttlecock is judged by where
it strikes and not by where it lies after
striking. In judging whether a player
has reached over tho net, the umpire
should bo careful to note if the shuttle
cock Is struck before it has crossed the
net and not by the racquet of the play
or, which is naturally carried forward
by the impetus of the stroke and which
might arrive at a slight angle over the
net, although the shuttlecock itself was
struck on the correct side. If, however,
the net is touched by the racquet the
stroke counts against the player, wheth
er the shuttlecock was struck on the
right side of the net or not
As will be seen from the description,
Badminton requires agility and a quick
eye, rather than great strength, and it
will be found to be a game at which
girls can play with pleasure and profit
Golden Days.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045604/1891-05-31/ed-1/?sp=9&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IrHE NET AND RACKET.
badminton Has Not Driven
Tennis From Favor.
BOSSIP OF THE CHAMPIONS.
I y Mabel Cahill, the John L. Sullivan
â€¢f the Xew York Club, and Other
i Great Flayers.
1
i jriw YORK. May 25.â€”[Special Corre
jpoodence.Jâ€”The tennis season of 1891 has
fairly begun, and from present appear
ances it will be the liveliest one that has
aver been known in this country. There
was a prospect earlier in the season that
badminton might supplant the older game
in favor, but every one concerned now
scouts the possibility of such a result. No
one, naturally, takes a keener interest in
the question than the makers of tennis
goods, and they report the largest advance
tale* on record. It is one of the not to be
forgotten consequences of the popularity
of lawn tennis that the manufacture and
nleof neta, rackets, lawn markers, shoes
and uniforms has become a great industry.
It is only a few years since all these goods
were imported from England, the home of
fee game; now they are practically all
Bade here, and thÂ» business amounts to
something like $10,000,000 a year to the
trade. This is looking at the other side of
the sport, but the point of view is not an
unimportant one.
The clubs in and about New York are in
nnmfctr almost legion, and they are pre
paring busily for championship events,
mcticaliy the season begins with Decora
tion day, the month of fine weather before
that date being given np to practice play
ing. Of course, play begins earlier South.
The Washington City tournament for the
championship of the Southern states was
held in the middle of May. Tomorrow
the New York Tennis Club will hold its
spring games, and from now to the end of
the season in October there will be a
tournament every dayâ€”for not a summer
hotel of any size is without its tennis
courts, the smaJlest villages have their
clubs, and matches and return matches
t are shrewdly relied upon to keep up the
interest in the game.
Undoubtedly the success of tennis is
OLLIE CA MPBELL.
largely due to the fact that men and
women can play it together. For flirta
tion purposes it may not quite eoual the
sedate and sluggish game of croquet,
but for a judicious combination of
sport and opportunities for tete-a-tetes
its equal has never been invented.
Indeed, tennis is the ideal ladies' game.
As it requires agility rather than strength
to play tennis, there is no reason why
women should not play quite as well as
men, if it were not for the perpetual haudi
cap ot skirts. As it is, an active young
woman is about a match for a stout and
middle-aped man, with equal practice, and
some of the l>est women players can hold
their own with any but the very best men.
i his is a test not to be recommended,how
ever, as the practice of playing with one of
the other sex rather tends to break a man
up. as he is divided between his gallantry
and his desire to excel. Thus it may easily
happen that a man will show tip in better
form at the end of a season with compara
tively little practice with men than if he
had considerable careless playing with
women. Championship games are, of
course, always between players of the
â€¢tne sex.
â€¢Since Scars, of Boston, who was an ex
fi.>rdinary tennis player, met with a dis
cing accident, the honors of the game
Jwe rested with the Brooklyn players
Henry \V. Stocum, jr., son of General ll!
W. Slocum, the champion of iw>, and Oli
"Ollie" Campbell, the present
bolder ot the championship, both having
park in past years,
though Mr. Slocum is ;IOR a member of
P:. George's Club, of New York. There is
perhaps no place in the country where bet
ter provision is made for tennis playing on
large scale than at Prospect park, and
there are few days in spring or summer
when a considerable number of games are
lot going on there simultaneously.
The frequency of va ant lots in the resU
yace sections of Brooklyn rather favors
KINKY W. STOCFM. *R
information of small neighborhood clubs,
Asocial amusement rather than tine
**y the result.
Jill!! orlt Vf 3 the younc woman
fÂ«g l f rather expected to win chief chain-
honors this summer. This is
Mabel K. Oahiil, of the Net York
lennis Club. Miss Cahill is an
woman ami won lame in the old
nir\ at tennis tournaments before com
lhl* Bhe is a vigorous, aihletic
younp woman, with merry, iaugh
yes, ana quick, viÂ« -rous movements.
It4mlv r^ Sen 10 ,^r woman's cham-
I P**nn P h 3 K Will not
withom
t n l her s:s!
amp iÂ° nfhll> for <*oubks. Miss
VA probabiy play in double# wiU\
SIXTEEN PAGES.
Miw Ballantine, of the New York club.
Miss Robinson, of Staten Island,
Mrs Morgan, of Short Hill*. N. J.,
the Misses Kiting. Frazer and Temple, of
Westchester county, and Miss Colby, of
Orange, N. J., are among the famous play
ers who may contert for the honors with
Miss< ah:i! and the Roosevelt sisters. Of
course, there will be dark horses, too, who
at the last moment mav appear to wrest
the leadership away from the well-known
plavers. It is always more difficult to
predict women's piaying than men's.
They have more time for practice, they
are quite as numerous, if not more so. and
they are far less likely to enter champion
ship contests than men, even if quite pro
ficient. Thus local pride may almost at
any time force to the front some splendid
player before unheard of outside of her
county. It is the peculiarity of the plav
ers of both sexes that they are at their
best while quite young and do jiotlong
retain their supremacy.
Badminton came to the front last winter
as an indoors game, for which it was well
adapted by the smallness of the court re
quired. A tennis court is 78 feet by 27
wider than an ordinary city lot and nearly
as deep. The badminton court is only 44
feet by 20, and can be recommended for a
home game where spare is verv limited.
The net is shorter and higher. The short
service line is 6 feet 6 inches from the net.
The base line is 15 feet t> inches farther
back on either side. The net itself is 16
feet long and 5 feet high in the middle.
In the play a shuttlecock is used in
stead of the white ball used in ten
nis. This is made of rubber and
feathered to steady its (light. Ordinary
tennis rackets are used instead of the ola
faehioned "battledores." The game is, in
fact, a sort of cross between lawn tennis
and the older game, and is said to be the
invention of an English officer in India,
who found the climate too hot for ten
nis. Perhaps that is the reason why old
tennis players call badminton a lazy peo-
Sle's When such sturdy at hletes as
[amihon Cary and .Stanley Mortimer and
such clever tennis experts as Miss Annie
Webb, Miss Turnure, Miss Minturn and
Miss Elsie Mitchell play and enjoy thgame, however, it can safely he assumed
that, there is plenty of exercise in it.
The rules of badminton are so simple
that they can be summarized in a para
graph. There is no authoritative Ameri
can body like the National Tennis Associ
ation, but the English rules are used:
The sides toss for choiceof ends or service
before the first game of a match, and change
to the other sideof the netafter each game.
The single-handed and double-handed
game consists of fifteen ares. At "13 all,"
the side which first reaches thirteen has
the option of "setting^'five; at 14 all, of
setting three. In three-handed or four-
handed jrames the game consists of twenty
one aces. First set is at 19 all; second at
20 all. A fault made by a player whose
I side is in puts a baud out; if made by a
j player whose side is out it counts an afe to
i the in side. It is a fault if the service is
I "overhand"; if the rirs-t part of the path of
the shuttlecock is inclined downward ;if the
service falls into the wrong court; if the ser
vice falls short of the service line or outside
the bounding line; unless both the server's
teet are in his own court; if the shuttle
cock falls outside the bounds of the court;
if the shuttlecock does not pass between
the posts, or if it pass under or through
tiie net or touch anything except the bat
of the striker, or the top of the net if the
shuttlecock !>e hit twice intentionally by
tiie same player; if the shuttlecock be
struck before it crosses the striker's side of
i the net; if the striker touch the net or its
supports with his racket or otherwise,
i The player in the right-hand court com
mencea the game by serving to the plaver
in the adverse right-hand oourt; if tfiat
leaver return the shuttlecock, it must be
hit ack by the in side and then returned
by the out side till a fault is made by one
j side or the other. The game is continued
in this manner, count being chanced after
j each ace ;s made. The service lines nre
disregarded alter the serve is returned,
j Iho innings always begin with the player
j in the right-hand court, and serves arc
i made alternately from each court into the
one d. t.; iia.lv opposite. In two. three
and tour-handed games, the side begin
ning a game has only one hand in its nrst
innings if there are two a side, and only
two hands if there are three a side. Inatwo
h and el game only the ptrson served to may
take a serve; not so in a three or four
handed game. The service must not begin
till the opponent is ready, but any attempt
to return is taken to indicate readiness.
Any unforseen or accidental hindrance
may be given by a "let" bv the umpire on
appeal from either side "before the next
service commences or before the players
have changed sides at the end of a game.
A "let" cannot be claimed it" an attempt
I ha* been made to strike the shuttlecock
Pitiably the next winter there will be a
badminton association iu this country r or
the new game may he taken under the
l government of the tennis association.
Magistrate (severely^â€”Why 'id
drive through the crowded thu fhfarea
at the rate of t:!teen miles an htur? I>o
you tlunk that the streets belong o you?
Culprit (earnestly protesting >-B_it,yg(Ur
honor, 1 drm a beer wagon.
PLAN OF A BADMINTON OOt'P.T.
A GAME OF BADMINTON</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-10-04/ed-1/?sp=8&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Champion Badanlatoa Tennla Playara,
Th Badminton lawn tennla axpert yesterday mo
eeeded In capturing both of the sterling silver trophies
In th recently formed Inter-Club Tennis Association of
King county. The scoresi
Gentlemen' Single Flnt round: B, IV Booecek,
Knickerbocker Field Club, forfeited to A. 8. Mertam,
Badminton Tennis Club; Dr. W.N. Fraser. King County
Tennis Club, beat B. 8. Ueltcamp, Altlora" Tennis Club,
e 8, ft 0; E. L. Heltrarap, Altlora T. C, beat A. Fransl
ola, Knickerbocker Field: Club, 82, 84: C. E. Mao
Mabon, Badminton T. C, beat A. G. McGowan. King
County T. C, 84. 80; A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T.
C, beat Dr. B.O. Fraser, Kings County T. C, 03, 08,
78.
Second Round K. L. Ileltkatnp, Altlora T. 0, beat O.
E. MacMabon. Badminton, T. O. 76. 88: A. 8. Mer
lam, Badminton. T. C, beat Dr. B, 0, Fraxer, Kings
County T. C tt-4, 68. 7-6.
Final Round A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T. C, defeated
L. lleltkamp. Alt.ora T. C. 0-0. 7-6, 82.
Gentlemen' Double, First Round E. H. Payne and
H. E. McGowan, King County T. C. beat E. L. llelt
kamp and H. B. lleltkamp. ARortaT. C, 8-8, 6-3: A.
8. Merlam and C. E. MarMahon. Badminton T. C. beat
K.H.Lou and Harry Wall. Knickerbocker Field Club,
fl 01; Harry rranclola and William Boocock.
Knickerbocker Field Club, beat J. 8, Jones and John U.
Rollins, Altlora T. C..H-0. 68,81; Dr. R.O. Prater
and F. M, Pendrelgh. Kings County T. C beat Dr. V. A.
Griffiths and O. N. Hchmtdt, BadmlntonT. C, 8-2, 8-0.
Heeond Round E. M. Payne and II. E. McOowan.
Kings County T. C were beaten by A. S. Merlam and C,
R. MacMabon. Badminton T.C., O 2. 2-fl, 0-4: Harry
Pransclola and William Boocock, Knickerbocker Field
Club, were defeated by Dr. W. N. Fraser and F, M. Pen
drelgh, Kings County T. C, 8-8, rt-O.
Final Round Dr. Prater and F. M. Fendrelgb. King
County T. c., were beaten by A. 8. Merlam and c E.
MacMabon, Badmldton T. C 13-11. 810, 67, 0-1,
68.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-10/ed-1/?sp=45&q=Badminton&st=text&r=-0.397,-0.047,1.795,1.795,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GAME OF BADMINTON
I Copyright by James Elver son
ITTS^~ ADAITNTON was invented,' or orig
|J Ij inatcd, whichever you please, in
I !*â€¢"*_ England, but owes its present rules
RtjlSSSfj to the Ahmedabad Badminton Club,
Mvlfilr" o f India, which has practically re
vived the sport. It is a modification
of lawn tennis, with some important differ
ences, as will be seen further on, and has the
advantage that it can be,- and generally is,
played indoors. This makes it both a sum
mer and winter game.
The dimensions of the court Imuit be de
cided in a grjfat measure by the j capabilities
of the room in, which the game lis played.
The best size ii one 28 feet long- by 20 feet
broad. The courts should be marked off by
means of pegs and strings, 'or better, when,
possible, by white chalk lines jon j the floor,
and divided in the following way: At each
end of the ground axe two courts. L jlO feet
square, while the centre is formed by a piece
of neutral ground 8 feet broad by 20 feet long.
On each of the outer lines of the neutral
I ground and in the centre are placed the posts
which support the net. .C-
The net, which is 2 feet to 2l2 l feet 6 inches
deep, is suspended at a height of 6 feet from
the ground, and firmly held by. guy ropes at
i tached to posts. ,y L
1 The racquets used in Badminton, to be easily
and quickly wielded, should be lighter than
those used in lawn tennis, and consequently
smaller. A shuttlecock is used instead of a
ball, and may be large or small, accorum" to
the 'wish of the players. .7 .1
In its general; line, Badminton is a game
played in the same fashion': as lawn tenni*,
with the exception that from one to four
persons may play on a side, and that the shut
tlecock must be returned on the volley. -_â€¢
The shuttlecock is served and returned
under the same provisions, except that, of
i course if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
it is counted as a miss to. the player missing
it and to his side." The service shall be from
the "service-corner," the server I and receiver
each standing with both feet within their
respective quadrants until the shuttlecock v
struck.
The divisions of the respective courts are
only observed in the serve or first hit; after
that the partners may 1 stand where they
please, on their side of the Â¦net....
The shuttlecock must be served in Mich a
wav that it falls clear over the net. without
touching the net, ropes or posts, and falls in
ide the lines of the service court.
If the net is touched m service and the
shuttlecock falls over, the stroke is oonsid
i BOYS AND GIRLS MAGAZINE SECTION
At tltc first tfelfOi 'crawAe&6>r J fyr/ffÂ£ Jttf/a /}&3&7ered 38 a "let," and does not count us a fault
against tbe person serving.
In play, however, the touching of the net
by the shuttlecock, when it falls over, is
counted as good stroke.
If the net is touched by the racquets of the
players, or if they reach over the neÂ£_ with
their racquets, the stroke counts against
them.
Two faultf puts "hand out." In all cases
a shuttlecock falling on any of the boundary
lines is regarded as a fault, as if it had fallen
outside of the boundary lines, both in service
and play.
Fifteen points constitute the game. In ser
vice no overhand stroke is allowed.
The shuttlecock is judged by where it strikes
and not by where it lies after striking.
In judging whether a player has reached
ever the net, the umpire should be careful to
note if the shuttlecock is struck before it
has crossed the net and not by the racquet of
the player, which is naturally carried forward
by the impetus of the stroke and which might
arrive at a slight angle over the net. although
the -shuttlecock itself was struck fairly on the
correct side.
If, however, the net is touched by the
racquet the stroke counts against the player,
whether the shuttlecock was struck on the
right side of the net or not.
As will be st%n from the description, Bad
minton requires agility and a quick eye, rather
than great strength, and it will be found to
be a game at which girls can play with pleas
ure and profit.
DIGNITY AMD IMPITDPNCe'</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-05-23/ed-1/?sp=29&q=badminton&r=-0.006%2C0.051%2C1.367%2C0.728%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BADMINTON TENNIS CLUB
HOLDS FIRST DAY'S PLAY
SANTA MONICA, May 22.â€”The
newly formed Badminton Tennis club
held its Brit play today on the Third
street courts. The club is the offshoot
of the Badminton dub, which held
sway last season, and Includes some
of the best racquet wlelders of South
ern California.
Among thus,- who will bi seen on
id, i club (milts this season are Mrs.
i; i,. Warring, the Mlssea Archer,
Miss Ryan, Miss Marshall, Miss Rower,
lliss Nettleshlp and Mrs. Bruce.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-03-28/ed-1/?sp=23&q=badminton&r=0.397,0.692,0.549,0.292,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Will Boom Badminton
j The Badminton Club, of New York,
an organization established in 1878,
I which has continuously since that time
I tried to foster and develop the game of
I badminton in this city, will hold 07;
I Saturday, March 27, an intercity tour?
nament with Caines Badminton Club.
I of Boston. There will be four matches
of men's singles, three women's sin-j
gles, two men's doubles, one women's
doubles and three mixed doubles. I
Ford-ham Nine
To Open Season
Next Thursday
Infield Presents Only Seri?
ons Problem for Coach;
Strong Pitching Staff</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1902-06-09/ed-1/?sp=6&q=badminton&r=-0.021,0.278,1.034,0.551,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Badminton Threatens
Ping Pongâ€™s VoQiie j
Badminton Is coming Into vogue again
In a way that promises to lay ping pong
on the shelf as a society game. English
social lights, which took so devotedly to
ping pong have begun to serve notice that
Badminton is in better taste, and a so
cial organ says of the game, â€œBadminton
can be played out of doors, on a lawn or
on a carriage drive, or indoors in a
large room. Two, three, four, six or
eight may play at once. The best game,
however, is six, when there are two wom
en up at each side of the net while a
man keeps back behind them. The game, j
as might be expected, derived its name
from the fact that it was first introduced j
in England by a member of a house par- j
ty at Badminton in the time of the late I
Duke of Beaufort.
Sober tennis players who had scorned
ping pong as something immeasurably
less than tennis may incline toward Bad
minton, though it, too, may be reduced
to indoor quarters. For. with the excep
tion of the balls used. Badminton is ten
nis. its plays and scores being observed
according to the same rules, and only
the lack of the rebounding quality in the
bails differing from tennis.
The ball used is the shuttlecock that
goes with the game of battledore. It is a
ball of cork, weighted with lead, or it
may be hard rubber, and in either case
it is winged with feathers, which causes
the ball to revolve, at the same time
flying swiftly, guided by the feather
wings. As the ball will not rebound when
striking the earth or floor, it must be
â€œvolleyed," and each failure to return
the ball is counted against the player
who misses.
For playing Badminton the best court 1
is 28 feet long and 20 feet wide, with the; j
service line ten feet from the base line.
A net one foot deep is stretchd across
the court five and a half feet above the
ground.
Only in the fact that these hard balls j
are winged, do not rebound, and have to I
be â€œvolleyed,â€ does the game differ from
tennis. In this volleying, however, is the
tension and strained interest for both
player and spectator, and as a rival for
ping pong it looks as if society needed
only to pass the word to effect the
change.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020645/1902-06-12/ed-1/?sp=10&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>CITY LEAGUE BALL OPENS
IN EARNEST SATURDAY
__
Falcons and Independents Will Line Up for a Re
cord-breaking Game of Ball on That
Bay-Sporting Melange.
When Ed Mahoney calls "play ball
Saturday afternoon the Inaugural game
of the new City League, an organUatim
that promises to be the most Â»uccewful
of the hind Montgomery has ever haa.
Will be on. The indication* arc that
there will bo a record breaWng crowd
for. aside from the fact that It is the
first of the league games the two teams,
the Falcons and Independents, are both
verv popular with a large following, both
making great reputations in the baseball
line last summer.
The patrons of the game will find
grounds, grand stand and bleachers n
as sehlpshape order as if professional nail
was being played. Yesterday a set of reg
ulation basts and a regulation rubber
borne plate were received. U
few people are aware of thefaettbat
the 190- home plate is responsible for the
phenomenal games being put up' W
pitchers in the different professional
leagues. The plate this season, instead
Iff being S'tuare is a kind of a triangle
and instead of a 12-inch front faring the
pin her It is 17 inches. I his gives the
pitcher five inches more play and he haa
all aorta of chances to cut the corners, a
great advantage to the man in the box
and a corresponding disadvantage to the
batter.
The street railway company yesterday
morning sent a big roller and mower out
to the grounds and President. Screws
had the infield thoroughly rolled and
packed and the grass in the outfield cu%
out. The street railway people are re
pairing the fences, wire-netting in the
grandstand and everything else that
needs repairs. They say that they will
have all the cars needed to take any kind
of crowd out to the games and bring
them home comfortably. A substantial
stand was being built yesterday for the
Infirmary Aid and will he ready by Sat
urday's game
One hour's hard practice a day has been
put in all this week by the Falcons and
Independents, and when they get on the
field Saturday both teams will be in the
pink of condition. After Saturday s game
the next league game will probably be
between the Gersts and Millers, the game
to be played for the benefit of the Confed
erate Soldiers' Home at Mountain Creek,
he President will be glad to heard from
ensacola. Columbus and any of the out
f-town teams.
The Memphis Commercial-Appeal has
the following:
Those who invested in the future pay
or play betting on the American Derby,
bai king Abo Frank. G. C. Bennettâ€™s colt
to win that classic, had just as well make
up their minds to part with the amounts
they wagered. Abe Frank has raced in a
manner since leaving Memphis to cause
a majority of those who backed him at
long odds during the winter to abandon
inv idea of cashing their bets for the
American Derby. There are still a few.
however, that cling to the adage of
"where there is life there is hope.
A letter received here yesterday from
G. C .Bennett says that Abe Frank has
started in his last IVrhy. He will not be
imong the field that faces the starter
n the American Derby a week from next
Saturday, and he will never be sent after
mother Derby. Mr. Bennett draws the
line on Derbies now and will go after :i
ear-old stakes, which are not featured
is Derbies.
The determination of Bennett to keep
Abe Frank out of the American Derby
will cause much tearing of tickets It:
Memphis. The colt received a liberal
,(Mount Â«Â»f backing during the wintei
when Hi odds wore offered at 10 to 1
Mr. Bennett holds tickets aggregatinj
Jl.oOft. which are now nothing but sum
mcr souvenirs of the winter Americai
Derby favorite.
Two big races will be run Saturday. th<
Suburban Handicap it Sheepshead pa;
md the St. Louis Derby.
This ear's St. Louis Derby will b<
one of the m Â»"t valuable year-old stake
decided Â«>n the American turf this sea
sou with thÂ®. exception of the Lawrenc
Realisation and the American Derby. The
Iaiwrenee Realisation, which is run at
Coney Island. *s worth about $30,000. while
the American Dert>y at Washington Park
has $20,000 added. The at. Louis Derby
will be worth about $15,000. This makes
It more valuable than either the Brook
lyn or Suburban handicaps. The 8t. Louis
Derby is a tjfie-honorcd classic with an
exceedingly Interesting history. It was
established in 1882. the year the present
Fair Grounds track was thrown open to
the public. B. C. Pate's Monogram won
the first St. Louis Derby, which was
worth $1,975 to the winner. In 1892 the
stake was abolished, but in 1896 was re
vived again under a different name, being
known as the National Derby. Prince
Lief won the stake in 1896. It had a
guaranteed value of $20,000 that year. In
1897 the stake was rechristened the St.
Louis Derby. It was worth $10,000 and
was captured by Ornament. John W.
Schorr has taken the last two Derbies,
with Sam Phillips in 1900 and Silverdale
in 1901. He will not have a starter this
year.
An Eastern tipster whose system is
"play the long shots.â€ advises against
the first choices by calling attention to
the downfall of favorites In 1901 and 1902
as follows:
In 1901:
Metropolitan. Starbright, 2 to 1. Lost.
Brooklyn Handicap. Banaster. 8 to 5,
Nit.
Suburban Handicap. Ethelbert, 7 to 6.
Trut.
Brighton Handicap, Alceds. 2 to 1,
Foozeled.
Futurity. Nasturtium. 2 to 1. No score.
Realization. Commando, 1 to 10. Got
the rinky-dink.
In 1902:
Carter Handicap, Himself, 7 to 5.
Dumped.
Metropolitan, Herbert. Down and out.
Withers. 0*4 Epgland. 2 to 1. Didnâ€™t.
Belmont, Compute, 2 to 1. Flung high
and dry.
Jockey Club Stakes, Heno, 7 to 10.
Went wrong.
Brooklyn Handicap. Advance Guard, 2
to 1. Hard luck.
English Derby, Scepter, 7 to 2. Too
much touting.
Badminton is coming Into vogue again
in a way that promises to lay ping pong
on the shelf air a society game. English
social lights, which took so devotedly to
ping pong, have begun to serve notice
that Badminton is in better taste, and a
social organ says of the game: â€œBad
minton can be played out of doors, on
a lawn or on a carriage drive, and in
doors in a large room. Two. three, four,
six or eight may play at once. The game,
however, is six. when there are two wo
men up at each side of the net while a
man keeps back behind them. The game,
as might be expected, derived its name
from the fart that it was first intro
duced in England by a member of a
house,.party at Badminton in the time
of the late Duke of Beaufort.â€
Sober tennis players who have scorned
ping pong as sometimes immeasurably
less than tennis may incline towards
Badminton, though it. too, nay he re
duced to indoor quirters. For. with the
exception of the balls used. Badminton is
tennis. Its plays and scores being oh
served according to the same rules, an-1
only the lack of the rebounding quality
in the balls differing from tennis.
The ball used is the shuttlecock that
goes with the gamr of battledore. It is a
ball of cork, weighted with lead, or it
may he hard robber, and in either case it
is winged with feathers, which causes
the hall to revolve, at the same time
flying swiftly, guided by, th$ feather
wings. As the ball will not rebound when
striking the earth or floor, it must be
â€œvolleyed.â€ and each failure to return
the ball is counted against the player
who misses.
Only in the fact that these hard halls
are winged, do not rebound, and have to
be "volleyed.â€ does the game dffTer from
tennis. Tn this volleying, however, is the
tension and strained interest for both
played and spectator, and as a rival for
ping pong it looks as 1f society needed
only to pass the word to effect the
change.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84027524/1950-01-27/ed-1/?sp=8&q=badminton&r=-0.028%2C-0.044%2C1.215%2C0.647%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Wants State Badminton
Association Revived
Interested in a state badminton
association is the Sunburst Bad
minton club.
Objective of the association
would be to promote and develop
the game, assist in the organiza
tion of clubs, conduct a state tour
nament and assist junior clubs and
school clubs.
There was a state badminton as
sociation before the war. The last
state tournament was held in Lew
istown in 1943.
The Sunburst Badminton club is
holding their 15th annual tourna
ment February 19. Persons inter
ested in either the tournament, the
state association or the game
should notify Jim Greer, Sunburst.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92073229/1940-03-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=badminton&r=0.363%2C0.836%2C0.865%2C0.46%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Badminton Chief
N. B. Adam* Elected President of
New Sports Organisation
N. B. Adams, professor of
Spanish in the University, was
elected president of the Chapel
Hill Badminton Club Monday
evening at a meeting at the Caro
lina Sport Shop. Other officers
elected were Mrs. P. S. Randolph,
vice-president; D. P. Henry, sec
retary and G. T. Goebbel, treas
urer.
About 30 persons attended the
meeting, and many more have in
quired about the plans of the
new c)ub.
It wad decided to hold matches
from 7 to 9:80 every Tuesday
and Thursday evenings in the
gymnasium at the elementary
school. Everybody interested in
playing badminton is myited to
take part.
Mr. Henry said yesterday that
facilities for badminton in the
school gymnasium are among the
best in the state.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1940-07-05/ed-1/?sp=7&q=badminton&st=text&r=-0.403,0.543,1.805,1.805,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Iftiday, July S' 1940
m
B,y E FREEMAN COMING
V tennis champ
I Last week we told you some-
B |rr 0 f the 19-year-old Jewish
player from the Coast who
being groomed as a forthcom-
M Davis Cup Star. Weâ€™ve more
K lay on the line for you today
â– onceming the technique and abi-
K v 0 f this Pomona College soph-
Kore who ranked twenty-second
Hjthe national listings last sea
ion and who looms as another
Kne Lacoste. (Lacoste, you will
â– ecall, has been the only Jewish
Bonis player on any Davis Cup
HFreeman reached the tennis
Bourts through a thoroughly nat-
Bral route. His rapid rise to fame
Brngresses from ping pong to bad-
Binton to tennis in six short
Bears. At the age of 13 he won a
â– ew small trophies as a table ten-
Bis menace. By the time he was
Seventeen, only two years ago, he
B-as garnering gold and silver tro-
Bhies. He has more than a hun-
Bed cups.
I But table tennis was childâ€™s
Blay and Dave turned to badmin-
Bon as more strenuous fare. (If
Bouâ€™ve never played this sportâ€”
Bhich is rapidly becoming a fav-
Brite winter indoor pastimeâ€”get
Bt out of your heads that itâ€™s a sis-
Byâ€™s game. It's strenuous, fast,
Bad requires plenty of skilL Some
Bonsider it more arduous than ten-
Bb.)
kl And it was only two years ago
Bhat Dave came out of the West
Bn unknown quantity at this game
MYRTLE AVENUE
LUMBER CO.
Lumber and Building
Supplies
Myrtle Ave. at Elm St
Phene 5-4260
BONO
CLEANERS Mid DYERS
WE CALL AND DELIVER
til Garments Fully Protected
By Insurance
Phone 3-9254 1005 Forest St.
SANDWICH INN
MAIN AT 27TH
PARK AT GILMORE
MIAMI ROAD IN
SO. JACKSONVILLE
Ride Safety With Safety
Safetp Cabo, Inc.
6-7890 X IOC
Authorized and Bonded
_ BAGGAGE TRANSFER
I! CAN. BE DONE
\g&
A "o WE CAN DO IT
There will be no repaired
appearance to your shoes.
A neat, smooth job from
toe to heeL
u Modem methods plus
Steerhead" Sole Leather
do the trick.
Let us prove it
LÂ°msSHOE SHOP
028 Pearl St. Phone 5-2986
We Appreciate your Patronage
POWELLâ€™S LITTLE FOLK* FURNITURE
â€œBABY FIRST*'
827 LAURA STREET
WE FEATURE THE LAY-AWAY FLAN
JEWS IN
SPORTS
ly Morris Weiner
and a kid who was beginning to
show an aptitude with the tennis
racket. At that time, in tourna
ments in Philadalphia, those who
watched him closely were con
vinced that they saw symptoms of
excellence.
Last year, while still a junior
performer, this Pasadena young
ster returned to New York. On
that occasion there was no un
certainty about his high-geared
play at badminton. He had ironed
out the rough spots, profiting by
his knowledge that tennis had
yielded him in the National junior
championships at Culver, Indiana.
He won the junior title two years
ago and last year was succeeded
by his chief rival on the Pacific
Coast, Ted Shroeder.
No other American performer
with the tennis racket and bad
minton bat has ever scaled the
heights Freeman has attained. He
was a star of the first magnitude
in the national badminton cham
pionships in New York last year.
His blend of tennis and badmin
ton was smooth, according to the
experts, and in the recent shut
tlecock championship at Seattle
Freeman was the whole show, ta
king no fewer than three national
championships.
He is so strong at both games
that the Californian looms as the
overpowering force in any cham
pionship at either game. It is al
so interesting to observe that
Freeman trounced Hank Prusoff
at badminton in the latterâ€™s home
town, thereby retaliating for the
defeat suffered at Forest Hills
last season at the hands of the
lad who went on to rate thirteenth
in the Nationals.
....By the way, the record books
also reveal that Davis Freeman is
the first Californian who has
achieved the highest honor in this
respect. He has made a record at
badminton which few can equal
and which only one other player
in the country has been able to
equal thus far. Freeman made
grand slam in singles and doubles.
The only player to do that hith
erto was Mrs. Del Barkhuff then
of Seattle and now of Honolulu,
who did the triple victory back in
1937, when this national event
was inaugurated in Chicago.
At a recent badminton tourna
ment, Dave was awarded the top
seeding, as champion, in singles,
He took that event with scarcely
any formidable opposition, suc
cesfully defending his crown as
there was no opponent capable of
taking him into camp.
And here you have the reasons
for it. Heâ€™s amazingly fast on
his feet, quick of anticipation and
durable for a long session. Speed,
stamina and sense three prere
quisites of the tennis player.
Freeman has made it evident
that he has what it takes in bad
minton and tennis to rate as a na
tional champion and to justify his
sponsorâ€™s predictions that in him
we have a future Davis Cup play
er and what is more the first Jew
ish Davis Cup player in America.
Judge Hardy, former interna
tional Davis Cup team captain,
who is pushing Daveâ€™s tennis as
pirations wrote in the U. S. Lawn
Tennis Journal only last month:
â€œFreeman has shown remark
able ability to round out his ten
nis stronkes. This makes him par
ticularly dangerous in the fore
court, repeatedly turning defen-</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025812/1931-11-13/ed-1/?sp=12&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Badminton'* Origin
The game of badminton, in crA
form, wns first played in India.w
was called poonit after th* t0l|
In which It originated. It
brought to England in 1S72 l?y?w.
lsh army officers and in 1ST.
Darned badminton in honor o'.t^
duke of Beaufort, at whose
Badminton, the game wns form*
Introduced.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78002169/1942-05-28/ed-1/?sp=3&q=badminton&r=0.032%2C0.108%2C0.92%2C0.49%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Game Of Badminton
Takes Camp Davis
Personnel By Storm
Badminton, originated by British
army officers in India 98 years
ago, has taken Camp Davis by
storm. Scores of soldiers are play
ing the game every night in the
week, making use of the courts at
Farnsworth Hall.
The craze has gained such im
petus that it has been necessary
to move the bleachers in the sports
arena to make room for additional
courts.
The athletic office loans out
rackets and sells the birds, or shut,
tlecocks at cost to the players.
Similar to tennis, badminton is
played with lighter rackets and in
stead of a ball the shuttlecock is
used.
The shuttlecock is made of feath
ers inserted and cemented in a
half sphere of cork. Object of the
game is to keep the â€œbirdâ€ in
the air. Nets, higher than those
used in tennis, are strung across
the badminton courts.
Among the officers of Camp Da
vis who can be classed (more or
less) as experts at badminton are
Major J. B. Yost; Lieut. R. F.
Bailey, and Lieut H. A. Johnson.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>





  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-labor-day/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1882-09-07/ed-1/?sp=4&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union&r=0.037,0.309,0.709,0.377,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>.1 IABOB DE3IOXSTRATIOX.
There waa little In the parade ol Tm
[n thia city, or ln any ol the many di Bcriptioua
which wi re yeaterday publiahed ol it. or iu the
...ir repoiti 1 ai haying been
ntade on tbe fK-caainn, n hich gave it or them
tbe character of o labor demonattation. There
wan iirj m the ajipcarauce of the raen lo
itidicate thal (hcj were aull iring for good
clothea or were wcak trom long (famialiing
They were nol only ueatly and comfortably,
l.ut in many caaearather extravaguntlj dicaaed.
Aud tbey n.ly nutrehed briaklj iu tlu--uu
foi many tnilea, bul a greal m iltitude of them
danced briakly aud liatem 1 t-> rather dull
apeecbea for the better part of the oftenuMin
There waa m> bread, bul plentj ol Iteer, pro
ided for them, and tbey bad I'hiinge to paj for
i;. Thegatbtring bad nuiie ol the aapecta of a
I.,, ,,,i riot, bul every aemblance ol ii pi< uic oi
a politiral barbecae.
The insenptiona ou the bunncra i an acarccly
l?. aaid to repreaeul truthfulij the aeuti
pnvailing amonghoneal workingmen. S.?
oi iiinl. w.-n rathei old un< ilioriania
uthep were pro|K>aitiona which noimd) ever
in?j w bile m urly all were |h>
litiral, tmdii in ijority were i ib inagog
il, hie w< rkingmen are nol liki 1;- i un
im dj on the propoaitioii thal "All mcii
.ui- iioni alike and ei| uil oi th? aeutimeiil
-i. ;n.,? Cniiin and tlu y bave uni
BUpp -n l':
Ci, ld Labor and pul ::!l
Solioola, nol iu iiu lorii Bi
.,,i thal l. ibor buill thia I and
Bhall riilr it," and tli il I iboi i a
i,,,,-. and shoubl i'.i no rcnl aml thal aa
iu ,.i i- im ,ii tke lun I, beuce no
-iini.lil ow ii n," tin\ -iiinl. rniae up donhtera
ii .1 long theii t>a n la--.
il,,-,- aeul in aud aimilar onea b
[utiud di iplaj. aie 10I mlj il aml
bul they do nol liml nctcptani i
more th in one In a>rer i u erj biiu
uinl. aml thal one ia more of an i
or demagogue thau itnythiug elae. Bryoud
tbeae itcd tbe iuacriptiona were purely political,
and -ot a very i" or -oir ol |K>titic? al thal.
I'be cartoona, too?aud then were aeveral dia
played?bad nothing in them otuei Iban
aiiggc dioua oi o political natnn
I ln- apeecuea were lacking in referencea to
the impoveriahed conditiou ol thewoikiugmaii,
bu( couiaiui (1 a groa1 deal aboul bia political
poverty uwiug Uitbe Eualavetueui of Labor bj
Capital. Monopoly, Saiional Bauka, VYealth and
Politica, all with i>i^', big capital b ttera, >r
ganization aud tbe Bullol were uientioned
:1> (it<- only I rue Remedj. Politica uol pov
,ii\ n-aa anatbematiztd as tbe cauae of all tbe
woi-Hoi tlie workiugman. In ahoit, tl.fina
gogue diaplayed biuieeli and wbat be bad to
?cll al every atep. It ia one tbing tu orgauizr
ii Utrge foree ol Idle workingmen, even of thoae
uboYO the general average ol intelligeuce, for
b public demonatration ol utnnbera wben tbey
areled to beliere that tbe demonatration ia
parely non-i?artiaan bol ijulte another tbing
io lead Ihem into a political oi g-aaization to be
uiauipulated uud aold oul by aeli-appoiuted
leadei Ibe so-called labor demouatrutiou of
Tueaday waaao pal^ably a political orgai
tion iii.it even the leaal Intelligeul and tbink
ingman ln the parademual bavediacovered
it b] tbia time.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1884-09-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union&st=text&r=-0.237,-0.069,0.987,1.051,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LABORS MONSTER PARADE
TIlE flllHT lIOHKtfiUXKVS HOLIDAY
JO UK ftrtY OHHERrZlt
Thnnaanela uC Artlsnna anal Iulxrers tu
March Tuilny Around the lly Hall cad
Vu Hrnitilwuy llilo Their frarta
Tho worklugmcu Bay they will have
200 men In line In the great labor parndo to
day and that tho day generally will be observed
throughout the city as a worklngmens holiday
day The Central Labor Union have been busy
four months with Ibo details and have already
begun n movement In several other cities to
have the frt Monday In September 1 univer
sal holiday for worklngmen
Typographical Union No 0 and kindred
trades will have the right of the line I will
form before 10 oclock In Uroome street right
resting on Centre street The printer will
have carriages for women printer They
think they will have 3500 men out altogether
A patriarchal printer will do his bAt a the
line moves to run the press that Benjamin
Franklin started In tho printing business with
William McCabe the printer delegate t the
Central Labor Union will b the Grand Mar
stial of the parade
Next to the printers in Broorue streetS Marion
street and Marion square will form the first
division InK trades proper made up of men In the build
There will b throe union ol the bricklayers I
the hodboIIUnIOOllneer the granite stone
cutters flue plasterers the Painter Union
the Progressive 1Hlnters Union No1 the
framcrs twelve divisions of tho laborers and
the hoimnmltlis Tho laborers say that about
ISO nf their number will carry hod tilled with
brlik nnd mortar
The Wendell Phillips Organization No2 of
colored men will liar tire right of tie second
III iilon They nay they hero disposed 1 of 1000
tIckets to paraderH They asked for ROO more
yesterday They Include all colored working
men Clgarmnkeis Progrcsfhe Unions Nos
1 and 22 the Clan Puckers Union No 10 the
clothing totters thin knife garment cutters and
tho tailors the piano makers thin coal shovel
lers HIM fiunlturu makers the upholsterers
tint Iarvorx nnd the varnlhnrs the trunk
mnkerxof Newark and the associated trades
lu Newark and nil unorganized trades not rep
resented In the Central Labor Union will 101
lowed tint colored men In the frcond division
The clgarmakers have engaged two large
Wagons and will niMke cigars on them They
will distribute tIlt cigars they go They nay
Io
they hnvn permission of the Internal I revenue
officials to make the cigars on route They
will have 2000 men in line The second di
vision will form in Canal street right resting
on Centre street
Tlm third division will consist of the
butchers unions the shoemakers tho horse
Bhoers the machinists the coopers the dry
goods clerks the shoo salesmen the silk
alk
ribbon neuvers the glees workers the gold
frame makers the shoe lastnrs the dock build
ers nnd the tin and sheet Iron workers The
glass workers will ply their Industry on three
wagons This division will form In White
street and Elm street right retting on Centre
Tho assistant mar hnls will be John J
Knnney of Krlcklaynrs Union No fhOf the first
division Frederick Huller of Progressive
Clgarmakem Union No 1 ot the second and
Tbomu J lllesslng of the Eastern Butcher
Protective Union of the third
The Grand MxrOials aids are Wm H Bailey
ar
I Baiey
of the Concord Labor Club Sylvester Kulllvan
of bricklayers Union No 4 Lorenzo Ernst of
tho IrnnierV Union George I McVeyof the
Piano Iakr Union Charles L Miler of the
Clothing Cutters Union William Blanoy of
the Excelsior Labor Club Daoor
A feature of the parade I will b massive col
ored Capt Frank IFerrnll of the hod hoisting
nnnliuvrs Ho will hove 100 membrR hol8tnl
union under his command as policemen
At 11 oclock sharp the first division will
wi
move down Centre street the second division
dllAlon
will fall In line at Canal street and the third
division will fall In at White street The pro
cession will move down Centre street to Print
ing House square to Park row to Mall street
Broadway to Fourteenth street round Union
square to t H eiitentU street to Fifth avenue
to Twentytlfth retreat and then AVOnUl
1h
procession will ho reviewed from the cottage at
Union sritinre by the followingnamed gentle
men Patrick Ford Henry Georgo Alex Jonas
P J McGulre Louis F Post John Hwlnton
lwlnlon
Dr Htelbllng Henry O Cole Dr A Douai Vic
tor Drury Robert BlInsert and others
A picnic In Joness Wood will follow The
athletic games at Joness Wood will begin at 3
oclock There wilt b speechmaklng afterward
Supt C I Hnnklnson of Mr Bcrghs society
presented this letter to the Central Labor Union
yesterday
OiiTitiirf Tomorrow morning a vast procession of
labor oruitnUattuns taken place In this elI1 uppeifrs
bv the daily papers Ainoinr them I am this u moment
Informed the butchers are In bu rtpresented a1 liar
ilnrln their mach animals are to be slaughtered upon
the l nhltc hlghwat t
I liex reiiiectfull and enrnelly In protest aralnst
stttli an llleiral and demoralizing exhibition In so do
Imf let me add that mv oppoHltlnn tirUes from no want
ofsinpatli with rust Wrest und honorable I represcnta
tlnn ne the light of labor of u erv irgrec I ant character
which the proponed procession designs lo Cite I expres
sioil In but 00 eh 1 to H feature of It which while 11 I In
cruel I demoralulnir I i and I iiniierenBary I would shot I the I
humsiie sensibilities I of our cltUens I and act Injuriously I
to the interests of all I iiibor oritanutitlons hereafter I
1 I us 111 be concedid that I I Is an unfortunate nefeltv
of our i litMion Ills killlntr I and eatimrnf the lekh of
animals but thai I ell requirement does not I extend 1 to
a uuntull pal fide of the I d tltir nifnnle of Innocent crea
lures wlille surrendering their hue for tho lien tit of
our rate Iheirtull i t belies p thut this resj ectfnl protest
rlu 111 l
test does not Jirocted from coy morl Id feniinieiiiiiflt
hut is based on Ilie smrKestinn of liutiiaoitv alll tiro
prletv and a due reifttrd to that civilization without
whlcn men lure Piraicre
Miireover tIn laws I of the land forbid the exhibition
proposed hirst tliereU asintiiteof tlio t Mate prohibit
li
ion the unnecessary muillatmnor I killing of eli animal I
seiondl the latts I of lie Health Hoard assUn certain
lint lii II the locslit where kiilniali ma lie i slauuhterrd
Klnally permit me to sav that the limlltiiiion I repre
sent has been appointed by the Mat to take coirnlzaree
tlIJ IJ
tl all matters relatlnK 1 I in 117 ri nun 1 herewith pro
test politely but In accordance with tin ohlliratloni
ImpoKid 111 request vein to suppress tlm above nmned
shocking much liii from your programme P lh great
respect InKY IIIKUll
Stiporlntendent Hanklnann said thai his
agents had been to look nt tine cattle which
were to be slaughtered and had heard from the
biitcheiH that such wan their intention
Grand Marnhal McCabe said that I was tho
butchers first Intention to butcher the cattle
but he had 1 found out that the law forbade it
He had not spoken to the butchers but he 0 II
llncd they would comply with tire law They
are to have two abattoirs on wheels</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1885-09-08/ed-1/?sp=2&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Labor's Holiday.
The first observance in tho state of
Minnesota of the 7th of September as a
national labor holiday passed off success
fully. The celebration was intended not
only to secure a day of recreation and rest.
but as an assertion of the growing intention
of the producer to secure recognition.
Other days In the year are set apart to
memorialize certain historical events, and
when the call was issued on the part of the
Trades and Labor assemblies of the cities of
Minneapolis, St. Paul and Stillwater for
ttie workingmen to take this one day of the
year for themselves, as a dedication to the
cause of their advancement, very few were
found who did not acknowledge the justice
and right of the demand. The mayors of
both .St. Paul and Minneapolis issued proc
lamations approvlving the celebration, and
employers generally did not attempt any
opposition. About :;,000 people attended
t he
LABOB PICNIC
at White Beai lake. Of this number prob
ably 1,500 came from Minneapolis, 1,300
from St. Paul and 300 from Stillwater. An
address was made by Richard Griffith of
igo, general worthy foreman of the
Knights of Labor, supplemented by re
murks from Dr. Ames of Min
neapolis. A program of sports
was carried out. while dancing
and boating contributed to lill up a day of
pleasure. The trains arrived from the
three cities at the lake about 11 o'clock in
the morning and the excursionists first
gathered in the pavilion at Cottage Park,
the Metropolitan band of St. Paul
discoursed music very acceptably. After
calling the meeting to order J. P. Mc-
Gaughey of Minneapolis, the president
of the day, introduced Richard
Griffith of Chicago, who had
been secured to make the address.
As the applause which greeted him died
away. Mr. Griffith stepped forward, and
after returning thanks lor the cordial greet
ing took up his theme, which might be
characterized as the
BENEFITS OP OKOA3TIZATIOX.
lie reviewed the history of the Knights
of Labor, going back to the time when ii was
a secret order. It was then denounced by
both press and pulpit, which did not under
stand its true nature. Being oath bound,
its members were prevented from replying
and were forced quietly to submit to mis
representation and imposition. The Knights
struggled on until 1880, when the general
assembly met at Detroit, Mich., and made
public the name and objects of the organiza
tion. Since then the march has been on
mard and upward, and the last assembly
organized m Chicago two weeks ago was
No. 4109.
The speaker then went on to illustrate
the difference between Trades unions and
the Knights of Labor. The unions are ex
clusive and take care only of themselves.
When a strike occurs in one trade, the
others simply look on and render no assist
ance, showing that
'â€¢Tho weil-fcdpig 1 in the sty doth lip.
Regarding not tho cry of the hungry one that
passetli by."
The Knights of Labor are broader in their
humanity and regard an injury to one as
the concern of all. It receives into its fold
all who work for an honest living, no mat
ter whether he may be a street scraper or a
skilled mechanic. All stand on an equal
basis and only the non-providersâ€”the bank
ers, lawyers, saloonkeepers and gamblers
are refused admittance.
To illustrate the efficacy of standing by
one another, as advocated by the Knights of
Labor, the speaker cited the great strike at
Pittsburg. The Brotherhood of Locomotive
Engineers was an exclusive organization.
When they struck the railroad company
simply tilled their places with firemen,
those of the Bremen with brakemen, and the
brakemen with yardmen. If the Locomo
tive Engineers, instead of being an exclus
ive union, had been an assembly of the
Knights of Labor, the other trades would
have stood by them and the railroad com
pany could not have filled their places.
The Knights of Labor are, however,
OPPOSED TO STRIKES
and court the settlement of differences by
arbitration. It opposes convict labor and is
doing the utmost to accomplish its abolition.
The effect of convict labor throughout the
whole United States is not strongly felt.
perhaps, but it affects localities disastrously
to the workingmen. For instance, Chicago
is tiie market for the boots and shoes
manufactured in eight penitentiaries.
No wonder many of the shoemakers of that
city are idle!
The Knights of Labor are also opposed
to child labor. In this connection n picture
was drawn of how the "store" and other
large mercantile establishments of Chicago
employ hundreds of little boys and girls at
wages ranging from Si to $1.50 per week.
These children should be in school, fitting
themselves for usefulness in life.
The Knights of Labor are also opposed
to the robbery of the public lands by specu
lators and the titled aristocrats who have
for 700 years deprived the people of the old
country of their lands and who now are
striving to steal the lands from the people
of the United States. Through the efforts
of the Knidit* of Labor the foreign con
tract system has been abolished, and the
stealing of public lands will also be pre
vented by the same means.
The Knights of Labor are opposed to the
discriminations of the law in favor of
CAPITAL AS AGAINST LABOR.
What this discrimination means? was
shown by the fact that in Chicago the fail
ure of savings brinks robbed So, 000 people
of their hard-earned savings, while the
bank presidents under the protection of the
law are allowed to retain and enjoy their
ill-gotten gams. The man who steals a loaf
of bread because Of starvation is also pro
tected by lawâ€”but is sent to prison.
"The law condemns the man or woman
Who steals the goose from off the common,
Bui lets tho greater felon lose,
Who steals the eoramna from thciroosc."
Mr. Griffiths then went on to describe a
pic. urc he had seen which portrayed the
workingman aa struggling to support the
aristocracy nnd non-producers, saying it
was time that labor should find or.t "why it
receives only 40 per cent, of the wealth it
produces. Why it has to pay for all the
show.
After picturing the misery and poverty
of the poor people, who live in the slums of
great cities. Mr. Grlfllihs closed by strongly
urging the advancement of harmony in the
ranks of labor, and expressed the hope that
Minnesota would be found tailing the lead
Ul every effort made to raise upon his feet
the down trodden son of toil. At the con
clusion of his remarks Mr. Griffiths was
heartily applauded. There were loud calls
for ex-Mayor Ames of Minneapolis, who
was present and that gentleman made a
brief address in response. He said he con
-1 himself workingman and was
1 take his holiday with the rest.
Me believed In the organization of
labor and thought that only in this way
could recognition be secured. He advised
them to beware of the men who could be
hired to betray their cause, while the fullest
confidence should be laced in ffibse who
have given proof of their fidelity. He did
not care, he sr.id. to detain his hearers with
any extended remarks. They were all
there for fun and frolic and the shorter the
speeches the better.
The doctor's concluding hit was the signal
for a rush for dinner. Those who "had
brought lunch baskets gathered their friends j
about them, vhwo o:.iucs patronized the
very palatable lunch which had been j
furnished by the Ladies' Aid society of St.
PaoL
At 12:80 o'clock the train from St. Paul
THE ST. PAUL DAILY GLOBE. TUESDAY MORNING, SEPTEMBER 8, 1885â€”TWELVE PAGES:
brought out about fire hundred more excur-
sionists, and shortly after their arrival</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040340/1894-08-31/ed-1/?sp=8&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
NATIONAL LABOR DAY.
Congress Has Officially Bo cog
nized the Right of Our Toilers.
A Day Set Apart for Rest and Recreation
In the Interest of tho Laboring- Man
Some Stites Already I'rovld-
ed Tor by Statute.
Special Lcttcr.l
Ihc cause of labor received an im
portant recognition in one of the few
hills just passed by the present con
gress that making the first Monday
in September henceforth a national
holiday devoted to the cause of tho
toiler and set apart for a rest-day in
tho workingman's interest. Other
sentiments and classes arc already
jwell remembered in the year's calen
dar. There is patriotism in Fourth of
July celebrations, remembrance of vet
erans at Decoration day, acknowledg
ment of favors of Providence at Thanks
giving, gifts at Christmas, social duties
Dn New Year's and religious ceremo
nials at Easter. But there has never
been in American customs any recog
nition of tho laboring classes in gen
erally observed holidays.
The origin of Labor day dates back
to 1SS0, when following the labor diffi-
ex-gov. rrasiriniEr, of kansas.
cnlties of 1877 the cause of the labor
unions received a considerable im
petus. There was a demand for a
general gala occasion, and in the labor
assembly of New York the matter of
adopting a special day for this purpose
was discussed. No particular resnlt
was attained beside adopting the first
Monday in September as a day for
worklngmcn's relaxation.
With the recurrence of the season the
idea spread, and labor unions of all
lands came to select a day in the first
week of September for their celebra
tions of this kind, the custom spread
ing from the cities and manufacturing
towns to the country districts until it
was well nigh national in its extent.
Up to 1890, however, no state observ
ance of the day had taken plack. In
August of that year Gov. L. U. Hum
jphrey, of Kansas, by request of the
'Topcka trades assembly, issued a proc
lamation setting ;aside the first day of
September for a labor holiday and ask
ing the people of the commonwealth to
devote the occasion to tho interest of
the toilers. The proclamation was an
innovation, and Gov. Humphrey was
criticized by many for his action.
Time, however, demonstrated his good
judgment, for several other governors
speedily followed his example and
ttatc legislatures took action on tho
(subject until, before congress had na
tionalized the day, more than half tho
states already had labor days of their
own.
The bill adopted June 23 was advo
cated by Congressman Cummings, who
immediately after its passage by house
and senate took it himself to President
,Clevcland and witnessed its signature.
The bill was a long time on the cal
endar, but required only a short timo
for reading or discussion, for it is ex
ceedingly brief. It is as follows:
"I3c it enacted, etc.. That tho first Monday
in September in each year, being tho day cele
brated and known as Labors holiday, is hcrc
fcy made a lcpl public holiday, to all intents
cad purposes, in the same manner as Christ
inas, the 1st dav of January, tho 2d day of
February, tho 3Cth day of May and tho 4th
day of July arc cow made by law public holi
days." In one respect the law is a curious
one. for it is unusual for congress to
legislate on the subject of holidays ex
cept for the District of Columbia.
There are exceptions, but they are of
a special character. April 30, 18S9, the
centennial anniversary of the inaugura
tion of the first president was made a
national public holiday throughout
the United States by the act of March
2, 1SS9. The last congress also passed
a joint resolution authorizing the pres
ident to recommend October 1, 1S92,
the four hundredth anniversary of the
discovery of America, as "on- to be
observed by the people by public dem
onstrations, and suitable exercises in
the schools and other places. These
arc the only national holidays pro
vided for by congress outside of this
latest addition to the list. It is ob
jected by some that the putting of
the day en the plane of the others
mentioned in the act is misleading
since none of them is a. national holi
day in a technical sense. They are
mado holidays hy state law or by na
tional enactment limited in its appli
cation to the District of Coluuroia.
Zren Thanksgiving day, though desig- j
natcd by the president, becomes a pub
lic holiday only by state legislation
providing that any day designated by
president or governor as a day of
thanksgiving shall be a public holiday.
Some states, including Pennsylvania,
already have a Labor day of their own,
set apart by state legislation, and have
chosen the first Saturday in September
rather than -the first Monday as being
more suitable to the laboring classes
who get a holiday at the end of the
week s work rather than the beginning.
The question arises in such cases: Dave
these states now two Labor days or
shall the federal holiday take pre
cedence over that of the common
wealth? A change in the state laws
to conform with the new conditions
may be expected next winter in these
states.
The setting apart of a holiday for
labor celebrations is due perhaps more
to the Knights of Labor than any one
organization. The celebrations are
nearly always held under the auspices
of this body, although there is gen
erally a hearty cooperation on the part
of other societies of workingmen and
those interested in their cause. The
late head of the order, T. V. Powderly,
was its enthusiastic supporter for
years.
The Labor day observance is not
similar to that of any other holiday.
It approaches the Fourth of July, but
is without the hilarity and exuberance
of that occasion. There is an under
tone of seriousness that tells of tho
earnestness of the cause of the work
ingman and shows the importance of
his interests in the development of
American civilization.
The chief feature of the day is a
parade but it is not a procession de
voted to drum majors and bunting. It
is more in the nature of a trades' dis
ply in which every avocation is repre
sented by workmen busy at their va
rious trades. Then there is a big pic
nic dinner rand later the speeches,
which are a far more important por
tion of the progammc than in most
other holidays. In th addresses there
has often been a tendency to a radical
presentation of the cause of the work
men, and the occasion has sometimes
been taken advantage of by reckless
agitators who have seized tho opportu
nity to express un-American and un
patriotic ideas.
While it is perhaps true that some
what extreme ideas are more readily
received than upon occasions like In
dependence day it is not generally dono
without disapprobation, and with tho
day made a rest day for the whole na
tion instead of for a particular class or
section, its observance will become far
more broad and less marred by any ex
pression tending to arouse antagonism
between the toilers and any other class
whatever.
The significance of the day is far
reaching, and the unanimity with
which congress indorsed it. the bill
a Hi
GRAND MASTER WORKMAX SOVEREIGN.
passing practically without opposition
in cither branch of congress, proves the
sympathy with which it has been re
ceived by those high in authority.
Indications arc that it will be moro
generally observed this year than ever
before in the nation's history, and the
problems that confront labor and have
received so much discussion during the
past few months will be prominently
before the gatherings in every village,
city and hamlet in the nation for so
lution. It is an encouragiug sign that labor
has received this recognition, and that
the United States of America has been
the first nation on earth to make so
important a concession to the laboring
classes. It is not only a permanent
concession, for such an enactment can
never be abrogated, but it will, if
rightly used, aid in bringing about a
hotter understanding of the laborques
tion, now 60 prominent in political and
ethical economy the world over.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1894-09-03/ed-1/?sp=4&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LABOR WILL REST.
A Grand Parade of Six
Divisions.
GRIEVANCE OF THE UNIONS.
How the Labor Day Law Was
Blundered With.
THE LEADING AIEN OF THE FETE.
Exercises in Metropolitan Temple.
A Theatrical Performance in
Turn Verein Hall.
Labor day will be appropriately cele
brated to-day, in spite of the general mis
understanding as to whether or not it is a
legal holiday. The various labor unions
in San Francisco and Alameda County
will turn out for a grand parade, with
music and floats and banners and oratory.
Hut it will not be entirely satisfactory to
the labor unions as a whole, because only
a limited number of members will be per
mitted to participate. Stores, shops and
factories will be kept in operation pretty
much the same as if no national Labor day
exited in the statute-books of the United
States or of California. The members of
the various labor unions feel that they
have a grievance and a grudge against
some manipulator of legislative proceed
ings.
The bill which passed tbe California
Legislature, and became a law, desig
nating the first Monday in October of each
year as a legal holiday and "Labor
day," was introduced by the efforts of the
laboring men. In its original state it des
ignated the first Monday in September as
Labor's day, and it passed to engrossment
in that condition. But, through some
hocus pocus not explainable, the engrossed
bill changed thÂ« time to tbe first Monday
in October, and in the rush of business it
was passed without tbe change being ob
served, and received the Governor's signa
ture. That is the grievance.
The San Francisco Labor Council sent a
communication on the subject to Governor
Markuam, asking if he would not ignore
the statute and issue a proclamation fix
ing Labor day on the first Monday ol
September. But this the Governor de
clined to do. In his reply, however, he
stated that if tbe labor unions throughout
the State desire to have the date changed
in conformity with the original bill, lie
will recommend such change to the next
Legislature.
How the change in tbe original Dill
came about no one seems to know. It may
have been a mere clerical error on the
part ot the engrossing clerk, or, for some
reason not clearly understood, it may have
been brought about intentionally. There
was at the lime the bill passed consider
able opposition to tbe measure, owing to
the closeness of Admission day, Septem
ber 9, to the proposed Labor day. and it is
suspected that tbe change was effected by
and through the influence of this opposi
tion. Last yenr tbe labor unions refused
1 to accept the first Monday in October as i
I labor's holiday, and, therefore, appropri
ated the corresponding Monday of Sep
tember the national dayâ€” and celebrated
to the best of their ability.
This year they will do the same, and the
autumn sun will shine upon a grand street
parade and the ocean winds will be stayed
in their course by the music of many
I instruments.
As many of the federated toilers in this
city and OaKland as can obtain leave of
absence irom their employers will attend
and participate in the celebration. Of
course the demonstration will not -be so
great as if it were in fact a legal holiday
by legal enactment. But it will be credi
table so far as it can go.
W. J. B. Mackay of the Sailors' Union
of tbe Pacific is the grana marshal of the
day. His chiefs of staff are: E. P. Bur
man ot the Furniture Workers' Union. L.
lluey of the Sailors' Union and H. lingers
of the Typographical Union. These gen
tlemen, together with the appointed aids,
will meet at the junction of Bush, Battery
and Market streets at 10 o'clock to-day.
The procession will be formed atth.it
point and will start punctually at 11
o'clock. It will be made up in tbe follow
ing order:
First divisionâ€” The Typographical Union
with a baud of music and Moat and 500 men;
.1. W. Newton, marshal 01 tbe union, and J. i.
Uoiton, aid.
ThY Pressmen's Union, 100 men and a float,
carrying a decorated press.
Second divisionâ€” TDe Uorseshoers' Union,
100 men, with a baud and a float; M. M. Don
nelly, marshal.
The Ironâ€” Union, 100 men.
The Stonecutters' Union, 100 men, with a
baud aud a float.
Third divisionâ€” The Sailor* Union of the
Pacific, 800 men, with a band, also a platoon
of sixteen young eiils, sailors' daughters, at
tired hi sailor costume.
Tim Coopers' Union, 200 men, with a band.
Fourth divisionâ€” Tailors' Union, 200
nun, with a baud.
The Carpenters' Unions, Nos. 483 and 304,
175 meu, with a float.
Fifth divisionâ€” bakers' Union No. 24, 75
men. with a band.
Painters' and Decorators' Union. 50 men.
Brewery Workmen. 100 men. baud and float.
Furniture Woikets' Union, 75 men.
Sixth divisionâ€” Alameda County Federated
Trades. 300 men and a band.
The procession will march up Market
street to Van Ness avenue, thence up Van
Ness to a point not yet determined upon,
then counter-march to Market nnd down
the latter street to Fifth street. The grand
marshal will review the procession from
the step? of the Lincoln School building.
The exercises will be held in Metro
politan Temple, and will begin at 2 o'clock.
C. li. Johnson will be president of the
day, and will open the exercises. Tbe
orator of the day is James H. Barry.
Speeches will nlso be made by A. Fureseih
of the Sailors' Union and James Andrew
of the A!aniP(ia Couuty Federated Trades.
Miss Lottie Graeber will recite a Labor
day poem written for tbe occasion by T.
11. MathiaH, formerly a sailor, whose
previous Â«efforts in verse have attracted
borne attention. M:ss Xena Roberts, the
well-known vocalist, will sing. Music will
be supplied by an orchestra under, the
direction of Professor O. T. Schuppert.
A grand theatrical performance will be
given in Turn Verein Hall, on Turk street,
at 8 o'clock to-night.
It is believed by the members of the ar
rangement committee that a number of
wholesale stores will close, at least during
a portion of the day, in order to give their
employes an opportunity to attend the
celebration, even though it is nut a legal
Holiday. Tne banks will be open, but ex
pect a slack business during the day. All
the Government departments. Federal,
State, city aud countyâ€” except some of the
courtsâ€” ;uid the public schools will go on
as usual-
There was a final meeting r,f the grand
marshal and his aids, at 363 Jessie street,
last night, and all necessary arrangements
for tbe celebration were coucluded.
The programme for the entertainment in
Turn Verein Hall is a musical affair, with
excellent talent. I: is as follows:
Overture by the orchestra; song, by
Mrs. S. .J. Tulley; banjo solo ana song,
by Tom Bree; sing, Miss Mabel Hudson:
overture by the orchestra; instrumental
specialties, by Mr. Monroe; the clown
juggler, by Mr. Sparrow serio-comic and
parody songs, by Miss Teddy Mayiiew.
The pleasures of the evening wind up
witb a merry dance.
The Law of the Day.
A correspondent writas
Ktl Hot Morning Call: There seems to have
been an inwnensn amount of Ignorance of law
amoug tUose wlioso business it Is to know It,
wim rday as a
legal holiday. There has never beeu any pre
tension tliat eliher ('mimes* or the President
lias any tight 10 pioclaun a legal nouday any
where except In the District of Columbia and
such other places as are exclusively under the
control of the Federal Government. All our
holidays have simply been adopted by tbe
MateÂ«, or by custom, tor the sake of uniform
ity. Decoration day stands In tbe same cate
gory.
The following cannot be disputed:
Kevised Statutesâ€”Laws relating to tbe District
of Columbia. January 'JÃŸ. 1S7O:
Section Â»93- The loilowin^ day?, namely: ThÂ«
first clay of January, commonly called Sew Year's
day: the fourth day of July; me twenty-fifth nay
of December, commonly called Chr stmas day.
ana any day appointed or recommended by the
President of tli- United St ites as a cay or public
rait or thanksgiving, shall be holidays within tbe
District, and shah, tor all purposes of presenting
for payment or acceptance for the maturity anil
protest, and giving no- ice or tbe dishonor of bills
of exchange, batik checks and promissory notes
or oilier negotiable or commercial paver. be
treated and considered as is the first day of the
week, commonly called Sunday, and all notes,
drafts, checks or other commercial or negotiable
paper Tallin;; doe or maturing on either of said
holidays snail be deemed as having matured on
the day previous.
W. W. P.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1900-09-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>REST AND RECREATION
tabor's Holiday Celebrated by Indus
trial l'arades and Picnics.
TRIBUTES TO TUOSB WHO TOIL.
BJrjftn mid Roosevelt Spoko at Ijiibor
Picnic In Chicago Observance
Ol' the Day by L ibtirO gaii-
izatlons iu Other Cities.
Chicago, Sept. 3. Organized labor
of Chicago passed in review before
William J. Bryan and Theodore
Roosevelt. Hour after hour, the labor
unions marched down Michigan ave
nue past the Auditorium 'hotel on the
loggia of which stood the Democratic
nominee for president, the Republican
vice presidential candidate, together
with Oharle3 A. Towno, Senator W. E.
Mason and a dozen other political
leaders. Fully 35,000 men took part
in the parade. Botih Bryan and Roose
velt were heartily greeted by the men
as they marched passed the hotel.
when 'the last of the long line of
marchers had swung round Michigan
avenue Into Jackson boulevard, Mr.
Bryan and Mr. Roosevelt went Inside
the hotel, where soo.i after they sat
down to a luncheon given by labor
representatives. It was a "flag of
truce" luncheon for the trades union
men had declared that in the celebra
tion of Labor Day there was to be no
politics.
While the parade was moving a host
of people, mostly the families of work
ingmen gathered in Electric park,
where the speeches of the day were
delivered. The program of speeches
was as "follows: From 2 to 3 p. m.
Governor Roosevelt; from 3 to 4,
Oharle3 A. Towne, Samuel Al
Bdhuler, Democratic candidate for
governor of Illinois, Richard
Yate3, the Republican guberna
torial nominee, Senator William E.
Mason, Mayor Rose of Milwaukee,
Mayor Harrison of Chicago, R. M. Pat
tison and P. J. O'Donnell. in the order
given and at 4 p. m. Mr. Bryan.
In the evening there was more
speaking, concluding with an address
by John Finerty.
Governor Roosevelt left here late In
the afternoon. Mr. Bryan left at 8
p. m. via the Baltimore and Ohio to
Cumberland, Md., where he will open
the campaign in that state Tuesday.
At New York.
New York, Sept. 3. In view of the
fact that there was no general parade
of labor in this city and that many
down town business house3 were
closed, the day was quiet. Most of the
trade organizations left the city by
early trains and boats for their out
ings, each 'having a program of Its
own. A Labor Day parade was held
in Jersey City under the auspices of
the United Building Trades council of
Hudson county. An incident of this
parade was the action of the Central
Federated union In refusing to march
past the grand stand, in front of the
city hall, where the parade was re
viewed by Mayor Hose and other of
ficials. The Central Federated union
is composed largely of silk weavers
and brewery employes, a large num
ber of whom are professed socialists
and opponents of both political par
ties. When tihey were two blocks
from the grand stand the men of the
Central Federated union fell out of
line and made a dotiour so as to avoid
passing the stand.
At Indianapolis.
Indianapolis, Sept, 3. The Labor
Day parade took place in the morning,
with all the local unions, plenty of
bands and several floats in line. The
principal event on the program at the
fair grounds was a natural gas explo
sion made to order. A four-room cot
tage builfto be destroyed, but neatly
painted and looking like a permanent
structure, was erected in front of the
grand stand at a safe distance and
here the audience was allowed to see
!how a natural gas explosion looks.
At Dayton.
Dayton, O., Sept. 3. Never before
has Labor Day been observed with
greater enthusiasm. Fully 5,000 uni
formed knights of labor marched In
tao parade which was the most Impos
ing in the history of the city. Rain
did not deter the unionists who for a
solid hour braved the elements. An
interesting program followed at the
fair grounds and races of all descrip
tions attended by 20,000 people.
At Knoxville.
Knoxvllle, Tenn., Sept. 3. Labor
Day was celebrated here on a more
extensive scale than ever before. A
long parade passed through the busi
ness streets. Floats representing var
ious trades unlonsappeared. A mili
tary tournament by state militia and
athletic contorts were the features of
the afternoon. At night the lakes at
Two Parks were burned, oil being ig
nited upon the waters.
At Atlanta.
Atlanta, Sept. 3. The largest cele
bration of Labor Day ever carried out
In this city, and probably in the south,
took place here, with 5,000 men, In line
representing every labor union and
large delegations from adjoining towns
participated. Civic and military or
ganizations were in the parade. The
cntnus-iasm along the line of march
through the city to Exposition park
was very great.
At Washington.
Washington, Sept. 3. Labor Day
was observed here for the sixth time,
the I a'l character of the holiday hav
ing been established by congress In
1894. All of the government depart
ments were closed, but there were no
street ipa"rades or public demonstra
tions, the various local labor organi
zations celebrating the day by speech
making and athletic game3.
At Memphis.
Memphis, Sept, 3. Labor Day was
more generally celebrated here than
ever before. The parade was the larg
est and most creditable in the history
of the city trades. For the first time
the business men were not called on
to contribute toward the expense the
celebration, the labor unions being
now so strong that tlhey needed no as
sistance.
At Louisville.
Louisville, Sept 3. Labor Day was
more generally celebrated than In
many years. Fully 10,000 were in
line in the parade and the afternoon
and night were given up to celebra
tions at a half dozen park3. The prin
cipal addres3 of the day was delivered
by Harry J. Skefflngton of Boston, who
spoke at Phoenix Hill park.
At Cleveland.
Cleveland, Sept. 3. A drizzling
rain interferred with Labor Day In
this city. Notwithstanding a steady
downpour, however, th3re were prob
ably 10,000 men in line representing
more than 90 unions. At the conclu
sion of the parade President Samuel
Gompers of the American Federation
of Labor delivered an address.
At Kansas Citj.
Kansas City, Sept. 3. Labor Day
here was a field day for politicians.
Joseph Floyd, Republican candidate
for governor, Hon. A. M. Dockery,
Democratic candidate for the same of
fice, both spoke to large crowds. Most
of the business houses were closed.
At Cincinnati.
Cincinnati, Sept. 3. Lahor Day was
celebrated here by a parade of work
ingmen estimated from 12,000 to 15.
000. It wa3 the best appointed pro
cession ever sepn here Labor Day.
The streets were lined with Interested
and applauding spectators.
At Chattanooga.
Chattanooga, Sept. 3. Labor Day
was celebrated by the workingmen
and their families under the auspices
of the Central Labor union by a basket
picnic. Music and dancing were the
main features. The usual street par
ade was dispensed with.
At Nashville.
Nashville, Tenn., Sept. 3. The La
bor Day celebration here consisted of
an Imposing parade throughout the
principal streets of the city and a pic
nic at Glendale, Ark., where addresses
were delivered by Governor McMillan
and Rev. W. S. Jacobs.
At Columbus.
Columbus, O., Sept. 3. Organized
labor celebrated the day by a big par
ade In tho morning and a picnic at
Andrews' grove. Former Attorney
General F. S. Monnett was the princi
pal orator of the day.
At Charleston.
Charleston, S. C, Sept. 3. Labor
Day was celebrated here for the first
time with any distinction. During tho
past year, workingmen organized
strongly and turned out with 1,500
men in parade.
At St. Louis.
St. Louis, Sept. 3. The day was cel
ebrated by a labor parade In which
more than 25,000 men of all trades par
ticipated. The day was a holiday and
all business was suspended.
At Wichita.
Wichita, Kan., Sept. 3. Labor Day
was observed here in an Informal way.
There were no speeches. In the even
ing a bail wa3 given by the labor
unions.
At Kvausville.
Evansvlllo, Ind., Sept. 3. The larg
estLaborDayparadoseen here In man
years occupied nearly an hour In pass
ing a given point. A picnic followed.
At Denver.
Denver, Sept. 3. About 6,000 work
ingmen marched In the Labor Day
parade in tr Is city. Business was gene-rally
suspended</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1901-09-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LABOR DAY IS CELEBRATED BY VARIOUS WORKERS
WITH PARADE, ORATORY, FIELD SPORTS AND A BALL
w,m"' iTldmi
Amid People's
Plaudits.
REVIEWED AT THE
CAPITOL GROUNDS
Oratory Marks the Morning's Cere-
.monies Jesuits oi Many
rieia evenu.
that moment when the
FHOM rays of the morning
sun gilded the flags of the first
body of marching men until
weary feet turned from the dance toward
rest for a new day's duties, yesterday
was dedicated to Labor. For the
second time the Territory of Hawaii
saw a celebration of Labor Day, and
from busy shop and mansion alike the
people of the city turned out to do
honor to the holiday and tin- men for
whom it was declared.
It was a day full of events. With
parade, oratory, sports and the dance
the hours were filled and until tired
heads ceased to toss on welcome pillows,
there was only time token from the
celebration for refreshment to make
certain the full of enjoyment. It was
a popular holiday,, No business was
done in the city after the early morning
hours, and those who can find no pleasure
In the multitude gave to the day
Us measure of honor in excursion and
luau, In picnic and social gathering.
None was so pressed by duty that time
could not be token for the celebration
of the annual day of testimonial to
trade and union, and those whoso working
hours were shortened by the recur
rence ,of the holiday spent' tho"tlme in-
the many ways devised by expert com
m luces, whose endeavor for weeks has
been the preparation of a program
which would leave nothing to be desired
by those who wished to enjoy an
outing.
That the day was appreciated by the
men and women whose lives are full of
toll, was Bhown by the zest with which
they entered Into the day's events. The
streets were crowded with eager throngs
who had early taken points of vantage
for the purpose of viewing the turnout
of the union men. It was o typical holiday
crowd, for the people were ready
to appreciate the display offered them
and they were unstinted in applause.
When the spcechmaklng began from
the bandstand in the Executive grounds
there were several thousand people
about the stand, and the crowds did not
diminish during the exercises.
Even before these had been completed
there was a movement toward the park
and when the afternoon came it was to
find the vanguard of the throng which"
was to see the events on the sports program
In possession of stand and quarter
stretch. There were five thousand
people in the park during the afternoon
und they seemed to find in the races and
the ball game enough to interest them
until dinner time, and a late dinner it
was too for most of the people of the
city.
Then at night there was a ball at, the
drill shed which was a fitting ending to
i.a day of pleasure. The dancing floor
was crowded until late in the night and
the men and women who had been all
day engaged In various forms of en
joyment capped it all with two steps
and square dances. It was a jolly closing
function for a day of restless pleasures
and the first Labor Day of the new
century will be a memory full of bright
spots for all Honolulu.
PARADE OF THE
UNION WORKMEN
Labor passed in review before Gov.
Dole, Gen. Breckenrldge and the officers,
of the Territory and the army and
navy who had earlier reviewed the military,
soon after the parade was formed.
The feature of the morning was
(he display of the men of the unions
of the city, who marched to show their
fealty to the Idea of union, and their
appreciation of the, holiday which is so
peculiarly their own.
As fsoon as the parade was formed In
Miller street the route was taken up
through the Executive building grounds, i
-i that the reviewing party might see
ll with the men fresh for the mnrch,
and every feature in the best shape.
II wtui Just a. little past nine o'clock
when the notes of a march sounded
nd the grand marshal ordered the ad-
:w m m z
vance. There was a general movement
down the line and with swinging step
the band led the procession Into the
grounds.
There was Just space enough for the
men to get straightened up before they
were in front of the reviewing stand,
which was he Ewa portico of the Exec
utive building. Gov. Dole and Gen.
Breckenrldge were at the front, back of
them being the various officers, Mrs.
Dole, Miss Adams, Mrs. Hoblnuon and
Mrs. White, and as the swinging column
passed them the salutes of the com
manding officers were In evidence and
the men bore their arms and tokens at
a present.
The regular soldiers with MaJ. Davis
commanding followed the band and
marshals, and the two batteries under
command of Captains Slaker and
showed thi'lr form In marching
past the reviewing party, their khaki
uniforms showing In contrast with the
white of the band and the black of the
leaders of the parade. Immediately following
them came the men In whose
honor the day was made a holiday. In
turn the workmen with their unliiue
devices, the floats representative of
their trades, and their attractive costumes,
saluted and their nppearance attracted
the undivided attention of the
members of the reviewing party.
Out of the grounds the procession
passed to meet upon the streets new
thousands of the people who had gathered
to cheer them In their passing.
The greatest crowds had gathered along
Fort street, but as well there were hundreds
at each crossing of the streets and
the people living along the line of the
march did all in their power to show
appreciation of the men In line and the
day they were celebrating.
At no time was there an absence of
enthusiasm and the attention given the
paraders and the floats was worthy of
the endeavor of the committee to make
the turnout an attractive one. The men
me women along the route were un
stinting In their uppluu.se for the pretty
piciure oi inuustry given in the work-
Inp rllctrtlnva nnrl nfen thn nA,.nn lir.
tuVe o7 n'
th e w, r, ,r
w.
appiause ana vocai reward.
The parade committee had not had
time to bring Into execution their plan
of posting placards at the places where
the different parties forming the parade
were to line up, so the procession did
not Btart at the appointed time. Final-
Mi, .c JMasau
REVIEWING THE LABOR PARADE.
ly, however, the march began. Five
'mounted policemen riding ahead to
clear the road. With (lowing banners
and martial music the long gaily bedecked
body turned In through the
palace gate and went through tlie
grounds, turning Into King street by
the makal gate. The Grand Marshal,
Matthew Heffern, rode ahead, and right
after him came the band, cheering the
march of the parades with gay music.
The laborers' big banner, bearing the
emblem of a brawny arm holding a
hammer, waving close behind them.
Hereupon came the assistant marshal,
his aides and other officials, followed by
a carriage In which were seated Mr.
Lorrln Andrews and Mr. T. McCants
Stewart, who were amongst the orators
of the day. Two companies of United
Suites marched after thorn, I
and Mr. Francis .Murphy mid Franklin
Austin, also speakers, followed In n car-
rluge.
N'ow came the main of the
parade, namely, the floats and
slon of the various labor unions. The

Plumbers marched ahead, twenty-four
strong; they were dressed In white and
all carried small Japanese paper para-I
sols, making a very pretty display, and
Incidentally shielding themselves from
the hot sun. J
The Electrician Union's iioat the
first one In the procession. It was gully
decorated with red, white and blue
bunting, und equipped with a dynamo,
electiic fans, meters, bells, a telephone
und nil such paraphernalia as belong to
this trade. Every now and then the
bells would ring out during the mnrch.
The electricians followed, twenty-four
In number, dressed In white, with carnation
lels around their hats'.in his
hand each man held a brass tube, such
is is used In electric chandeliers and
on the end of the tubes were alternately
red, white and blue electric globes, so
jrdered, that the color-scheme of red,
white nnd blue could be seen from any
direction. Twenty-four carpenters
diessed In khnkl nnd white und clrea,
twelve nliisi.rer.s hv h

"Z', "m !?Z. i."""1'
twiinju u in i uiwiwin jiwut? rrucieu on
onB wagon: when the parade started
Us white canvas sides shone forth in
virgin beauty, but during the mnrch
busy painters applied their craft to It,
and when the float finally turned up
by the CapltoJ building, the house wan
painted; this being undoubtedly
rifKTY' ip WW
vSS). W M
ord ns far as house painting Is con
cerned. After the Moat followed two
clowns mounted on donkeys. The Painters
Union followed their leaders, and
Schuman rubber tire rig closed up this
part of the procession. Now came the
Portuguese hand. After them wheeled
the sailors' lloat, an enormous model of
a ship, mounted on a bunting draped
carriage, the sixty-four pallors which
followed, dressed In tasty blue and
white uniforms, and headed by thejed
Stars and Stripes, formed a very pretty
part of the display. Sixteen moulders
with Japanehe parasols followed their
lloat, which was conspicuous by a furnace
vomiting yellow name and smoke.
Then came the Union Ironworks' lloat.
the biggest one In the procession. It
consisted of an enormous boiler, upon
which men were hnmmerlng In rivets,
producing a noWe nlmost aH strong us
that of the Portuguese band. Another
lloat belonging to the same union was
gotten up by Catt..il and Nelll. This
float, which was smaller than the first
one, resembled It much In the general
make-up. These floats were followed
by the Boilermakers' and Iron Ship
Builder's Union men.
The and many others.
who Miould have come In this pait of
the parade, were conspicuous by their
absence, but In their place a host of
vehicles, representing different business
houses In town, followed.
First came a sausage wugon, the man
In charge offering the multitude dog-
'meat In different shapes. When his talk
got too much for the soda water people
In the Hawaiian Soda Water Works wagon
behind him, a well directed squirt
from a siphon would shut him up temporarily.
Miller's candy wagon caused
great Joy amongst the younger members
of the crowd, ns candy came flying by
the handful from Its voluminous casks.
Then came, what probably was the most
expensive outfit In the parade, namely
John Nott's two wagons with plumbers'
fittings. A carriage, filled with lawn-
mowers, around which was twisted rub-
ber hose and bunting, came next.
Then came the most imposing, and
to many certainly the most attractive,
number of this part of the program,
namely the Hawaiian Beer Co.'s lloat
and wagons. The float consisted of a
big red-painted canvas house, upon the
front of which "Home Industry" was
written In large letters.
Upon the first of the beer wagons
stood a benevolent personage, clad In
fantastic raiment and a still more fan
tastlc wig. He was easily the favorite
of the parude, as he, with liberal hand,
distributed foaming schooners whenever
a stop was made. A parcel delivery
wagon, draped in bunting followed, and
Lewers Cooke's display ended the
parude. This display, which was more
noticeable because of Its extent, con-
,slsted of fifteen or sixteen wagons loud-
with all kinds of material, which the
firm carries, split posts, glass, wallpaper,
paint, lumber of all kinds, etc.,
etc. The firm evidently Intended to live
up to the motto, which they had on
their first carriage, "What we do not
carry, Is not worth handling."
Notwithstanding its length, the procession
must he said to have proceeded
with very few hitches mid it wus en-
Joyed with fun, noise ami laugh
ter till the minute it reiched back to
the Capitol building, where It dispersed.
Nautical Bchuol at Manila.
The Navy Department has received the
report of Lieutenant It. H. Tnwnluv nt
his administration of the nautical school
at Manila, from which placo lie was do- I
tached and ordered home. H Into effect on the Hth of June; A. D.
mends the use of tho Bancroft as a j ,so. which really supplied tho nachln
tlce ship and sajs among other things: (ry for enforcing the exclusion act. Un-"The
students are native aud in ucr the Chlneso laborers In Hawaii
eral are olivdlunt, zealous, htudlous and wcr" given one yenr In which to register
ambitious. Their most marked penalty of deportation on failure.
turistlfH are un Imitative aptltutln and a 1','ro wo "to somo more of the nefarious
rctcnthe memory In all practical and effects of this exclusion act. A peoplo
mechanical work. The grcutust dlllluulty w,1 1'irtcl been given tho rights of real-Is
In enforcing regularity of attendance, dence and tho pursuit,,, of happiness by
which Is so essential In progiesslve In- nn Independent sovereign power, are
structlon.
"I would recommend that hereafti'r thn
number of cadets to bu l. nn.
portioned to the various provinces of the 11,to do under tho ban of the dog-tax
Islands In proportion to the population 'aw- i am right In calling It the,
thut tho uppolntmvnts be made by dental annexation of Hawaii, as all the
me governor or tiy some Hultablo olllcer
of the piovlnce, tho appointees to be subject
to the general admission examina
tion to be held at thu school. As the
oung men of the entire archipelago are
eligible to admission to thu school, this
plan. In my opinion, would afford the
best means of giving general and equal
representation
Labor day passed oft most satisfactorily.
The parade was good, the exercises
appropriate and sobriety was the rule.
No laboring man has any cause, as a
citizen, to feel anything but pleasure
at the way In which the day waa celebrated.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045555/1901-09-02/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LABOR DAY IN
ALL THE LAND
Plttsburg Sept 2The steel strikers
who have been trying for a week to
get the employes of the Carnegie plant
at Duqueine to come out made a last
stand today and foiled A parade
from McK sport to meet the workmen
on their way to the mill at C am nnd
Induce them to remain away had been
arranged but when tho hour arrived
there were no marchers and the parade
was abandoned
Thu tight bad been made In the open
hearth department but notwithstand
ing a house to house canvass by the
strikers last night only tno men re
fused to return to work Today the
works ore In full operation and tot
strikers admit that there Is little hope
of cioslnu the plant
DIMttlnfactlDn IS Increasing at Me
ICr port last Friday about forty
stirrers returned to work at the Seam
less Tube plant And today this force
was cjnMderably Increase It Is snlo
pttparatlons are In progress for re
sumption at the National Tube work
and that the machinists who wore oom
celled to cease work thiough the strike
have been ordered to report for work
for the purpose of getting the machln
frY in order The Monongahcla blast
furnace department of the National
Tube works Is working full and an ef
I fort Is to br made this vreelc to beat
I 7f
1 J
tI
the output record since the strike start
ed At llu Dcmmler tin plate plant
everything has been loads ready for ni
early start A report was current lu
McKcusport today that a large num
ber of deputy sheriff had been sworn
In to KO to Demmler to guard the
work at that place The deputies
have been ordered to report for duty
next Wednesday
Beginning today the Amalgamated
association will pay benefits tl their
nrudy members but the first payment
will rot be mode until September 15
when each man will receive n for the
two weeks The strlK began Its thira
month with n few InJIcatloiiR of early
peace It has settled down to a ques
tion of endurance both sides claiming
the advantage
Praxldcnt Burns expects to hear from
President Schwab today In reference
to the new peace plan said to have been
submitted to him on Saturday
Iltt bUrg was given over to the
Sturdy Sons of Toll today who pat
nded the streets many thousand strong
In celebration of Labor day Tho In
terest owing to the Amalgamated strike
was never ns great us this year ana
the prwojilons contained workmen
from almost every trade In this great
industrial center The procession w a It
In lour divisions The first division
was mode up of the Amalgamated
strikers with President Shatter In com
mand They were greeted with en
thulium nil along the route A tea
tUft of the parade was a long line of
Industrial exhibits Illuntrntln the ac
tive workings of trales andl manufac
turing business of all kinds The best
of frfllns prevailed and there was no
disorder After the parade there was
a central exodus to Ross grove Thor
n nunltn of all the allied trades of
western PtuniylvuxU WM held Ad
t
t I 1 AJ ll
dresses were made by President Shaf
fer Simon Burns George J Church
hill and others
In Xow York
New York Sept 2Labor day was
observed In this city by a general sus
pension of business There was no par
ade of labor unions the day being gl
en over to picnics and outdoor sports
The nlr was chilly and rain fell at In
tervals
In Tncnnia
Tacoma Wn Sept 2Labor day was
generally observed here as a legal holi
day Nearly all business houses were
cloe di There was a large parade of
various unions but speeches were ct
pensel with and the afternoon was de
voted to a program of outdoor sports
Tonight there will be a grand ball
At Portland
Portland Ore Sept a Labor day Is
being generally observed In Portland
All the Important places of business are
closed In order that employes zany IIIe
an opportunity of participating In the
celebrntlons The parade of labor or
ganizations this afternoon was the
largest ever held under similar aus
pices In this city
At Dcmcr
Denver Colo Sept I Todays labor
parade In Denver was the largest on
record for this city The weather was
perfect and about 7000 union men were
In line The parade was followed by
a picnic and snorts
In Untie
Butte Mont Sept 2ono of the
I
I
Cr
M r aeon
greatest demonstrations ever seen In
this labor center on Labor day took
place today Oer 5000 men were In
line and had the miners union turned
out Its full strength the number would
have been nearer 10000 Forty dif
ferent trades nnd labor organizations
were represented The large majority
of them had specially designed uni
forms which added to tho nttracllv j
ness of the turnout Aftitr the parade
there was speaking nt the gardens nwxr
town The orators of tile day wore
Martin J Klliott member of the legis
lature and Charles Lane building In
spector
In San IraneUoo
San Francisco Sept 2Lltbor day In
this city was colebrated by the labia
unions which gave a public domonstm
tlon of their strength by parading
through the business section of the
city Twenty thousand men were
marthalled In the parade columns In
tluoinp nearly every union In this city
nod a great majority of the union men
Following the parade literary mc1e
were held Congressman Maguire being I
the orator of the day
At Hi lend
St Louis Sept 1 Labor day at St
Louis was celebrated with two grand
parades that wound up with picnics
and celebrations attended byt thous
ands of laboring men and their fami
lies The Building Trades Council pa
rade was formed In six divisions This
procession marched to tho fair ground
The other procession under the aus
pices of the Central Trades and Labor
union marched to Conconlla park It
Is estimated that fully 40009 men
marched In the two procession</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-09-02/ed-1/?sp=5&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BIG
PARADE CHARACTERIZES
THIS HOLIDAY CELEBRATION.
VIEW OF LABOR DAY PARADE GROSSING OLIVE STREET AT BROADWAY
-various trades. In the afternoon there was
a big picnic, where addrctses were delivered
or Colonel J. a. Fetter of Bpringfield. TV.
I' E. Brandt cf St. Louis. Thomas V. llliamsos
of Edwards-riUe. and tba Reverend Harding
of thia city.
A week Street Fair commenced In the
evening, and the city Is crowded with vis
itors.
TOW" SETT DELEGATIONS.
J
y
Fifty Thousand YTorkingmen With Flaps and Emblems Symbolical
of Their Crafts Parade the Thoroughfares in .Celebration of Their
Annual Holiday Largest IK-monstration in History of Lo
cal Labor Organizations Picnics Held at Concordia
Park and the Fair Grounds.
a
FEATURES OF LABOR
DAY CELEBRATIOX.
Parade Are miles la leasts
Fifty thousand men In line.
Every labor organisation in the city
represented
Picnics siren at the Fair Grounds
end at Concordia. Park.
Parade started from Twelth and
Market streets In three corps, the
Central Trades and Labor Union, un
der Grand Marshal J. G. Hoppenjohn.
The Metal Trades Council, under the
leadership of J. P. O'Connor and the
Building Trades Council under com
mand of C. L. Meyers.
The paraie was lour hours passing
Broadway and Olive street.
No accidents occurred during the
parade.
..a.!
Marching side by side. strong, repre
sentatives of more than 30 labor unions
paraded for hours the streets of the down
town district yesterday In what was the
greatest labor demonstration In the history
of the city.
In former jears there has been Jealousy
between large organizations, resulting In
divided parades. This year Grand Marshal
Hoppenjon. president of the Central Trades
and Labor Union, was followed by members
of every labor organization in the city.
Before, the hour set for the start of the
parade, uniformed troops left ehelr head
quarters to march to Twelfth and Olive
streets. By 10 o'clock thousands of men
bearing banners stood about in lrregu'ar
companies, but without disorder. Then
numbers of vans arrived, all fantastically
decorated with bunting and flags and em
blems symbolical of the crafts of 'he
workers. Then, came the mounted mar
shals with their broad sasjes and badges.
Losg experience in similar parades since
tie first Lahf r Day celebration in St. Louis j
In 1SS7. had given the ofSciils In charge
the requisite skill. There was no confu
sion.
At a Utile before 11 o'clock bombs
were exploded tor tne stair ono. me "-j
m .i
mass Began to moike ..u a jw. .M.a
line.
THOUSANDS WITNESS PARADE
The sidewalks were thronged with specta
tors and the windows of the big mercantile
establishments on "Washington avenue were.
Ailed with clerks and porters, many of j
whom, through megaphones, shouted words j
of cheer to the marcher!". The same scenes i
were enacted along Broadway, where the itecoru-uir, w. ----were
e1 rlac. ,n .ji Eat St. Louis and Belleville,
crowd was more dense. All along the line picnics, at which the crowds
of march the street cars stopped to alow wf accmaojaled.
the passage of the men to be uninterrupted, "'f ra-ade star-ed -om
Tho fair weather called out the laborer yS!Sa. mS ITiJ'ttMS
In unexpected numbers. Id by mcttnted i j jj rnarched through the principal
aolice under Sergeants McCafferty and Bo-
C hnds nlavini- all
elang the line; the unionists rnarched from
Twelfth street and Washington avenue to
Broadway, to Chcuteau avenue, to Tenth
screet. to Allen avenue, to Menard street.
to Victor street, to Twelfth street, to Sid
ney street, to Thirteenth street, which was
followed to Concordia. Park. The corps cf
the iletal and Building; Trades Councils dis
banded at Twelfth street and Washington
avenue, tiling street cars to the Fair
Grounds.
MARCHED E EIGHT DIVISIONS.
The Central Trades and Labor Union. In
eight divisions, continued its march. In the.
first company following President Hoppen
'ohn and his aides; M. E Murray. J. T.
Wade. Charles FInie. S. O. Ingram. G. A.
Hoehn. Jacob Gableman and Charles RoloS.
were representatives of the hoot and shoo
workers, tho cigar makers, carriage and
wagon makers, leather workers, broom
makers, the Theatrical Brotherhood, bill
posters and soda, bottlers, under J. V.
O'CormelL division marshaL
The second division, under Richard De
harry, was composed of woodworkers,
brick. tHe and terra, cotta workers. marbJe
and glass workers, metal polishers, grani
toid and cement workers.
Marshal Georgo Staley of the third dlvi
Eion was foUowed by various organiza
tions of the typographical union and allied
trades, mailers, upholsterers, waiters and
Jfeakers.
In" Th-larth division, under R- B.
Parker, were hrher-trnkand bag mak
ers, electrical workers, sewermes. team
sters, riggers, whiteners, pattern makers,
badge makers, tailors, brush makers and
bottie packers.
P-ct-si Pred Baeckmarm of the fifth
alvlsion led the molders of stoves,
car wheels, core makers, coopers, car and
coach painters, millwrights, machine
erectors, blacksmiths and bollermakers.
In division six were brewers and maltsters,
beer drivers, bottlers, brewery firemen and
engineers, with other brewery workers.
The butchers were under Marshal Julius
Rudolph.
The seventh division. led by Otto Ehr
hnrdt. was made up of garment workers,
alrrmeu, retail clerks and members of the
Federal Labor Union.
Marshal U. S. G. White of the eighth di
vision was followed by Tobacco Workers
and members of the Laborers" Protective
Union.
Under Grand Marshals J. P. O'Connor and
C L. Myers and their aids. J. A. Davis and
Edward King, the forces of the Metal and
Building- Trades Council formed for their
ehort march before taking street cars for
the Fair Grounds. The same good order
that characterized the ranks or the Central
Trades and Labor Union was observed.
The Metal Workers preceded, many in car
riages, the others marching In double file.
All were attired in rent new uniforms, car
rying emblems and banners. The Building
Trades followed In six weH-ordered divis
ions. Interspersed with floats. The division
Targfral were Frank LesUe. J. W. Wood,
W. A. Perry. George Powers. Mlchatl Shan
non and George Palschraff.
TWO PICNICS ARE HELD.
Two basket picnics were given at. Concor
dia Park and the Fair Grounds, la the
north, and south of the city.
Men, -women and children numbering IflO.
000 participated. The wives and families of
the marchers arrived at the picnic grounds
Ions before the paraders. Thousands fol
lowed In the course of an hour. Tired from
their Journey, whether on foot or in convey
ances, all sat on the grass or around rough
tables for their noonday meal in the open j
air.
AT CONCORDIA PARK.
The feature of the afternoon, programme
was a speech on the coal strike by General
Organizer Prank Stevermana of the boot
end shoe-, workers' national union at Con
cordia Park. The speaker- outlined what
he held to be the underlying causes tor the
failure cfithe laborers to secure their In
terests, arguing that the proper nse of the
ballet was their only zafegcard and. that
they rnustibe responsible tor Vie probable
iallcre.
The athlrrlr events -were all contested,
the -2S0-Tards dash being won in eleven
afTT1 flat In hard finish between Albert
suit- and. Wjniaa Carroll, the former win-
nmj5- Thirteen young -women contested
In the next event at fifty yards, and one
of the unlucky number fell. The time.
t even antl" a half seconds, was creditable,
considering that the contestants wore long
skirts and that the course was rough and
uneven. The winner was May Blake.
place going to May Schelp. who ran the
w winner a hard race.
1 The other two events, both at fifty yards.
were for children under 1 years old. the
boys finishing in six seconds and the girls
In eight. The winters were Edward Wil-
son and Maggie McEaroy and the reconds
Benjamin Ilanwey and Ida Telss. All the
contests were well managed, hard fought
and rich in useful prizes.
In the evening dancing continued urtll
laie. The committee on entertainment and
arrangements was: L. P Negele, chairman:
W. A. Kenward. 3. Lev, J. C Goedeckei
and L. Stoil.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1906-09-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+holiday+day+parade+union&st=text&r=-0.204%2C-0.021%2C1.408%2C1.408%2C0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>UNION LABOR LABORWill LABOR1LLCELEBRATE
Will 1LLCELEBRATE 1LLCELEBRATESalt CELE8RA TE TESalt
Salt Lake L ke Organizations Will WillHave WillHave WILLHave
Have Extended Program at atx atSalt atSalt
x Salt Palace PalacePARADE PalacePARADE PalacePARADE
PARADE IS THIS MORNING MORNINGFIGHT MORNINGFIGHT
FIGHT NEWS TO BE BULLETINED BULLETINEDTHIS BULLETINEDTHIS BULLETINEDTHIS
THIS AFTERNOON AFTERNOONI
4 4 I 444 I 44444444444mL411 i I t tThe
4 4 The Labor day parade wllXorm at
41030 4 1030 oclock this morning mornln morning at the thei thet
i t i Federation of Labor hall Fourth
HSouth 1 South and State streets The Hnf Iinpof hinof f
of march will be north on State StatestrCQt 4
4 4 street from Fourth South to Third
South street thence west on Third
f South to Main street tre t thence north on 4 f
4 Main strefet str t to Brigham Youngs Youngsmonument Youngsmonument
f monument thence countermarch countermarchs2uth f
4 4 sguth on Main street to the Salt y 4
f Palace PalaceHtttt 4 4Twentysix
Htttt 44 t t 4 t f 4 t e t f t t t f f 1Twentysix t t tTwent
Twentysix Twent slx affiliated trade unions 3000 3000strong 31110strong 3OWstrong
strong will ihI form In lin of march at 1030 1030oclock 1030oclock 1O3oclock
oclock this morning at the Federation uf ufLabor If IfLabor
Labor halls and celebrate the working workingmans workingmans workingmans
mans holiday The details of o tlM t1 th paradft paradftwere paradAwere paradwere
were perfected yMtflrrday mornhl morning when whenthe Whllthe wheithe
the Labor dny committee met in labor
halls It promises promh es to be the greatest c P Pebratlon pI pIebratlon
ebratlon given in Salt Lake and evtrv evtrvunion PHVunion evrvunion
union has been asked to be repre repreeented repreeentedForming nt nte Kl 1 1Forming
Forming at the Federation building the thecolumn thlcolumn ttiacolumn
column will move north on State street streetto strPftto
to Third South street thence west on onThird 01Third ntThird
Third South street to Main street and andthence an anthence anilthence
thence north to the Brigham toung mon monument monument menument
ument where theprocession will counter countermarch counttrmarch countermarch
march to the Salt Palace rhe judges judgesstand jndgsstand
stand will be In front of the Federal Federalbuilding Federalbuilding Federalbuilding
building and prizes will be awarded to tothe t tthe
the Jjest appoofing organization in pa parade parade parade
rade Nearly every union has built a afloat 3float afloat
float representing its members in their thHrdaily thl11da1Jy theirdaily
daily walks in life and the competition competitionamong competitionamong competitionamong
among them for or the prize showing is iskeen iskeen iskeen
keen keenAfter keenAfter keenAfter
After the parade the afternoon celebra celebration ce1 celebrathin bra bratfon
thin will be held at the Salt Palace wh where whpraathletic whereathletic re reathletic
athletic sports will be hfeld d In the even evening eyenIng evening
ing there wilKbe wilY w1l be dancing and prizes will willbe wUlbe willbe
be given forahe for the best waltzers waltzersThe waltzersrne waltzersrhe
The Labor day da celebration will clo clothe clMA clMAthe clothe
the season at the resorts The banks banksstores bankstores banksstores
stores and business houses will close thiir thiirdoors thlirdoors thtirdoors
doors to allow an ow their employes to atterl attendthe atterlthe atterlthe
the celebration The poatofflce will ob observe u1senre observe
serve the following hours hoursThe hoursThe hoursThe
The money mone order window will be closed closedall cIosIdaJl closedall
all day da The box window inquiry divi division dlislon di dision
sion general delivery dellyer forwarding depart department department departmont
ment stamp window and registry division divisionwill tIlYIsiNlwill thviaionwill
will be open from 11 a a m until 1 p m mThe mThe mThe
The carriers will make One ne morning de delivery dflIYer thIlycry
livery lIYer covering the entire city cl The hot hott hottdelivery l ldelivery 1deUer
delivery deUer and collection COn UOt1 will w tl be made at
9 a m
Labor Union Sports SportsTIUI SportsThe
The Th labor unions TIUI will ii hold i their their prn pr o
gram g ram of sports at the Salt Palace A spe special sp spat
cial d at wire giving returns retu ns by rounds on th thGansNelson thf thfGansNElson thapsNelson
GansNelson G fight at Goldfield will be in installed tnstaUed intalled
stalled s on onthe the front stetMrofthe ste1Mfof stel ofthe the theater theaterThe theatlIhe theaterhe
The T he program for the celebration was wastprinted wasprinted wasrinted
Tp printed p rinted In The Herald yesterday yesterdayAt
At Lagoon the Labor day committee committeehave commfttlehare committeeave
have h ave arranged for two sixround boxing boxingmatches boxin boxinmatches boxingmatches
matches The contestants are Terry Da Davis Davis Pais
vis v is of Salt Lake and Joe Green of Chi Chicago hi hicaso hiago
ago c and Jack Christy ChrI5t and Kid Bern Bernstein Blrnstein Berttein
stein s cs of Salt Lake A baseball game will wiUbe willbe wille
be b e played in the afternoon between th thOBountiful timountiful j jBountiful
Bountiful B and Garland teams teamsThree teamgThree tenmThree
Three harness and one running event eventwill evt eventwill nt ntwill
will be pulled off during the afternoon ou outhe onthe otthe
the t he Wandamere raco track The races raceswill mctswill raceswill
will start at 2 oclock and a number lit litthe if ifhe f fthe
the t he animals entered have raced in Salt SaleLake SaltLake SaltLake
Lake before beforeFortyFive beforeGRANO beforeGRAND
GRAND REVIEW REVIEW OJ OJA orATLANTIC
A ATLANTIC FLEET FLEETFortyFive FLEETFortyFive
FortyFive Ships of War in Po Positions Positions Positions
sitions Assigned Them Themat Themat Themat
at Oyster Bay BayOyster BayOyster r rOystet
Oyster Bay Sept 2 2The The United UnitedStates UnitedStates Un1teStates
States Atlantic fleet is ready for In Inspection inspection inspection
spection of President Roosevelt when whenthe whenthe whenthe
the greatest American naval review in inhistory Inhistory inhistory
history takes place The fortyfive fortyfiveships fortYfiveships fortyfiveships
ships were In the th positions assigned assignedthem assignedthem assignedthem
them at noon They lie In three col columns columns columus
umns east and west Just outside the theentrance theentrance theentrance
entrance to Oyster Bay In Long Island Islandsound Islandsound Islandsound
sound soundJust soundJust
Just before dark the Dolphin flying fiylngthe flyingthe
the flag flagof of the secretary of the navy navysteamed navysteamed
steamed IntQ ths harbor and anchored anchoredThe anFhoredThe anhoredThe
j The M4k35flQ3y0h l rq r i which Vl1i h is to carry carryPresident carryPresident carryPresideift
President Roosevelt lies he tonight where wherehe wherehe
he will board her In mn the he morning In Inthe Inthe inthe
the harbor of Columbia Grove A num number number
ber of dispatch boats also are In the theharbor theharbor tiicharbor
harbor for readiness ss In the morning morningThe morningThe
The presidents guests tonight at Saga Sagamore Sagamore Sagamore
more hill include the secretary of the thenavy thena thenavy
navy na y and Mrs Bonaparte Speck Von VonSternburg VOIlSternburg VonSternburg
Sternburg the German ambassador ambassadorand ambassadorand ambassadorand
and Surgeon Surg on General Rixey RixeyHarbor RixeyHarbor
Harbor Is Crowded Cro CrowdedAlthough ded dedAlthough
Although a brisk breeze was blowing blowingand blowingand
and threatening rain the anchorage anchorageground anchorageground
ground of the fleet was a place of great greatattraction greatattraction greatattraction
attraction til day for pleasure craft of orevery ofevery
every description de cripUon The harbor tonight tonightIs
Is crowded with every type of craft craftthat craftthat
that can be pressed into service tomor tomorrow tomorrow</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075141/1934-08-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+day&r=0.074%2C0.594%2C0.702%2C0.374%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<textVol. X.
LABOR DAY PICNIC AT COLUMBIA GARDENS
11
i
far
*\1

i\
Jrl

DRIFTS AND RAISES
column contributed by Butte
Miners* Union No. 1)
(This
The Winter's Outlook
Some of the things we should worry
about are the constant increase in the
cost of living, and the constant de
crease in the number of people re
quired to produce all the necessities
and luxuries that can be consumed by
the people of this country. Our faci
lities for production are constantly be
coming more efficient, so that a short
er time is required and fewer people
are employed in the performance of
these functions than ever before in
the history of the world. These, and
a number of other things must be taken
into serious consideration in the final
settlement of any wage disputes or
similar controversies in existence at
the present time.
The present and immediate future
cost of living is another serious con
sideration. The cost of living has seen
a considerable step-up during the past
year, and according to all indications
the coming winter is likely to see an
additional step-up of probably 15 per
cent in the prices of the staple food
commodities that workers use most.
Where will the worker find this extra
purchasing power? Certainly not in
the pay envelopes the large employ
ers intend to force upon him. Through
the F.E.R.A. the employers have found
out how little the workers and their
families can exist upon, and hereafter,
that is the mark at which they are
shooting in re-arranging! their wage
scales. In a great many cases this
short-sighted policy amounts to actual
blindness. They fail to realize they
are humping their own destination.
There are many ways in which this
situation may be remedied, but its en
tire elimination is the thing for which
we are most desirous. As a prelude
to this ever to be hoped for consuma
tion, we believe that an adequate Old
Age Pension Law coupled with an In
heritance and Income Tax Laws, where
by Estates for inheritance purposes
and Incomes from whatever source de
rived be taxed at 100 per cent above
certain predetermined amounts,
these amounts were placed low en
ough, there wouldn't be much incen
tive to build up huge fortunes, there
by keeping the workers and their fam
ilies continually on the verge of starva
tion. These fat boys, like Con Kelly
and a lot more of them would very
likely relinquish a lot of the product
they have been appropriating to them
selves and spread it around in wages
rather than turn it over to the govern
ment in taxes.
Of course, Con knows as well as we
do, and probably better, that he isn't
worth the huge salary he pays him
self. He pays himself that salary be
cause he happens to be in a position
that permits him to dictate the amount
he will collect. Perhaps he realizes he
would be just as happy and content
with one per cent of the huge salary
he pulls down. But, be that as it may,
these people will not do anything to
remedy this situation on the contrary
they are doing everything in their pow
er to intensify it. Consequently, it is
up to the intelligent rank and file of
the working class to do .something
about it.
It has been said that in a country
where the people have universal suf
frage, the government of that country
and the conditions under which the
people live, must be good enough for
a majority of those people. If they
weren't, the people would change them.
Welt, that contention seems perfectly
logical; but of course, it isn't as easy
as that. Human nature being what
it is, the working class will require a
lot of experience and education before
it measures up to that standard. But
the outlook for the future looks bright
and we believe that if a real working
class political and economic movement
was launched, with a comprehensive
program of progressive principles, that
its success would be immediate.
Meantime, we must keep our col
lective ear to the ground, repeal, to
the best of our abilities every invasion
of our rights. Sec that when this
strike is settled, it is settled right and
that every move we make is calculat
ed to strengthen our position in the
future.
If
HAVERHILL, Mass. â€”(FP)â€” "Are
you better off than you were a year
ago?" the Haverhill Gazette asked its
readers, in an attempt to get an answer
to the now famous question President
Roosevelt asked over the radio.
"No," loud and decisive, was the an
swer of 77 per cent of the ballots.
NO ACTION IN STR:
SETTLEMENT
Crafts Waiting Decision of In
ternationals.
Reject Agreement.
Butte Crafts
Radio reportÂ» to the contrary, the
Butte strike has not yet been settled.
The majority of the craft locals in
Great Falls and Anaconda have ac
cepted the proposed agreement after
men who are not involved in the strike
were allowed to vote and decide upon
strike.
conditions for men who
Delegates from these cities state that
strike had
ly those who
been allowed to vote not one local
.1
would have accepted the agreement.
The Butte locals voted to reject the
agreement with the exception of two
unions. These two Unions accepted
for the same reason as those in Great
Falls and Anaconda. The agreement
not in
accepted by men who
volved.
There has bee
presented to the international Union
of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers.
It is hoped that a meeting will take
place between the International and
the Company some time next week.
agreement yet
Railway Workers
and the New Deal
The railroads, 137 strong, have asked
an injunction to prevent the Railroad
Retirement Board from collecting as
sessments from the carriers and their
employers under the provisions of the
Railroad Pension Act which was
passed by the last Congress. The car
riers, as was expected, invoke the "due
process" clause as well as the inter
state commerce clause of the Consti
tution. The Railroad Pension bill,
which has just gone into effect, is the
Administration's only tangible accom
plishment to date in the matter of eco
nomic-security legislation. Almost all
the carriers intend to continue their
"charity" pension plans until forced to
discontinue them by judicial edict.
Some of them, like the Pennsylvania,
will immediately begin making the
payroll deductions required by the law,
but will segregate the funds pending
the outcome of the suit. Holding fast
to the capitalistic ethic, the railroad
executives believe that retirement pen
sions should be a reward bestowed out
of the overflowing good-will of the
employer. They cannot as yet accept
the idea that the employer owes it as
a legal duty to his workers to provide
for their old age. More concretely,
the charges imposed by the bill on the
railroads represent a substantial step
ping-up over the contributions which
the railroads have seen fit to make un
(Continued to Page 2)
Alabama Miners Win
An important victory has been won
by the iron-ore miners of Alabama,
who are organized under the Interna
tional Union of Miine, Mill and Smelt
er Workers. Previous to the strike,
the condition of these miners was com
parable to that of the slaves before the
Civil War. Negro miners were in some
cases paid less than $1.00 a day and
even that was not in currency but in
scrip that could be spent only at the
company stores.
Now their wages are $4.56 for an 8
hour day, which is 31c higher than the
basic wage of Butte miners. Besides
the raise in pay, they won other im
portant concessions. The negro and
white miners stood solidly together
during a long and bitter strike in which
all the forces of a vicious corporation
and a reactionary state government
were used against them. It is estimat
ed by strike leaders that 35 men were
killed during the struggle. A high
price to pay for a living wage and the
human rights supposedly guaranteed
under the Constitution.
The Birmingham mines are mostly
controlled by the Tennessee Coal and
Iron Co. which is a Morgan enterprise
captured during the panic of 1907. This
Company has played the same role of
feudal overlord in Alabama as the Ana
conda Co. has played in Montana. The
low standard of living of the South
ern industrial worker has long been a
sore spot in the labor movement. It
is surely encouraging to see them or
ganizing into industrial unions and car
rying thru a successful struggle for
better conditions of life.
â€”(Mundy)
LALOR DAT, 1934
By William Green,</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036012/1899-09-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=labor+day</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HISTORY OF LABOR DAY
Facts in the Case Compiled by
Hugh Cavanaugh.
NEW YORK CITY FIRST
A Monster Parade in 186--Oregon the
First State to Make September 6
a Legal Holiday-The Gos
pal of Humanity.
The history of legislation by the dif
ferent states of the union in behalf of
a Labor day will be found of particular
interest in Montana at this time. Hugh
Cavanaugh in his publication, the
Butte Labor Day Souvenir," has made
the following compilation on the sub
ject:
"Labor day may be said to have been
first celebrated in New York city, the
occasion being In honor of the sixth an
nual convention of the Knights of La
bor, which convened in that city Sept.
5, 1882. The celebration conolated of a
monster parade of the labor organiza
tions, followed by a picnic at which ad
dresses were delivered by several of the
delegates in attendance.
"When the general assembly con
vened on the above date, a communica
tion was read from the secretary of the
New York Central Labor union inviting
the members of the body to review the
great parade from the grand stand at
Union square. While the parade was
passing, one of the delegates turned to
his associates and said: 'This is Labor
day in earnest.'
"Whether this was the first time the
term had been used is not known, but
the event was afterwards referred to as
'the Labor day parade.'
"Two years later, when the labor or
ganizations had the question of parad
ing up for discussion, George K. Lloyd,
a Knight of Labor, offered a resolution
declaring the first Monday in Septem
ber to be Labor day. The resolution
was adopted and steps were at once
taken to have the legislature enact a
law to make the day a legal holiday to
be known as Labor day. Although New
York was the first state to introduce
the measure before the legislature, Ore
gon was the first to pass the bill into
law. Prior to the act of congress four
years ago making the day a national
holiday, nearly 30 of the states had
adopted Labor day legislation, a list of
which we append and, as near as possi
ble, the names of those who introduced
the bills and the dates on which the
measures became laws.
"It was the intention of these who in
troduced the first Labor day resolution
to make the day stand apart from all
other holidays in the nature of its ob
servance; the princlpal feature of the
exercises of the day was to consist of
lectures and discourses upon topics re
lating to the welfare of the industrial
masses. Every question of political, so
cial and economic importance should be
discussed at the meetings on Labor day.
Those who address such meetings are
burdened with a weighty responsibility.
It is their duty to teach a doctrine of
Independence of thought and action to
the industrious, the right of man to all
that his labor creates, and the duty of
the Industrious as a self-reliant citizen
should all occupy the thought of the
speaker and be the theme of his dis
course.
"That which will best serve the living
men and women of to-day and the fu
ture should receive the careful att.n
tion of all who take part in honoring
that greatest of all factors in minister
ing to the good of the world, labor. If
Labor day is observed as it ought to be,
the gospel of humanity will be under
stood by all men and women, there will
be no slaves to employer, party, boss or
creed.
"The following is the list, in alpha
betical order of the states that adopted
Labor day legislation prior' to the na
tional law:
"Alabama-Hon. Oscar R. Hundley,
member of the senate from Huntsville.
introduced the bill making the first
Monday In September a holiday. to be
known as Labor day. The same was
enacted into law and received the sig
nature of Governor Thomas G. Jones on
Dec. 12, 1892.
"California-Senator N. C. Maher of
San Francisco introduced the measure
during the last session. It passed both
houses and received the approval of
Governor H. H. Markham on March. 21,
1t93. Labor day in California is held on
the first Monday of October.
'Colorado-On Jan. 20, 1887, Hon. Jo
seph F. Hooper of Leadville introduced
a bill in the legislature, and on March
15 of that year Governor Alva Adams
affixed his signature to the act after its
passage through both houses of the Col
oradd legislature.
"Connecticut-Hon. A. F. Hunte, on
Jan. 22, 1889, introduced the bill in the
Connecticut legislature: it became a
law and was approved by the governor
on March 20, 1899.
"Delaware-Senator John Pyle of
Wilmington irtroduced the Labor day
law in the legislature of Delaware. It
passed both houses and was approved
on Feb. 14, 1893. In Delaware the gov
ernor is not required to sign or ap
prove of laws passed by the legislature,
and the Labor day law bears the signa
ture of Charles B. Houston, speaker of
the senate, and Harvey Whiteman,
speaker of the house of representatives
of Delaware.
"Georgia-The legislature of 1891
passed into law the bill introduced by
Hon. E. W. Martin, and on Oct. 16 of
that year Governor W. J. Northen
signed the bill.
"Illinois-The Thirty-seventh general
assembly of Illinois passed the law
making the first Monday in September
a legal holiday. The bill was introduced
in the senate by Hon. Albert W. Wells
and approved by Governor Joseph W.
Fifer on June 17, 1891.
"Indiana-l- y an art of the legisla
ture. approved March 9, 1891. the first
Monday in September was made a legal
holiday, to be known as Labor day.
"Iowa--On Feb. 28, 1890, Hon. W. W.
Dodge introduced the original bill mak
ing Labor day a legal holiday to the
lowa senate. A substitute was offered,
and on March 19 all members of the
senate voted for the measure. It went
to the lower house and was adopted
there on March 26, all present voting
for it, and on April 5, 1890, was signed
by Governor Boles.
"Kansas-The custom of recognizing
the first Monday in September as Labor
day was established in Kansas in 1890,
and the governor of the state made it
legal by proclamation. At the session
of 1891 Governor Lyman I'. Humphrey,
in his biennial message, recommended
that the legislature enact the measure
Into law. Senator Elliston introduced
the bill in the senate. It became a law
and was signed by the governor on
March 4., 1891.
"Louisiana-Act 93 of 1892 makes Nov.
25 a legal holiday, to he known as La
bor day, in New Orleans and all cities
with a population of 100,000 inhabitan:s
in the state. Governor M. J. Foster ap
proved of the hill July 7, 1892.
"Maine-Maine enacted a law at the
session of the legislature held in 1891.
and declared the first Monday ln Sep
'tember to be a 'legal holiday, the same
as Thanksgiving, Christmas day, Deco
ration day and the Fourth of July are
now by law made public holidays.' The
bill originated in the house of represen
tatives, was presented by Hon. Edward
J. Irvine, and received the signature of
Governor Burleigh on Feb. It. 1891.
"Ma-uyland-A bill to make Decoration
day a legal holiday was Introduced in
the Maryland legislature in January,
1890, and became a law. While it was
on passage Hon. J. H. Jones of Balti
more offered an amendment making
Labor day a legal holiday, but it was
not adopted.
"Massachusetts-Massachusetts in the
session of 1887 acted upon a bill present
ed by Senator Alger of Cambridge, on
Feb. 2. It passed both houses, and 'o
May 11 of that year received the signa
ture of the governor.
"Michigan-There Is a bill before the
legislature of Michigan having for its
object the creating of a legal holiday, to
be known as Labor day, but definite ac
lion has not yet been taken upon it.
"MissourI-On the 14th day of the leg
islative session of 1889 Hon. Francis X.
Rotermann of St. Louis introduced the
bill to the Missouri legislature. When
the vote was taken it stood ayes 63,
nays 38: it required 71 votes to pass a
bill in the house, and the measure was
defeated.
"Montana-Montana piassed a law
making the first Monday in September
a legal holiday, to be known as Labor
day. This bill originated in the senate
and was introduced by Heon. E. D.
Matts. I do not know the date of the
adoption of the law, but it was at the
session of the Montana legislature held
In 1890-91.
"Nebraska-In Nebraska Senator
Frank Ransom, on Jan. 9, 1889, offered
a bill making Labor day a legal holi
day. It passed the senate by an unani
mous vote on the 17th of that month,
and on March 29 passed the house and
received the signature of the governor.
"New Hampshire-On June 7, 1897,
Mr. Stone of Andover introduced a bill
in the legislature of New Hampshire to
establish Labor day, but the committee
to which it was referred reported it
back with these words on the envelope,
'Inexpedient to legislate.' In the session
of 1891 Hon. Andrew KIlloren of Dover
introduced the Labor day bill. It passed
both houses and was signed by the gov
ernor, but I could not learn the date of
signature.
"New Jersey-H-on. William Harrigan
of Newark introduced a bill in the New
Jersey legislature on Jan. 31, 1887. It
passed both houses and was signed by
the governor on April 8, 1887.
"New York-On Jan. 4, 1887. Senator
Edward F. Reilly of New York city in
troduced the bill In the New York son
ate, and, after passing both houses, it
was signed by Governor HIill on May
6, 1887.
"Ohio-tn the Ohio house of represen
tatives Hon. John P. Green introduced
the Labor day bill on March 10. 1890. It
was signed by the speaker of the house
of representatives and president of the
senate on April 28, 1890.
"Oregon-In Oregon the hill was in
troduced by Hon. J. J. IPaley of lallas,
Polk county, on Jan. 17. 1837. and on
Feb. 21 of that year it received the sig
nature of the governor.
"Pennsylvania--In Pennsylvania the
bill was originally introduced by Iena
tor Lines on Jan. 17, 189S. It pasaed
both houses and was signed by Gover
nor Beaver on April 25 of that year.
"Tennessee-In the session of the leg
islature of Tennessee of 1891 Mr. Alla
man introduced a bill in the house of
representatives to make Labor day a le
gal holiday. The bill passed both houses
and was signed by Governor Buchanan
on March 11. 1891. At the session prior
to that the Tennessee legislature enact
ed a law making 'all days set apart for
holding county, state or national elec
tions legal holidays.'
"Texas-Senator Miles Crowley of
Galveston introduced the bill in the
Texas legislatdre to amend the revised
civil statutes by adding the first Mon
day In September to the list of legal
holidays, the same to be known as La
bor day. On the 10th of February, 1893.
the bill, after passing both houses, was
approved.
"Washington-Senator John R. Kin
near of Kings county introduced the
Labor day law in the legislature of
1891. It passed the house on the 9th of
February, the senate on the 28th of
January and was approved by the gov
ernor on Feb. 24, 1891.
"Wisconsin-In his annual message to
the last legislature Governor Peck said:
'A large number of citizens who cele
brate Artisans' day as an annual festi
val are desirous of having it made a
legal holiday. I feel much In sympathy
with this, to me, reasonable request of
people whose holidays are few, and
therefore commend this subject to your
careful consideration.' The bill, which
is now chapter 271 of the laws of 1893,
was introduced by Assemblyman Har
mon, passed the legislature on April 17,
received the approval of the governor
on the 19th of the same month and was
published as a law of Wisconsin on May
2, 1893. Section 1 of the bill reads: 'The
governor is hereby authorized to set
apart by proclamation one day each
year to be observed as Labor day, for
the purpose of affording all laboring
classes one day of rest and recreation,
and which day when set apart shall he,
and the same is hereby, declared a legal
holiday. The law does not specify what
day the governor shall designate, but
Governor Peck has assured the labor
organizations that such day as they
may select n ill be chosen by him as
Labor day."
Sons of St. George excur.lon to Deer
Lodge, Labor day, Sept. 4th. Fare for
round trip. $1.00: children, 50c.
Praised on All Sides.
"On to Manila" for one coupon and
25 cents has "caught on." Over two
thousand readers of the Anaconda
Standard have already taken advan
tage of this offer. Secure a copy to
day. Standard Office, Anaconda,
Butte. Missoula and Great Falls.
Copies will be mailed to any address
without extra chalrge.
Portraits of Montana's 1st regiment
commanders and line officers in "On
Manila." Only 25 cents each, when ac
companied by a coupon.
tLabor Day Excurslon.
On Labor day the Sons of St. George
will picnic at Deer Lodge. Excursion
trains will leave Montana Union depot
at 8:30 a. m.. 10:30 a. m. and 1 p. m., re
turning, leave Poor Lodge 5 p. m., 0:15
p. m. and 10 p. n. Fare, $100; children,
SOc.
$26 reward to any one proving that E.
F. Mayer, 40 West Park. does not put
in the best mainspring made for $1.
Watch cleaning. $1.50.
Montana Boys Coming Home.
"On to Manila" is just the thing to
read up before the Montana boys re
turn. It tells all abhout the campaign
in the Philippines and the movements
of the 1set Montana from the day they
departed from San Francisco to date.
One coupon and 25 cents secures a copy
at Standard office in Anaconda, Butte,
Missoula or Great Falls.
J. Spiegel, ladies' tailor. Furs remod
a:ed. No. 42 West Park street.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075141/1950-08-31/ed-1/?sp=5&q=labor+day</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOMPERS OWN STORY
OF LABOR DAY
HISTORY AND SIGNIFICANCE
of Labor day
By Samuel Gompers
(The 1921 Lahor Day
the founder and first
the AFL in the American Federa
tloliist of September, 1921 I
LaiÂ»
nual eelebration
let.il national holnlav
e
president of
'Inessa
Â»f Labor Day is
1 he liMory
f Lahor Day is significant of the
Dav. 1921, is the 27tl
a li
increasing strength and progrÃ¨s- of.
labor Lahor Day evolved from the
movement
as not handed down as a pres
by

aspirations the labor
it
eilt.
recognition was won
labor; it was not given to labor.
The united voluntary efforts
tin- workers themselves Â»established
11 P a a ho, 1
long betÃ¶re any slate legislature or
the national legislature enacted the
custom into statute law. I
But the history of the statute lau
if j
i

Northwestern
Bottling Works
A Sign of Quality
NORTHWESTERN
BEVERAGES
e

I
220 S. Montana .St.
Ph. 2-4502
I
j
*X^^*^K**X m n m m
til
1
CONGRATULATIONS
TO
ORGANIZED LABOR
i
Lovell Transfer Co.
121 E. Aluminum
Phone 6071
GREETINGS TO LABOR
B K CLUB
VISIT THE B K FOR YOUR FAVORITE
SANDWICHES, FRIED CHICKEN
AND SPAGHETTI
WINES
BEERS
LIQUORS
PHONE 9741
3544 HARRISON AYE.
ifiii
GREETINGS TO LABOR
TO OUR FRIENDS and CUSTOMERS
ACOMA LOUNGE
33 N WYOMING
ftlltf I .*i
LABOR DAY GREETINGS
PARKER MORELLI MOTOR COMPANY
I
STUDEBAKER DEALERS
t tf-if
i
i: "niiiiniiiiiiiirrni Â«â– Â«â€¢irt:.''

Greetings

To Organized Io*bor and Their Families

BUTTE BREWING CO.
220 No. Wyoming St.

KJ9BRI
in itself significant; it indicates
lu ever-increasing influence of the
oiioinic organizatiuns of labor over'
of political legis.
j the deliberations
of lators.

I 1 Ik* J.abur liay idea was ongi*
j I â€¢'Â»ted by p. J. Mdiuire. the founder
I Â»I the 1 Jrotherhoud of Carpenters
aland Joiner*. and for
f number of the K
j of the
li
many years a
Council
xecutive
\nurican Federation of I
.a
of. I or
I
At the meeting of the New York
J City Central Lahor Union held
May 8 1882,
I propriety of
in the
McCuire urged the
tting aside one day
on
year a> a general holiday
l,,r die laboring people. He sug -1
{tested that it he called ''labor Day." I
riÂ» idea was adopted by the I
Central Union and it staged
a Labor Day parade and festival
I on the tirst Monday in September,
MSJ
if j
r endorsed tin- national Labor Day
holiday at its 1884 convention, held
at l
American Federation of Lab
ago, 111 The convention
unanimously adopted the following!
resolution introduced by A. C. Cam
Illegale from the
i I rades and Labor
RKSOI.A l-.D, That the first Mon
i c
e roll,
L hii ago
Alliance;
September of each year he
a laborers' national
we recommend its
all wage workers
irrespective ol >e\. calling
lioiialitv.
in
set apart as
holiday, and that
observance In
or na
1 hrmigli tin* a
t Any of the
state
federations <>i labor and the central
labor bodies the Lahm Day demand
spread from citv
to city and state
til
state.
Many municipal councils and state
legal holiday.
Oregon was the tirst state to ac
*ede to labors' demand that Labor
legislatures made it</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075141/1935-08-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=labor+day</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SPECIAL LABOR DAY EDITlOlSf
OFFICIAL ORGAN OF THE MONTANA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR
Montana Labor News
There can be
without justly high
Earnings of
the basis and index of
y community.
standard of
be maintained
prosperity
The AmeriÂ«
living must
in order that American in
stitutions may not bo sub
ject to perils of discontent.
wages.
king people
progress
PUBLISHED WEEKLY BY THE SIEVED BOW TRADES AND LABOR COUNCIL
BUTTE, MONTANA, THURSDAY, AUGUST 29. 1935
No. 26
Vol. XI.
LABOR MESSAGE SOUNDS WARNING NOTE
48 STATES HAVE
LABOR DAY LAWS
First Law Making Labor Day
Legal Holiday Was Passed by
Oregon in February, 1887
Colorado, New Jersey, New
York and Massachusetts Also
Enacted Labor Day Laws
During That Year.
Wyoming Passed Last Law in
1923â€”Now Every State in the
Union, the District of Colum
bia, Hawaii, the Phillippine
Islands and Puerto Rico Have
Labor Day Statutes.
The Central Labor Union of New
York City started Labor Day on its
way as a general holiday on May 8,
1882, when the Council adopted the
plan presented by P. J. McGuire,
founder of the Brotherhood of Car
penters and Joiners, that one day in
each year should be set apart as a spe
cial holiday for working men and wo
men.
On the first Monday in September,
1882, the Central Labor Union spon
sored the first Labor Day parade, which
was reviewed in Union Square by
prominent labor leaders and ended with
a celebration and speeches in Elm
Park.
Following the New York City cele
bration several municipal councils
passed ordinances making the first
Monday in September a municipal
holiday, but it was not until 1887 that
the States initiated the movement to
make Labor Day a legal State holiday.
First Law Enacted by Oregon.
Oregon enacted the first State law
in 1887, The legislature fixed the first
Saturday in June as Labor Day, but in
September, 1893, changed the date to
the first Monday in September.
The action of Oregon was followed
in quick succession by the legislatures
of Colorado, New Jersey, New York
and Massachusetts, all of them enact
ing Labor Day laws i
The forty-eighth State to come un
der (he Labor Day influence was Wyo
ming whose legislature enacted a La
bor Day law in 1923.
Dates When Laws Were Passed.
Following is the list of States, com
piled from data in the Bureau of Labor
Statistics of (he United States Depart
ment of Labor, which have passed laws
making Labor Day a legal holiday, with
(he date of the enactment of the law
Alabamaâ€”December 12, 1892.
Alaskaâ€”March 28, 1913.
Arizonaâ€”April 29, 1912.
Arkansasâ€”January 29, 1903.
Californiaâ€”February 23, 1897. Under
the original law of California of May
23, 1893, Labor Day fell on the first
Monday in October.
Coloradoâ€”March 15, 1887,
Connecticutâ€”March 20, 1889.
Delawareâ€”February 14, 1893.
District of Columbiaâ€”June 28, 1894.
Floridaâ€”April 29, 1893.
Georgiaâ€”October 16, 1891,
Hawaiiâ€”1903.
Idahoâ€”March 5, 1909.
Illinoisâ€”June 17, 1891,
Indianaâ€”March 9. 1891.
Iowaâ€”April 5, 1890.
Kansasâ€”March 4, 1891,
Kentuckyâ€”March 17, 1902.
Louisianaâ€”July 8, 1912. The law en
acted July 7, 1892, affected Parish of
New Orleans only.
Maineâ€”February 10, 1891.
Marylandâ€”March 23, 1910.
Massachusettsâ€”May 11, 1887.
Michiganâ€”May 12, 1893.
Minnesotaâ€”April 18, 1893.
Mississippiâ€”March 4, 1904.
Missouriâ€”April 9, 1895.
Montanaâ€”February 19, 1895.
Nebraskaâ€”March 29, 1889.
Nevadaâ€”March 11, 1913.
New Hampshireâ€”March 31, 1891.
New Jerseyâ€”April 8, 1887.
New Mexicoâ€”March 15, 1915.
New Yorkâ€”May 6, 1887.
North Carolinaâ€”January 23. 1901.
North Dakotaâ€”March 13, 1909,
Ohioâ€”April 28, 1890.
Oklahomaâ€”May 23, 1908.
Oregonâ€”February 21, 1893, Under
the original law of Oregon of February
21, 1887, Labor Day fell on the first
Saturday in June.
Pennsylvaniaâ€”April 25, 1889. In
Pennsylvania by an act of May 31,
1893, the date of Labor Day was
changed to the first Saturday in Sep
tember, but by an act of June 23, 1897.
the original date was restored.
Philippine Islandsâ€”April 30, 1908.
May 1 is observed as Labor Day in the
Philippine Islands.
Puerto Ricoâ€”1902.
Rhode Islandâ€”May 26, 1893.
South Carolinaâ€”December 22, 1891.
South Dakotaâ€”February 12, 1907.
Tennesseeâ€”Mardh 11, i891.
Texasâ€”February 11, 1893.
Utahâ€”February 23, 1892.
Vermontâ€”November 26, 1898.
Virginiaâ€”February 5, 1892.
Washingtonâ€”February 24. 1891,
West Virginiaâ€”February 21, 1899.
Wisconsinâ€”April 19, 1893. Labor
Day is set by governor.
1887.
Labor Day Celebr i
Fort Pec 1
All Valley County Far
have consented to turn
and parade with the Feat. Trade
Unions at Glasgow, Montana, Monday,
September 2nd, 1935, Labor Day. Each
Fanners and Trades Union will be
designated by their local banners. The
High School Band will furnish the
march music and the principal float of
the procession will he an insignia of
(he American Federation of Labor,
mounted on a truck.
This emblem was made by the dif
ferent craftsmen represented in the
parade.
This parade and (he celebration fol
lowing will be the final climax sealing
(he bond of alliance recently created
between the Farmers' Unions and the
Trades Unions of Valley County.
The Trades Unions have an agree
able surprise for their Fraternal
Farmer brethern. Immediately after
the parade which is scheduled to start
from the courthouse at 11 o'clock, A. Mr
James D. Graham, President of the
Montana State Federation of Labor,
from Helena, will deliver the address
dedicating the initiative movement ad
vocating a Farm-Labor Alliance. Other
features of his address will be of in
terest to others besides Farmers and
Trade Unionists and for this reason
preparations are being made to accom
modate a large audience.
The Honorable Secretary of State,
Mr, Mitchell, has been invited to be
here and participate in the speaking.
His friendly attitude to Farmers and
Organized Labor is well known and
if he accepts this invitation the Farm
er-Labor parade promotors will feel
that their efforts have met with huge
success.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075189/1947-08-29/ed-1/?sp=3&q=labor+day&st=text&r=0.071,0.481,0.51,0.543,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
53 Years Since First National Labor Day
Labor's long fight against oppression
is highlighted by the issues it has
raised on Labor Day since the national
holiday was established in 1894.
1894-1905
The crucial issue of the period was
the rapid development of the trusts.
Golden tongued William Jennings
Bryan was one of the most popular
speakers at Labor Day demonstra
tions, where unionists raised the cry
for a boycott. On Labor Day 1901
workers demonstrated in support of a
strike against J. P. Morgan's new' steel
trust, U. H. Steel, and In 1903 parade
placards declared: "The trusts fight
usâ€”let's fight the trusts by not using
their goods."
1905-1915
As the trusts grew, so grew the vio
lence against labor. The use of in
junctions drew Labor Day wrath. AFL
Pres. Samuel Gompers told a 1907
Labor Day demonstration: "The in
junctions as issued against workmen
are never issued against any other
citizens. It is an effort to fasten an
offense against them when they are
innocent of wrongdoing." A 1910 pa
rader carried the slogan; "Plutocracy
Governor's
(I 'on I In lied from Paire One)
the event of dissolution of the corpor-1
ation shall not be deemed forbidden
to such non-profit corporations". (Em
phasis ours)
Obviously, the three or more actual
incorporators of one of these "social
clubs" will be able to find sufficient
use for all the funds accruing from
the operation of the club for "legiti
mate operating and administrative ex
penses". And the other simple card
holding members will have to get all
their benefits from supplying the cash
for these "operating and administra
tive expenses".
Special Session Might Be
Embarrassing
It is not expected that the Governor
will call any special session to stop
the organization of these clubs. It is
the general opinion of competent at
torneys that the racket can be stopped
by simple court action. Moreover,
the embarassing question he has to
answer ofâ€”why he saw fit to veto
HB 403 which would not have permit
ted the present flood of organization
of "social club" rackets even though
HB 353 had been passed or even SR 75,
would be sure to be brought up in a
special session.
And "Saintly Sam" would have a
hard time justifying himself. His ter
rible anger about conditions now indi
cates considerable histrionic ability,
and perhaps may be just an opening
gun in a campaign to endear himself
again with the more straight-laced
of the church people of the state, who
are not familiar with all phases of
why these conditions exist.
They can be laid squarely at the door
of Saintly Sam. Had he not vetoed
HB 403 they would not be here.
steals our soap, then calls us the great
unwashed."
As the first world war hung over
the land, labor opposed U. S. participa-;
tion. On Labor Day 1915 AFL Sec.
1915-1920
Frank Morrison declared: "Labor
sees the wolf of militarism concealed
behind the Little Red Riding Hood
pretense of those men responsible for
Ludlow." His reference: the mass
acre of 33 w'omen and children in the
historic strike against John D. Rocke
feller's Colorado Fuel Iron Co. Labor
Day 1917 saw' most of labor swing to
support the war which the U. S. had
entered.
1920-1925
End of the war brought quick re
newal of the onslaught against labor.
Labor Day 1922 saw the union move
ment, threatening a general strike,
rallied in opposition to Atty. Gen.
Harry Daugherty's sweeping injunc
tion against striking railroad shop
men. Charged Sam Gompers; Daugh
erty is "exercising a pow r er never 1
dreamed of in the history of the re
public."
fought for democracy and got 23c an
hour."
Slogan of the times: "We
1925-1930
The so-called Golden '20s brought
a lull in union militancy, a slump in
union membership as many thought
the millenium had come to stay.
1930-1935
But the end came with a crash,
bringing with it bewilderment, bitter
criticisim of Herbert Hoover's do
nothingism, growing demands for un
employment relief, jobs, security. The
advent of the New Deal brought the
NRA and section 7 (a) and labor's
resentment channeled itself into sud
den union growth. Employers' oppos
ition drew from AFL Pres. William
Green on Labor Day 1933 a demand
for court action against violators of
NRA collective bargaining agree
ments.
Revise Concept of
IContinued from Page One)
the hardest pressed,* Harsch said.
Their traditions and their pride make
their present lot difficult to endure
because it precludes normal prewar
social life. Many of them talk about
leaving England, and those who get
the chance to migrate seize it eagerly,
he continued.
Military Methods Won't Do It
The struggle to contain Communist
influence in Europe promises to be
long-drawn, subtle and not susceptible
to the use of military methods, he con
cluded. From the British, who coped
with the job of keeping tabs on the
Czarist Empire during the 19th cen
tury, Harsch derived the impression
that the conflict will have to be waged
by the same slow, persistent diplomat
ic, economic and political means.â€”PM,
New York City.

.a
and would like to have the rest of it. They
turally against any project, or any new wealth creation,
they cannot absolutely control and exploit in their own
private interest.
are na
Great masses of the common people
â€”the people who made this country and still keep it
afloat as a going concernâ€”are growing tired of being
pushed around, cut off, chiseled on, and high priced
into pauperism, and they want a development in which
they can share, have a say, and enjoy security.
The Big Boys have the jack, control most of the
avenues of publicity, and are able to employ a whole
legion of henchmen and fixers. Moreover they finance
a lot of politicians into power and are able to apply
a heavy pressure on those they do not own. All this
permits them to keep the real issue either concealed or
so muddled that the man in the street is often a long
time getting it straightened out in his own mind. Bas
ically this does not change the actual issue, it only
muddles things and delays final settlement.
'I o force settlement in their own interest and by
overwhelming numbers the common folks have the
votes.
The only question is whether they will use this
power to the best purpose, which is their own self-in
terest.
It is a safe bet that ninety-nine percent of in
dividuals who have an assured income of $10,000 per
year or more are, and will continue to be, against an
MVA. Ninety-nine percent of those with incomes less
than $10,000 per year should be for an MVA. The
great majority of them undoubtedly will be when they
understand that self-interest is quite as important to
them as it is to he Big Fat Boys who will vote the
other way.
the political theory of "the greatest good to the greatest
number." It is still a good principle if we will only
make it work.â€”JEROME G. LOCKE, Member of Reg
ional Committee for MVA.
After all our government was founded
on
1935-1940
The labor upsurge sharpened the
split on craft vs. industrial unionism,
brought the sudden bursting birth of
the CIO, headed by John L. Lewis,

On Labor Day 1937, as Green hailed
the U. S. supreme court's decision up
holding the Wagner act establishing
labor's right to bargain collectively,
Lewis reported the CIO's organizing
and sitdown strikes had won it a mil
lion new members in its first year.
1940-1945
Labor Days at the turn of the de
cade found labor divided on its atti
tude toward World War II. Some
unions favored all aid to those fight
ing the Axis short of U. S. involve
ment. Others held a hands-off posi
tion. But Labor Day 1942, nine
months after U. S. entry, found labor
united in support of the fight. Labor
Day 1945 was a day of victory and
mourning. The w r ar was w'on. Frank
lin D. Roosevelt w r as dead.
1945-1947
Keynote of the postwar period was
struck by William Green, Labor Day
1946, when he declared: "The forces
of fascism in America have determined
to smash trade unions." Said
CIO Pres. Philip Murray; "Greed and
profiteering" threaten our "economic
liberty."</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075141/1950-08-31/ed-1/?sp=6&q=labor+day&st=text&r=-0.316,-0.263,1.094,1.094,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Labor Day,
1950
By MAURICE TOBIN
Secretary of Labor
labor Day, 195o, has a -pccial
significance. It comes at a time when
the United States ha- accepted the
challenge of totalitari-m by going
to the defense of the people in South
Korra and all other peoples menaced
by Communistic aggression Organ
ired labor has thrown itself into
mi and
this struggle with all 'its
might.
I.ahor is free and ran be free
only in a democracy American labor
realizes that there can be no freedom
for workers in Communist-domin
ated countries. Free workers under
stand that they owe it to themselves
and their handcuffed brothers un
der totalitarian rule to join unre
servedly in the fight to set worker
free in every part of the world
Americans are lovers of peace
They have shown a spirit of inter
national fellowship which ha- gone
beyond faith to works, Onr action
have brought relief and hope to
the stricken and oppressed of other
land-. Onr actions have made ti
the protector of helple
women everywhere.
men and
We did not like persecution and
tyranny. We won our release front
oppression many years ago.
cherish the rights of a freedom
loving people We have never hesi
tated to help others enjoy the same
priv ileges.
That is why vve have gone to the I
We

LABOR DAY
GREETINGS
from
The Wulf Realty
FIRE INSURANCE
List Your Home for Sale
With Us
NEW PARK MARKET
615 W. PARK
CALL 2-2361
BUTTE TIN SHOP
Phone 2-2446
W. C. Wills</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
