<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport&st=text&r=0.137,0.75,0.143,0.152,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
>a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.
se metpractice is required to learn it and there
6, no incident roughness if the rules are
stictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr.
deyce is try to have other teams formed in the
symmasisme in the city and to have regular
entestn between them. It eomameade itself in
s it can be played in almost any sized room
den any had of lot. whether it be large or
mail, and that the number of player. need
only be limt. I b the size of the ground. It
bkings into play all maseles of the body. thus
being a healthy exercise, and at the same time
te a ws incidens to moet sports are want
1. The only apparatus neessary for the
oe to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball
mnd re half-bushel baskets.
movwr rT PL 6TD.
Theegh she courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Stan
aoprter witnessed a game of basket ball played
M the Carrer Institute on one of the evenings
of this week. The two baskets are attached to
th =anig strack at the opposite ends of the
gymmsam and U.s object of the game is to
Shen e heU in the opponent'e basket. The
uame consist of mine men each. made up of a
gaiheeper. two backs to assist him. a center, a
eight and left henter, two forward and a home
ma. They are arranged in this order from
Oe gnal whica they are defending. It is not
asessmry that the players thou!d remain in
teir glaces. but they should move in such a
way as to gie the forward player an oppo:
baesy Is gee a good tos at the goal or the
baecks to keep theer opponents from obtaining
so mmm by taking it from thea when they are
ghbntsto throw. It is the luty of the goal
ba~to beep the ball away fromi the vicinity.
etgoal. end it is more often neessary for
hi to bat the bail with his had tha for
e~er meambers of the seama to do so.
L. Serim. 3. leeward
4.ame.. eae...
4. Sm. .a.5
en.. ...s-....e.
The game is started by the teems lining up
ba their respseutve positions and then the
safeae tomes the ballian the air, It must not be
te.-d antal it strikes the ground. Thea the
players ean catch it. and the object of the one
who obtains it isto pass istso one of the players
ahis own sidec.who either passes itto inotherwho
msay be in a favorable position to tom f~ar goal
or else attempts to auake a goal himself. To
bee a foot bal into a basket euasiended ten feet
a cen SsA.av
beG airani eiasest lags en~t. held it.ie
net en eas messean means, end thee.
thanmy ethe at guat are madebut
as t ase -s eemtl, and e sensty
ohB~in meds. esnammty, an the
qshad esty. The haDeam be aoma
an ists with -n or beth --a-~
In bM the sesm s e 40 -a -e
e be h ss:
asmmmS he es h the det er hased
A e esms e with te hasb mUs
am thmm... ..a. a. he
Gotas o ben shile rmaI and Mas to stop
The har maw be held in ds baud The arms
Iee or bod soat not be used for blding it.
If h lb is beld for any length of time th
referee tess it into the air. as in the baegtnmg
of theam
o the5 ein, holding, J~n .trp, n
or striking b allowed. The t iafringem m
'f this rule eosnts a foal and a second dis
q"mli= a player, but, as in foot ball, a substi
tats may take his place.
IN TaN BAsKET. C
When a ball goes out of bounds it is put in
play in the same way as in a foot ball game.
The game consists of two halft of twenty
minutes each or such time as the captains may
decide on. and time is taken out for delays.
A goal counts three points and a foul one
point for the opponent. and a majority of the
points decides the game.
There are a referee and umpire, whose duties
are the same respectively as the same officials
in a foot ball game.
Any player has a right to get the ball at any
time while it is in the field of play. provided
that he handles only the ball and not the op
ponent.
ADVANTAGEs OF THE GAME.
To an observer the game seemed to be one
that will solve the problem, which has been a
knotty one for some time, of introdncing a
game which will meet the excitement incident
to most outdoor sports and at the same time
be suitable for indoor play. At present when
the outdoor season closes most of the athletes
drop tbe sports in which they have been in
terested and the benefits thev derived from
them are lost. This game is one that requires
skill and agility. but strength is not one of the
necessary factors. and, consequently. men of
all physical conditions can take part in it. It
has also been found to have been a useful
sport for girls and women, as it is especially
APTEn THE FALL.
adapted to securing good health without having
the nervous strain caused by some of the
sports now indulged in.
In its principli. it is a combination of foot
ball and lacrosse. It resembles foot ball in
most of the rulings, but in the method to be
pursued to obtain a goal the game more closely
resembles lacrosse. Although at first glance it
would hardly seem possible to have any amount
of team play in the game, still it is only by the
concerted action that a team can play to the
beet advantage. A novice in the game inva
riably feels disposed when he obtains the ball
to make a shot for the goal, which could not be
made from any distance one time in a hundred,
as in order that the ball should remain in the
basket it has to be skillfully and easily tossed,
not thrown. A good player will. when he has
the ball, quickly look for one of his own team
who is in an uncovered position to whom he
can tos it. In this way a well-drilled team
could almost entirely keep the ball from the
hands of a team made up of new men. Quick
ness of eye, hand and foot is one of the first
requisites for a good player, and he also must
keep his head about him. A moment's hesita
tion or a wrong pass may give considerable
advantage to the other side.
If an umpire is chosen who strictly follows
the rules of the game there is little chance for
any roughness, as running with the ball is
prohibited, and thus the injuries coming from
sharp tackling in foot bal are done away with.
The attention of the player is fastened on the
ball and personal feeling in the matter is lost
sight of. The object of each player when one
of his side obtains the ball is to place himself
in an uncovered position so that one of his own
team can pays it to him, while the opponents
should in this eae stick closely to the men
with whom they are paired so that a pass to
them would gave an equal opportunity for each
to catch the ball. It is in this respect that
cool-beadedt.euand quickness count. Idi
vidlual play on the part of one man will destroy
all the good work that the rest of the team may
do. If the game in played indoors in a gym
naisium the passee should be more of a toes
rather than hard straight throw.
As the game has apparently obtained a good
foothold in this city and as it is a healthful and
at the same times exciting sport it is to be
hoped that the efforts of Mr. Joyce to make the
game a popular one in this city will meet with
success, Some of the men under him are bo
conming quite proficient and before long he will
have a iirst-class team,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86088296/1893-06-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Indoor</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GAME OF BASKET BALL.
Interesting and Exciting Sport For Thos
Not Able to Exercise Kegularly.
The unnounceinent that at a woman's
educational institution not far from this
city tho students played a close and ex
citing game of "basket ball" wasperhaia
the first item which attracted public at
tention to a sport that is rapidly becom
ing very popular in this country among
those who have neither the physique nor
the taste for baseball or football. The
rules of the new sport are comparatively
simple, and the ease with which the
fundamental laws of the game can be
acquired in a few minutes' practice have
served to make it popular wherever it
has been introduced, while its freedom
from much of the roughness and intri
cacy of football has also tended to make
the devotees of basket ball enthusiastic
in their praise of its merits.
The name "basket ball" is derived from
the fact that scores are made not by car
rying the ball across the goal lines or
kicking it over the goal bar as in foot
ball, but by throwing the spheroid into I
a moderately small basket, which is hung
about 10 feet above the ground or floor.
To accomplish Buch a feat usually re
quires much practice, and as a rule tho
try at goals are far more numerous than
tho scores. Either hand or both hands
can be used in holding the ball, and it
must either he thrown or be batted with
tho open hand a punch with the fist or
arm, or a kick, constituting a foul.
The game differs from football also in
tho fact that no player is allowed to run
with the ball, but must stand where it is
caught, and a fair catch can be made
only with the hands. If the ball is held
for an unnecessarily long time, the um
pire takes possession of it and puts it
"ia play" by throwing it in the air, no
player being allowed to touch it in such
an event until it has struck the ground.
If a ball goes out of bounds, it is put in
play as in football, and no player is "off
sido," but every player has the right to
touch the ball anywhere or everywhere
in the game, provided the ball is in play.
No pushing, tripping, 6hoving or tac
kling is allowed, and every such offense
constitutes a foul, which gives one point
to the opposing nine. As a goal counts
but threo points and a foul one. there is
every incentive to avoid rough play. The
players advance the ball by tossing it to
some member of their own nine, and
there is the best opportunity for success
in personal skill combined with good
team play. The "forwards" and "cen
ters" usually toss the ball forward, but
when it gets dangerously near his own
goal, the goalkeeper often bats it with
tho open palm.
Ono advantago which basket ball has
over many other forms of popular sport
lies in tho fact that, while it allows 18
players to participate, it can be pursued
tho year round in tho open air during
tho warmer months and in the gymna
sium whilo cold weather prevails. Again,
basket ball can be played by persons
whose physique is not of tho most robust
type, although many athletes also have
found, in it a healthful form of exercise.
It has pypved of great value In furnish
ing exercise for business men, women
and children, as wpll as brawny students,
and from the general success it has al
ready attained wherever it has been in
troduced there is every probability that
basket ball will soon become a very popu
lar and widespread form of outdoor and
indoor sport. Boston Advertiser.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1894-11-25/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Sport+Game+Indoor+Outdoor&st=text&r=0.17,0.243,0.165,0.175,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text><BASKET BALL
JTHAMChGIVIXO GAlE 31ETWEEX
oPlioUORES AXD IRESllJIE
3 Iopular and Graceful Game bat
Has Foiinil Great Favor AnioiiK
Girls Some of the Rules nUll HeK
iilations Observed in PlajinK1 It
Basket ball is to tie womens col
lege what football is to the mens
The Bryn Mawr girls are particu
larly enthusiastic over this sport and
the Smith college students are in train
ing for a match game some day
Thanksgiving week
A picked nine from the sophomore
class will be pitted against a picked
nine from the freshmen class The
Smith college girl is immensely inter I
ested in basket ball which she also
calls cradle ball
1
I j
I
r
r
j
1DiUikct For IIKIOOM
Daslcct Vac Outdoor
L At Bryn Mar the students are
equally as devoted to this game in
deed their interebt in it is tremendous
and vies with 5 oclock teas and the
atricals in mitigating the ennui l of var
sity life The freshman and sopho
more classes are particularly alive to
this sport Miss Elsa Bowman is the
captain or the sophomores nine while
Miss Corlnne Putnam is the leader of
the freshman
WHY THE GAME IS POPULAR
The beauty of tne gameor one of I
I its beauties for it has manyis that II
it can be played by any number and
the more he merrier it is usually i
J
J voted The ideal number however is
nine on each side There is a goal I
keeper two backs to assist a center
a right and left center two forwards I
and a home man I e a woman in this
c1 TJ y
Tire accompanying diagram shows
the positions of the players
The end and aim of the game is to
toss a ball which is the size of a small
football into one of the two large bas
kets suspended at each end of the field
The winning side is the one that lands
the ball in the opponents basket The
basket is placed about ten feet high
When the game is played in the
gymnasium the basket Is bracketed to
tb side of the wall For outdoor use
it is supported at the same height by
au upright post The price of the bas
Jets or goals is 15 per pair for in 1
door use when supplied with a pipe
or post for outdoors the cost is some
what more The balls which are cov
ered with Jeather and about twenty
A four inches in circumference cost
about 3 each a rubbercoated ball
J can be purchased for 115 1
Basket ball can be played in a gym I
nasium in a large room or a small
b 1 HeW 01 a large field if in the latter I I
as many as thirty or fifty players may I
take part I
APPROPRIATED BY WOMEN I
The man who originated the game j
01 invented it or whatever the proper
word may be did not intend it merely
for amusement his idea was to pro i
vide a good allaround physical exer
cise and as such it cannot be im
P oyed upon combining as it does run
ning jumping bending pnd twisting
nearly every muscle and joint in the
body is brought into exercise
Mr James Naismith of Springfield i
Mass originated basket ball about
I
three years ago As soon as it became
known among the gymnasiums it
spread like an fclHdenfie Primarily
intended for young men for whom
most of the good things of life are in
tended it was soon taken up by young
women who declared that If there
was anything good in the game they
would like io become acquainted with
itThe
The girl forthwith bought a book of
rules which they masteredin very
brief order donned their gymnasium
ostumes and began playing at once
The fine points of the game however
Were only acquired by practice
I RULES OBSERVED
j The three players ivho are designat
ilL ed as forwards occupy the third of
the ground nearest the opponents
pwal the centers occupy the middle
third and the backs the defensive
third of the ground The forwards
of one team stand near the backs of
the other
Out of doors with plenty of room
the field may be 150 feet long the goal
lines running through the baskets per
pendicular to the length of the field i
the side boundaries 100 feet apart
The ball is put in play IJ by the icferee 1
throwing it up in the middle of the
field this is done at the commence
ment of the game at the beginning of
the second half after each goal and J
when a foul has been made The time
of play is two halves of twenty min I
utes each I
A goal is made when the ball is I
Yf thrown or batted from the ground into
the basket provided it stays in It is
a foul if the ball Is struck with the
I fijts or kicked
The ball must be held by the hands
fl
0
i
the arms or body may not be used for
I holding it
No pushing tripping shouldering or
striking is allowed infringements of
this rule count as a foul
The score is counted by points A
goal counts three points a foul one
point for the opponents A majority of
points decides the game/text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023253/1895-01-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Games+Sport+Baskets&r=0.354%2C0.788%2C0.735%2C0.391%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL.
Those who were interested in the
basket ball games played last winter
will be pleased to learn that the town
and school boys are tohaveonemore
battle for the supremacy. A word
about the game which has become so
popular in the past few years will
be interesting to those who enjoy
good honest sport.
Basket ball was invented in 1889 by
ames Nuismith, teacher in the interna
tional training school, Springfield. Dur
ing its first season it wasnot particularly
popular hut has gained in favor and may
now be called quite as important sport in
the Y. M. C. A. world as football and
baseball, but it is essentially an indoor
game and the interest that is excited in
an exercise confined to the gymnasium
can perhaps never equal the zest which is
thrown into a game like football, played
under the blue of heaven, in the fresh out
door atmosphere and sun's rays that seem
to penetrate the muscles ot the athlete
and impart added vivacity. However,
at the season when football bruises have
long ago healed and conquests on the
gridiron are matters for rumination, he
who sighs for the pigskin can find much
satisfaction in basket ball, it possessing
all the elements of football but, if rules
are enforced, lacking the excessive rough
ness. The ball used is perlcctly round,
made of a rubber bladder, covered with
leather and is about a foot in diameter.
Briefly outlined the game according to
official rules for 1805, is played as follows:
baskets especially constructed tor the
purpose, are placed in a vertical position
with the mouth ten feetlrom the ground,
one at each end of the field (gymnasium),
occupying much the same position in re
lation to the players as do football goals.
i ne competitive teams tane positions on
the field as in football, save that there is
no line-up, The teams are composed of
five men when the playing space is less
than 1800 square feet, seven when it is
more than 1800 and less than 3600 and
nine men when over 3600. The referee,
with a player from each side, takes posi
tion in the center. He puts the ball in
play by throwing it up. Which side has
first ball depends on which center man
secures it. The ball is not kicked or
struck with the fists but thrown or batted
with the flat of the hand and the object
is, to get it into the basket, doing which
scores a goal. On the number of goals
secured depends the victory. The net
work of rules which govern the action of
the game is quite as elaborate as football
and will not be given here. Suffice it to
say that spectators easily comprehend
its action. The putting of a ball into the
basket may seem a veryeasv thing to do
but as a matter of fact it is very difficult
to acomplish with the floor empty and,
of course, much more so when two teams
are at strife. One of the rules says that
the ball shall always be kept in motion.
Two twenty-minute halves are played
with a rest of ten minutes between "the
halves. This is the time of actual play.
Each side has itscaptain while position
is the same as in baseball. The referee is
judge of the ball. He is the superior offi
cer ot the game and decides all questions
uul ucuimciy lulling on me umpire, i lie
umpire is judge of the men, calls all fouls,
notifies the offenders and has power to
disqualify men.
The game which was to be played
on Thursdayevening of this week has
been postponed until Saturday even
ing. The two teams have been prac
tising faithfully and will be able to
play a very interesting game. It is
hoped that the public will turn out
and encourage the gymnasts, as all
the proceeds over and above the ex
penses are to go towards much need
ed new apparatus for thegymnasium.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-04-02/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Co-eds+Basket+Ball+Match+Basketball+Basket-ball+Teams+Team&st=text&r=0.651,0.558,0.294,0.313,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CO-EDS AT BASKET BALL
Secret Practice at Berkeley for
the Great Match on
Saturday.
Greek Letter Fraternities to Present
Plays Paul Revere Lodge
Was Honored.
BERKELEY, Cal., April I.â€” The Berke
ley Co-ed basket-ball team are ready for
their battle with the Stanford nine next
I Saturday. They have gone into secret
practice and are devoting their time and i
i attention to signal work and to giving
their muscles the hnal course of ex
ercise before they stand up against
the wearers of the cardinal. They
are ail on the gui vive, as are
j the other women athletes of the
i university, for the contest on Saturday
will be t*e first contest they have entered
for honors. "We have the reputation and
the athletic prestige of the university to
uphold," said one of the fairest members
of the team to-day, "and we are going into
1 the struggle with* the purpose of coming
i out victors. We realize the odds we will
have to contend against in not being in as
I good training as we might, and then the
Stanford girls are much more experienced
than we. At any rate we will do our best,
J since we have accepted Stanford's chal
i lenge."
Two or three of the young women have
the appearance of being overtrained,
judging from their pallid faces and worn
expression. This may be due, however, to
anxiety over the result of the came. Tlieir
new costumes consist of white sweaters
and blue bloomers with gold trimmings.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-12-18/ed-1/?sp=18&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+K+U+Naismith+Sport+Team&r=0.599%2C1.081%2C0.403%2C0.214%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL AT I U.
XKW BAJIE I.. CHKlT FA VII IX IX TUB
CLASSIC SHADES OF LA1VIIEACU.
How It I Plajeil The Tennis That
Ilnie Hern Formed The Fncnlty
Eiijoj- Ihe Game Clinncellur
Snow a. Crack Plnjer.
LAWRENCE. KAS.. Dec. 17.-(SpeciaU
The basket ball "fever" has broken out
In Its most violent form among Kansas
university people. Dr. Naismith. the new
physical director, brought the germs with
him, and that they were healthy specimens
is evidenced by their activity.
At first only a few of the students siw
in basket ball the diversion. But the dis
ease spread rapidly. Not only doe- eai h
class already possess its basket ball team,
but the literary and the scientific men of
the faculty are backing their "crack fives.
Eve-ry evening the gymnasium is filled with
a scrambling mass of humanity, and the
spectators who can recognlz. a friend or
acquaintance In the melee must be gifterd
with second sight.
Five men compose a team at basket ball.
The floor Is divided into three parts. Tho
center men of the plaving teams oe-upy a
space chalked off in the middle, am, the
other four dispose themselves In various
graceful attitudes in the end sections. The
referee tosses up the ball just above the
heads of the centers, who are standing
face to face. Each makes a jump and en
deavors to hit the hall, knocking it over
to his own men and toward his goal. Then,
the scramble begins. The accomplished,
and gentlemanly contortionist in the pat
ent medicine show could not rival basket
ball players In the way of tying French
knots in their corporal systems. The ma.-s
of writhing humanity turns over and over
in kaleidoscopic fashion, suddenly un
winds itself and is again resolved Into
parts. A man goes diving after the ball
and comos triumphantly up out of the
fray with his arms full of another man's
head! The aim In playing basket ball, so
it Is claimed. Is to throw the ball Into tho
round baskets, suspended at each end ot
the field, a greater number of times than
the opposing players. In reality, however,
it would seem that the cherls-hed object of
each plajer was to make as large and
choice collection of hruises as possible.
But that is basket ball from the specta
tor's point of view. To the players It Is
an all absorbing sport. Some of them
even have the audacity to assert that It Isi
a "gentle game, don't you know." Gentle,
indeed! One might as appropriately speak
of a bucking broncho as "well-mannered."
When the field Is not divided into sec
tions the game is reallr rough, but If thi
chalk lines are drawn, and fouls are faith
fully called whenever a man over-teps.
his boundaries, the bruise hunter adds to
Ills collection more slowly. It Is amusing:
to watch the players trying to remember
to have the proper respect for the bound
aries. Indeed It is truly pathetic to sej
what limitations of power a simple chalk
line can put on thee great, strong athletes.
In actual agony they har.g over the edge
and reach out helpless, longing arms to
ward the ball. Now and then an unruly
foot goes across the line, and then the
sharp whistle of the referee Is heard. A
foul entitles the players ort the otht.r side
a chance at throwing goal.
The game consists of two halves of
twenty minutes each. A twenty minute
rest is given between, and a new- team
put on to utilize the rest time. Each time
the ball goes Into the basket two points
are scored for the side whose goal Is
thrown As In baseball, a small score
Indicates a good game.
The Inventor of Ilnsket Hnll.
Dr. James Naismith Is the inventor of
basket ball. Unlike most of our games It
Is not the development of some medieval
sport. It was worked out on scientific
principles to meet a long felt want. Dr.
Naismith was physical director of a Y.
31. C. A. training school at Springfield.
Mass.. where the problem of supplying thlsj
need was brought to him for solution.
Busket ball was the result. It was In the
winter of 9I-52 that the game was intro
duced. The rules were made out and hung
In the "gym" fdr the inspection of playerj
before the game was ever tried. The men
were a little skeptical "at first about it.
but after the; ball was once thrown up no
coaxing was needed to Induce them to
Play. Basket ball came Into general favor
first through the Y. M. C. A. Having been
Introduced through the association it was
natural that it should spread through that
medium. Before long, however, colleges be
gan to investigate and adopt the game, ami
In the short .-pace of seven yeirs It has
gaimd a wide iopuhirlty. In the Eastern
colleges, both for men anil for womn.
basket ball Is the reigning favorite among
sports. The rules are not changed for tho
young women players, though doubtless the
game is played with a bit more tenderness.
Though at first sight the game appears
to be a free for all scramble. It soon be
comes evident that a number of sclentiilr?
,1'laya are iossibIe. Unfailing good judg
ment, anu goon muscular control are the
first requisites for a good player. The treat
ment of the ball Is the subject of several
rules. It can be tossed, rolled on Ihe floor
and pushed around, but must never In
kicked. There are no signals, and a play
lasts until the ball Is passed Into the basket.
Tennis In the 1'iilverslt jr.
The Kansas university men are going to
be great basket ball enthusiasts. Each
class has a picked team, and places on thei
teams are as much sought as on the var
sity eleven. Among faculty members thero
are two teams the Snow hall and tho
Frazer hall, representing the scientists and
the literary men. On the former team
Dr. WHHston. Marshall Barber. Clarenco
McClung. A. H. Clark and Dr. Naismith
hold positions. Their opponents are A.
G. Cantield. AY. H. Carruth. E. M. Hop
kins. M. W. Sterling and Archie Hogg.
On Tuesdays and Thursdays at 3 p. m. thesj
distinguished individuals lay aside their
dignity and their collars, don sweaters anil
pugilistic airs, and come forth into the
arena to dw battle. With a grace that
is acciuired only through long years of
bending over desks and laboratory tables,
they scamiier now here, now there, after
the elusive canvas sphere.
When the faculty teams met for their
last practice. Chancellor Snow- appeared.
He was Immediately besieged to play. The
chancellor protested that he was too green,
but such fetching invitations could never
be turned dotvn. The head of the universi
ty disappeared Into a dressing room, and
In a few moments, he emerged In a cos
tume of which the most noticeable feat
ures were- white canvas shoes, a seraphic:
grin, and a neutral tinted sweater. With
characteristic vigor he attacked the game,
and before long he was the champion play
er. There is nothing slow about the chan
cellor when he gets into action.
Tournament in January.
On January 13 an Indoor tournament will
be given. Basket hall will be the chief
feature of the c-xhihltlon. The old skat
ing rink on Kentucky street will probably
be rented for the occasion. Dr. Naismltii
says he enjoys working with college men
far better than with others. He believes
there is no artificiality whatever about e-ol-Iege
students. "If a man is a man they
will respect him and his endeavors in their
behalf." he says, "but they won t Stan. I
trilling a minute. When I find it yo'ing
fellow who kicks on the referee's decision-..
I just ask him n call fouls for a few mo
ments. After he has called a few and other
men have kicked on his rulings, h,. never
kicks again."
Pr. Naismith has much influence t
the young men in his charge. In Mrs. Cora
McColli,m Smith he has an able colleague.
The revolution In feeling which a few yearn
have brought about among the physical
culture students Is remarkable. When the
training was first Introduced about four
years ago and the girls lirst donned their
suits, the presence of a man within a ra
dius of three blocks wrought the most
awful consternation. Now men pass back
and forth throuch the r-vm to and from
the laboratory during the girls" cla.-aes and
ni'liing is thought ot it. Before long :hi
g.rls will trv basket ball. too. Equal suf
frage in ainietirs is one oi me cnarms of
Kansas university. Visitors to Lan-rem-o
must get a basket ball guide beforehand and
lecrn tne nngo. it tney wis.i to dd able to
converse intelligently with university peo
nle. for that is the all absorbing rnnle re
the day. It may not be a great while. Judg-
i hi; iruiii uiijjemuiii e ueioic processors
will be whistling students down in their
recitations and -allInc "foul" when thir
make mistakes in their translations, so
jreai is cue iiiuiience oi iiaoit</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92053934/1904-11-19/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Rules+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Dribble&st=text&r=0.506,0.568,0.197,0.21,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW RULES ON BASKETBALL
Changed Conditions For Championship
Contests.
Up to the present the basketball
rules have been amended each season
by additions and omissions in various
places. This year, however, the rules
have been rearranged and many rules
bear different numbers and are not
found in the same successive order.
An advantage in the new rule book
also is that at the top of the page i3
the page, so that it is no longer neccs-
indicated the rule number printed on
that page, so that it is no longer ne
cessary to turn back or forth to ascer
tain which rule is being read.
The first new feature is that the
rules became effective Nov. 1, 1904.
This settled a fixed time for everywhere
and did not leave it open for teams to
play old Ule3 because "they did not
have the new book and there is noth
ing in the rules saying when they be
come effective," In referring to the
basket, the word "basket" is not used
in contradiction to "goal."
The minimum size of playing space
(2,400 square feet) is omitted in rule 1.
section 1. Rule 3, section 1, requires
a background of wood at least three
quarters of an inch thick for the bas
kets. Screens are no longer permitted.
The paying of the officials expenses in
serial championship games is no longer
mandatory.
An important change in rule 11, sec
tion 10. prohibits more than one player
of each team from tackling the ball at
the same time. A "dribble" is now
only counted such when the player ad
vances more than two steps wtiile roll-
UDUDDDDGBD
You can eat anything, digest it and
enjoy it if you give your stomach a
thorough course of treatment with
Dr. laber's Pbpsin lompouna.
Perhaps your stomach is over
worked and accumulates undigest
ed matter whici ferments and up
sets the entire system, causing
belching and bloating, bad breath,
a languid, weary feeling, sleep
lessness, etc.
T&ESER'SIEEEMMlGOrJlFOUnD
cleans out the refuse, heals the irritated secretive linings of the stomach, stim
ulates an activity of the digestive fluids and tones up the entire tract. Blood is
pure when digestion is complete. Dr. Taber's Pepsin Compound produces
perfect, healthy digestion. 9
TABLETS, 10c, 25c, 50c. at drug stores. Uquld Form, 50c. and $1.
KTKZPMTK? To prove its merits, we will send sample
m mmwtmmm package by mail. Free, to any address.
DR. TABER MFG. CO., Poorto, Ills.
ing or bouncing the ball.
The rule that in a dribble both hands
shall not be used simultaneously more
than once is still effective. Under rule
11, section 17, a man is not out of
bounds if only one foot is outside.
Players may be changed at any time
during the game (new rule 1, section
26). Last year's rules as well as the
new rules authorizes the referee to
award one point to the man fouled by
an opponent while trying for goal.
There was some doubt formerly as to
whether the team whose player was
fouled should also have a free throw
for goal.
The uew rules add that "this shall
noi interfere with a free throw for goal
from foul line," thus making It pos
sible to secure four points on this olio
play, if while being fouled the player
throws the goal, two points are scored,
oue point is awarded by the nfere
aud the ilayer is allowed an additional
free throw for the foul giving him uu
opiiortunity of scoring one point moro
if he throws the foul goal.
Under the old rules if a player threw
for goal from outside and missed thu
basket the ball went to the center,
while under the new rules the ball con
tinues to play. r
Under rule 12, section 1 and 4. tho
referee is required to promptly dis
qualify any player using profane or
abusive language.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble&st=text&r=-0.198,-0.266,1.395,1.395,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOO MANY fOijl Fo1ftjj l
IN BASKET BASKETPresent 1 1Present
Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
l
BY ELWOOD S
BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
r
bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
etEd ujxi np
entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
cs
ginger s and In i inn
general Generl makes the thean ui uin
an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
rather than good team work l lluther
luther tem a aacular
tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
I Iblame
or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
fou
opponents opponent much more than is nee
Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
are called caled for holding tripping A
tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
fnc
offenses but tepresnt preSfnt ytm o t
ing i ng a foul on someone somenp Eo V er TV tini tinimen tn
men i touch each other evry fr tltneTj Hme tln
moves an Inch and Vnn l
every timf time timearm 1m 1marm m marm
arm arm gets part way around an uppcEeni I
dead ded wrong and Is spoiling spiing th UPJt gas ga b
gl
loge lee rules rule permit permi a great deal more f
teal moe
dom of play pIn than do the A A f TL TLto i aD
The college dribble rule
colege permitting a
to throw the ball In the th pritn air or roll k i I t tthe
the floor take ta1t any number numbfr of steps stei rol t
catch it and try for or a baskft bkft i i is isone steP M I f JM1 JM1one
one The A A I r rules rul s make it a I dl
for a man to take more than two tw i vl t i
in a dribble In regard resrd t to the therule pror
rule rle a man running at full ful speed p us r rnecessarily l lnecessariy
necessarily necessariy take an extra step spe or orand uj i1 r rand
and his momentum usually usual bring brjn brjnar bringsarm jjr
arm ar in contact contct with wih his opponent L P Pspite
spite of the fact fac that tht the opponet rules rule saylL sy say
lowance Jownce shall shal be made md for a man mancatches r rcatches
catches the ball while whie on the run ru runare f fare Etj Etjcatches e eare
are invariably called caUe If a man eve evemuch t evemuch r
much as takes a small smal extra step stepCauses 1 1much t t tt tCauses
Causes Many Fouls FoulsAnother fra fraAnother
Ie IeAnother
Another rule that causes cU trouble Sa is Iiwhich SMJ bb bbhic
1i
which hic says sas putting puthI one ant or both bothabout i1 if ifthis
about an opponent cnsttutes constitutes arc arcThe a 1
The strIct Interpretton interpretation now OW applir i
apPl
this rule Ie causes c es more fouls tojle tojlew to be bethan bethan
than other and th the
any makfS g gslow 1 1s10w
slow w and uninteresting uninteretng M Mhave Many Tfn rnet g
have been suggested suggeste by different diftrfnt b bbal bat DSL
ball bal authorities authortes and there therp is i no douWt5 doub dOUbfethat
that the next rule book bok will wi show showeffect how howffcct T1 T1effect
effect of this agitation agItaton Manager Managtr OTT OTTT O T
the Crescents suggests that in ordf ordfsave orrf orrfsave r t
save time and in order to maka the post postwon por porwon
won on fouls a less los Important Imprtant fartc fartcdeciding faC faetrdeciding p
deciding a game that a man fouled fouledhe fou1e fouledtry
tr try a tree throw ge from tht the spot on w whe t the
he was fouled arguing arging that there therebe w i I Iplayer f
be no running to a certain lne line th tbx tbxplayer tU
player would have less chance to toa ri ria 1
a free throw that the throws wouW wouWquently woWdquently
wou
quently quenty be long ones one and that this thiswould ts tswould thuwould
would lend a spectacular clement Clement ta tagame Iigame
J
game I do not favor this rule rule bK bKwhen 1wJ b bwhen
when a guard gard was fouled foulEd under IB IBponents b bi bironents
ponents onen1s basket he would ould bfi so far is isMs t this
Ms hI own basket that a successful succesful tt ttwould t ttiitz ttiitzwould 2
would be almost impossible Impslblp an4 an4would ad an anwould f3i 1 1would
would encourage forwards forwads to foul foulguards fou f fguards
guards with impunity impunityNeutral impunityNeutral impunityNeutral
Neutral Men for Officials OfclS OfficMlsThe I IThe
The Canadians Cnadians have a system irtkj irtkjsatisfactory wt0 wt0satisfactory b
satisfactory satsfactory providing the officials officialsneutral oWc iU iUneutral
neutral which is not very ver of ofen often tenths te the OH OHIn t tt ttIn
In Canada the instant a man is A Athe t iit iitthe 1
the referee blows his wnistlP wnlst tM tMkeeper t tI t tkeeper
keeper awards one point to tho oifesei oifeseiteam oKftteam
team and without further delay dela on tb t w wIs Jt JtIs t tis
Is thrown up between the te two B Ilt10opponents i iopponents ot
opponents and the game gae goes on onscheme on onscheme o oscheme
scheme would ould be good with absoBM absoBMneutral abot abotneutrl abeOneutral
neutral neutrl officials oftclals but under this systts systtsan z syltean et
an official was the uner least l ot bit bi partial partialcould partiatlo partiatlocould
to pUO pUOcould
could swing a a close game either vrtft vrtftI m s1lth s1lthI ti
swng
I favor a rule which gmo provides that thatneutral trhp trhpevery thaJb thaJbevery
every match game the oficia officials sh S1ItdS S1ItdSneutral Uls Ulsneutral
neutral men and gme shall sQl be speciflcaDrs speciflcaDrsstructed speccUS specIflcaU3tructed f
structed to use their judgment judget as aswhether 8 83whether
whether or not the foul was wa wasintentIonally comm cr t tintentionally d T TIntentionnlv
intentionally Intentionnlv This I think tink would wuld wouldthe 5T 5Tthe rthe
Tl
the situation sltuat n The T1e trouble doesnt doet doesntmuch t tmuch 1 n nmuch
much in tho rules themselves themselvCB nUb alt nUbsome r rsome 11 11some
some of them th m are too tight tght bat ba in I1ttl I1ttlpresent 11 11present t tt ttpresent
present close interpretation Interpretaton and a andgeneral it itgeneral r rgeneral
general rule rlo cose was a inserted allowing aUowmgclals e eCJUIS Ccials
clals CJUIS a a ltte little 11LUW more 1UUIO use not u of thfir their fcii ii iiment own 3 3ment
ment and providing always that OW tHJi tHJiabsolutely thtf thtfabsolutely
absolutely h neutral neutrl men the game gamebe TT TTwithout
absolut be greaty greatly ben bencfited fited I It Is impos imposplay 1mposshb 1mposshbplay go r
play a gae game as fast a as bket baskethd1 baskethd1In
in such 3 a Umled limited space 2f as 0 a gn gnwithout gynin gyninwithout
without having scores score of foulsfinato1 foulsfinato1der touls mflI mflIder
der the strict stict interpretation Interretion of mht tha thaUUl t a abut r r rbut
officials would refrain fm fromIng
but UUl 11 It uUbiaio oficials refrn w III 1 1Ing
ing fouls which in iio io o way IirJurtv IirJurtvchances h1u in1urO in1urOchances
chances for either team tem for scoriTig Bcong Bcongwould scofl8would w5 w5would
would bo dono to elmnate eliminate toul troubl</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1908-12-06/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Strategy&r=-0.02%2C0.466%2C0.631%2C0.336%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket Bail JBailStrategy Baili all allStrategy
i Strategy StrategyBy
i
By DR DRJMiES JAMES NAISMITH NAISMITHFather
Father of the Game GameCopyright GameICoprlght190S Gameicopyright
Copyright ICoprlght190S 190S bi Joseoh B IL Bowles1NEW Bowles Bowles1NEW
1 1NEW NEW ELEMENT S IN THE GAME
I was AI ar forded rded the honor of ofth ofth ofng
t
th game of basketball ba ketbal1 some somears somen somerar5 me mering
n ng
elements elementsicn
many new
ring ago
were remotest in my m mind mindno mindowr
y ten icn
owr nr into no the winter pastime PMtUnea
g field ld for effort If IfJtassarhusetts ItfrIends IfE Ifyllass
new ne
CD a
E Jtassarhusetts yllass yllassa rice friends t then had told toldien toldhe
hen he that a quarter of o a a century centuryatuetes centurati1etes centurye
atuetes would be planning planningand er erlt eft e
lt t manners of attack and on defense defenseconceiving defenseonceiV se seconceiving
conceiving onceiV ng schemes schemes of play lay to toHer toIder
Her and hoodwink opponents I Ihave It
d t have doubted but such suchcome events eventst eventscom
t come com to pass Year by year ear the theor
or for plays of new variety Is Isbring IslIng
bring stronger and the thee mortel more In Ine InIe
Ie e the better liked d by b coaches coachesI
I have pet et about aboutes to tell you youPS youhave
PS S fans and players alike alikee alll lr lrt
e f t center your our efforts how to tost tot tost
st t your plays to the best ad adage adedurlng ads
age during s the progress of plan plays playswhere plaRwhen
where to direct your our attack attackscience in ingame 10J1me
game where strategy and science scienceUidoing scienceJwiClln se sei
Uidoing i themselves themselvesthe thEmS lves lvesthe
the spectator tator who watches basketplay basket basketplay basketpIa
play pIa for the privilege of Indulging Indulgingcsasies Indulgingrstasles Indulgingrstasies
csasies over the wild movements movementsermoving movementsermoln movementsermoving
ermoving legs arms and Indoor Indoored
ed muscles the science n of f abth the theie th the e ee
ie e oustltutes itself in scoring sco scoarcuracy 1e leather leatherre abil abilarcuracy abllaNuracy
arcuracy In lodging the leather leatherre
re within the net nete
e Till 111 endeavor to demonstrate demonstrater
r t c science of this game gameability lies in inutility inabIJit
utility abIJit o M th tho guards forwards ana anaer
er to nork up to a highly em emit effipdnt e epclnt
it pcnt m the movementsede movements which whichIe
tde Ie the hl efforts at goals goalsese
ese irtKlfs lrt df les on Basketball Strat Strattherefore Stratthenfore Strattherefore
therefore will deal eal with the thea
a of the players about the floor floorsslng fioorsslng floorasing
sslng of the ball and the most mostre mostt7e mosttse
re manner of puzzling oppo oppoby oppoby oppuby
by a series of plays To start starttake starts
as s take the play which has has2e ha hae
2e e known as left forward to toforward toforwar toforward
forward In left forwards posl postof poslOf poslOf
Of course your our team must musta
a set of signals which are easily easilyed ea l1y l1yl
ed l They may be number signals signalsed
ed to the players by b the captain captainhe
he 11 e team or they the may ma be silentq silent silentjr
jr q In the rase tEl of number slg s1gtie slgtlie sl slthe
the same course Is I pursued as asused asused II IIUed
used In football For Instance Instancethe
the accompanying diagram Sup Supthat Supthat Supthat
that the series of numbers whlcn whlcnthe whlcnthe whichthe
the direction of the play Is the thed
d ottered by b your our captain Tour Touril
il I for the play pia left forward to toforward tof toforward
forward f in left forwards pos poswould poslwould post postwould
would be b 26 312 88 The cen cennamber cennumber cennumber
number being 3 the ball leaves leavesto leaveto
to go to the left forward whose whosen
n rat Is I while the last player to tove tovs
ve 1 the ball before the shot at the theIs
Is attempted Is the right forwardla forward
la o a2 a2ou 2
roJ ou may rea use us a movement of the thec th thc
c foot to Indicate n w certain play playnrtr pia playthe
nrtr 1 the th man who gives the 81 stdgnil e elsnal 81R1
lsnal R1 1 must give It unconcernedly unconcernedlyat
at It t nay 113 not be noted by b op oprts opt oprtt
rts rtt t and arc Dr made use u e of to advantage advantage1s
aftl aftlIs aftela
1s e placing of players imme immefly
fly 11 after the completion of the theKbJh thehl1 thevLh
KbJh proves especially effective effectiveIts
Its h accompanying diagram the theare theare theare
are idle Idl If the center of the therepresented tllorepresented therepresented
represented as the aggressor aggressortie o
tie t e jump on his opponent and ands
it t s the ball in the direction hull indiby Indlb hullby
by b the captains signal In this thishft thishe thisthe
the centef slaps the sphere to toeft toeft toe
e eft t Fide where the th left forward forwardes
jves es It and shoots It back to the theforward thefonard theforward
forward who ho In the mean meanhas meanhas meanhas
has taken up a position to the theff ther
ff r the basket from which he tries trlesn triesgoal
goal goaln 011
n 1 the truly tml scientific part of the theimation theinaUon theination
imation takes place The center centerJumping centerjumping
Jumping spurts for a position to togh
IgM gh side of the basket while the theoarl1 theorward
forward having handled the ball balla ballthe ballthe
a the goal tosser secured it iti it itI
i a bee line for a point directly directlysnt directl directlJnt
ant of the basket basketstudying basketstudying basketstudying
studying the accompanying dta dtayou dla1Cu dtayou
you can readily see what an ex exit
it t defense f this makes providing provldlnrlg
right rlg t forward falls In his hi effort effortii
ii the ball within the net You Toucovered YouQered YouCowered
covered every point toward which whichaU
HI uay bound as it caroms away awa
the goal It Is then up to your OU
to 0 leap into the air and again at atR atn
n R goal go L it is a noticeable fea feajjnat
jjnat that in this or any an other play for for2rertne forltter
2rertne ltter the plan Is for every ee play p1nrlose
lose his opponent and to do 110
mast aromplish a ompllsh his part partof of the thein
Ina inatlon J2A0rn Ion from a point T lnt otl other er than
in n which
he places himself at the
m the referee to tosses les es the sphere
the centers at the start of theId the thepostnjr held
ld tie e OPposing oPPOsi postnjr renter leap Into Intothan
higher than your our center thus thust t11UI t11Uthe
g the ball
toward the opponents opponrntst opponrntsItmalnl s
I it
t t mains ln for y your our ur guards flrtls to toi tosphere toSphE
the
i sphere SphE IE and follow out Ute UteI UteslgnajEd tlioEvery
as slgnajEd
Every move must mustId
I e VitI itJi the
utmost
celerity elerlt The
Id to revive rl rerelve hE the ball from the theBtinrt
Btinrt must takE ke It on n the run and the
I under thn
basket should do the theSll00t
aid shoot hoot for the goal ool before beforer b rOrp
r cress n L 1 baR R st stopped PPed and the pnr pnru pnrth pl1redgunrd i w
edgunrd guan of th the opposing team teamte
ed Wm to u
te block his hl s pass passBm past pasdiagram ar arthe s
t diagram Bm to the thear richt isthe Is Isthhe s stje
thhe the play pla ay reversed rever red that isthri Is IsIn
In thri the e right ght forward orw to left for
right gri
forwards poMtlop poMtlopcoverlnsr JJn tlo The
1es naes for covering th the bound of
i 1
following a nol THMwlbl tfbl faUiirc falllJTII
Pan pa of the
I jroalshootine for fornbseri
ree also Iso nbseri obsenet the th poMMon M c Hons of ofthe q qI qmEn
mEn used beln r l
I erte er erWI
tinat WI Jt hive f Cn cousidemi ld th the
w nho
wa srn rt the first trijght to
t at a t the t r
nt opening enln of each fac lCll CPaco RSn RSni RSnPnrnnr t
i nraTnr to ail 11 M 1 the ther pinvrr I ht
InS n
r J1ni s sfrr l11r
for a tMII rritePln Uln
ba bai 111 thr fIt T 1 e a ctrrs 111 e t1
career a TPer ends wi retn t th tht
eaylslte alslt alsltI p anti thlO
I IAltnot 11 n oy
n and 1In other I tl
1P1 manner thsn th n ht
i se nO for 1r
I L v pehns h nII 1Itt1 t u uon ts
r11tt It I
lefro Pcr H
Trio mstrlt t11 t11bap qm qmwind
bap wind n hsnt 1 env tI NJul NJulII r
season aon on onaccp t tra
bar coact
II an 1 1p 1fn n
season fn is I t
p ha5kethol thU thUntlnT1 1
ParHrlpntlnn ntlnT1 t
r en t tu
al alt6 aids In
n pot
t6 hr at t1 r
Tl d
t rsieal si a 1 rott en ait v h hn t ti rl
rhhh l hI
1 i npCIo t t to toar hr hro n
o I mAnn of t tIftlatJ
ar T t n
IftlatJ rOI11 onr plA plAaCCount
accp aCCount nt for this by b de
daring Iarin that different lffer nt sports bring dif different dtferent dlfferent
ferent sets of muscles into play pll and inconsequence In Inconsequence Inconsequenco
consequence the start of the basket
ball season finds some parts of th thplayers tile tlieplayers tilepl1ers e
players machinery maclilne weakened lay bymonths laymonths b bmonths
months of Inactivity But basketball basketballuses
uses every 6VC1 muscle of the body bod anrt anrtthat anr1that an anthat
that continuously Hence the lunsjc lunsjcand lunljand lunyand
and heart have a heavier hea Ier part to play plaIn piain k t
In purifying the blood and building up uii uiithese tr trthese
these unused muscles AX s soon u uthe aM aMthe uthe
the athlete ath etc begins to get into basket basketball baskctball basketball
ball trim these muscles are strengthened strength strengthened strengthened
ened he breathes easier when dashln dashingabout dashlnabout dashlnabout h
about the basketball floor and con constant constant constant
stant exercise puts him In shape for forhard u uhard ahard
hard season seasonThe seasonThe ea80nThe
The basketball player also needs needsa 5
a stomach which is not susceptible susceptibleto
to hard Jolts That Is a xequisttwhich requisite requisitewhich requisitewhich e
which cannot be neglected If the play player pla plaor
or intends to put forth his best ener energies ln s sgies r rgles
gies Sweet stuffs coffee alcoholic alcoholicbeverages alcol101lcbevcrages alcohollbeverages c
beverages tobacco pastry I1ast and late latehours latehours lathours e
hours must necessarily be blacklisted blacklistedAlo
Also before practice and games the theathlete theathlete th thathlete
athlete should eat lightly and of food foodswhich foodwhkh foodwhisk
which contain the largest I amount o onourishment or ornourishment ornourishment f
nourishment In the smallest buk bukIn bukIn bulkIn
In future articles we shall outline outlinemore outlinemore outlinmore P
more plays which arc absolutely es essential e eentinJ ersentiaL
sential and when len these are Impressed Impressedwill impressewill
will add what coaches recognize rcc gnlze a afeature ni nifeature aifeature
feature plays that is combinations combinationsout 5
out of the ordinary run which added addedto add lt ltto t tto
to the repertoire of teams Rive a va varied vavied n nrled
vied and complicated style of attacand attack attackand attackand k
and defense</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1913-11-30/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Basket-ball+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Code+Amended+Sport+Game+Intercollegiate&st=text&r=0.219,0.33,0.279,0.297,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET-BALL
Dr. Sharp e Takes Side of
Player at Intercollegiate
Meeting.
LEAVE OUT ROUGHNESS
Too Many Tecnnicsfities It Claim of
Coaches and Players New
Role Affects Centers.
New York, Nov. 29. Exception to the
trend of collegiate Icglsla ion was voiced
In no uncertain terms at the annual inter
pretation .neetlng of the Intercollegiate
basket-ball rules committee at the Hotel
Astor yesterday afternoon Dr. A. II.
Sharpe, coach of the Cornell football,
basket-ball, and baseball teams, took the
side cf the plajer and coach against the
rules committee, which, he said, was con
cerning itself more with ruling on tech
nicalities than on the practical issues of
the game.
The discussion arose when Dr. Joseph
E. Ray croft chairman of the rules com
mittee, and the presiding officer, called
for the consideration of Rule 11, which Is
designed to penalize blocking. The rule
had been amended over summer so that it
read: "A player is entitled to take any
position on the court but if in taking a
position he faces an opponent or makes
bodily contact with an opponent so as to
interfere with the latter's progress he
Is blocking."
Dr. Raycrott said that the change had
been made In the rule 'as part of the
general plan of the rulemakers to elim
inate all unnecessary roughness and com
pel the plajers to "play the ball and not
the man." By this rule, said Dr. Ray
croft all Illegal Interference with a play
er by his opponent resulting from the
close guarding of pla, would be deemed
a foul and penalized as such.
Dr. Sharpe carried his point because.
when the discussion had been concluded
and a vote taken on the Interpretation of
the rule Dr. It ay croft and Ralph Mor
gan, of the University of Pennsylvania,
secretary of the committee, agreed to
permit an editorial correction which sub
stituted an "and" for the "or" in the
rule in question, making it mean that
only by direct bodily contact can a player
block his opponent
The most important changes In the rules
forthe coming year have to do with the
"Jump" ball and the ball when It goes
out of bounds. In order to eliminate the
fouling that so frequently happened under
the old Jump rule, the players Jumping
for the ball now, either In the center or
on any part of the floor will have to
Jump with one hands behind the back.
The meeting ruled that b behind the
back was meant behind any part V the
back below the shoulder, with the hand
touchihg the back, rather than the strict
working of the section, which compelled
the player to have on hand behind the
back at the waistline.
The other rule regarding the Jump ball
was aimed to do away with a great many
of the "Jumps" along the sideline after
the ball has been out of bounds by giv
ing it to the opponent of the man last
touched by It The rules relating to
dribbling were also discussed, but no rul
ing was made.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1930-12-28/ed-1/?sp=6&q=basketball&r=0.095%2C0.51%2C0.774%2C0.412%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> BASKETBALL
_ PlAVS^ PLAYLPS
Fine Gyms Make Basketball Second Only To
Football In Popularity
BY EVERETT S. DEAN
Basketball ('each. Indiana l'.
Basketball is recognized in most
of the country as the second major
sport. Its progress has come about
solely on its merits. Proximity of
the crowd to the players lias made
it possible for the crowd to experi
ence thrills which go with speedy
action more than in any other
j sport.
Pine gymnasiums and field houses
in many states are real testimony
I to the popularity of basketball. De
mand for seating space has led
larger towns to build gymnasiums
With seating capacities of 4000 to
5000. F.ne field houses with seat
1 ing capacity from 8000 to 15.000
have been built to meet the college
demand. Outstanding basketball
plants of the country are the
I Palestra at the University of
Pennsylvania, and most of the field
houses of Big Ten schools. The
Indiana State High School Basket
ball Tournament is played each
i year before 20.000 fans and offers
a great spectacle to sportdom.
Schedule making and tournament
f play in high shools have been
regulated by state athletic asso
ciations to the extent that high
school basketball is on a sounder
basis than ever before. Schedules
once consisted of 35 games, which
were too many for the high school
boy. In some states 18 to 20 games
now make up the schedules. The
strain of long tournaments has
been avoided by spreading tourn
aments over a period of three weeks
j instead of two.

Uniform officiating is another
sign indicating progress. Officiating
I
North, South
Elevens Will
Meet Sunday

NEW YORK. Dec. 27â€” Dâ€” The
latest football game on record for
j an eastern field is scheduled to
be played tomorrow when all star
teams from the north and south
1 clash for the benefit of charity.
After many vicissitudes. Jack
McBride and Stumpy Thomason of
the Brooklyn Dodgers professional
team, former luminaries from
Syracuse and Georgia Tech res
pectively, have carried their plans
through to the point where their
teams are all assembled and a
waiting the kickoff at Ebbetts
Field tomorrow afternoon.
The question of just what charity
is to benefit has been in doubt
ever since the Knights of Colum
bus. original sponsors of the game
withdrew, but it is certain there
will be some beneficiary.
Chinese are taking a fanev to
hard candy, which is sold at the rate
of six large sticks for a cent.
Mrs M Swaine. Australian oldest1
colonist, died recently at Adelaide
at the age of 10&. 1
is on a higher plane now than ever
before. Basketball is the hardest
game of all to officiate for officials
have helped to standardize offi
ciating.
Basketball has gone through dif
ferent evolutionary stages and with
each succeeding one the game is
becoming more scientific.
Few people are aware of how
universally the game Is played.
During the last few' weeks I have
received requests for basketball
lessons from the following coun
tries: Alaska. Porto Rico. Mexico.
Guam, and France Our service
teams have no doubt been the
greatest medium of spreading the
game.

Basketball is played In the fol-
lowing countries that we know of:
Alaska, Canadian Provinces, Hawaii.1
China. Japan. Porto Rico and oth
er South American countries, Cuba.
Panama. San Salvador. Spain.
Greece, Persia. Guam. England, j
France, Mexico and others.
In many of these countries the
game is played outside due mostly
to the warm climate. However,
playing facilities are increasing
with the popularity of the games
as manifested by an order received
from the Mexican government bv
the Nurre Plate Glass Company of
Bloomington. Ind., for four com
plete sets of glass bank boards.
Mexico sent a team to tour the
mid-west last year and it surprised
everyone with its ability.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2023271000/1944-09-22/ed-1/?sp=7&q=basketball&r=-0.292%2C0.134%2C1.281%2C0.682%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Specialists in Each
Barracks Plan
Fall Sports Program
k
Individual, Group Sports
Begin in Barracks;
Tourneys Planned
Complete Program of Fall and Winter Sports Planned for Enlisted Men
fan ana winter sports are being planned in a big way for
enlisted men on the Depot.
Under the leadership of Lt. (jg) Rov I. Carriker, recre
ation and welfare officer, and Lt. (jg) J. C. Hickey, officer
in charge of Naval Barracks recreation, a group of
and recreation specialists are working out the details
plan, which will provide recreational opportunities
fields.
athletic
for their
in many
Specialists Arrange
Nine Tournaments, 12
Other Activities Begin
Athletic specialists and recrea
tional directors in the various bar
racks are organizing tournaments
in nine different activities.
They are bowling, pocket bil
liards, touch football, horseshoes,
table tennis, volley ball, shuffle
board, badminton and boxing.
Barracks and Depot champions
will be decided through these
tournaments, and awards will be
given to the winners.
Refinishing of the gym floor in
the temporary recreation building
is the only thing holding up the
starting of 12 activities to be held
there.
Through instructions by athletic
specialists, the following activities
will begin:
Basketball, badminton, volley
ball, shuffleboard, tumbling, box
ing, bat ball, wrestling, combative
judo, weight lifting, table tennis
and calisthenics.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1916-02-27/ed-1/?sp=15&q=basketball&st=text&r=-0.294,-0.23,1.172,1.172,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKETBALL NOW
ONE OF AMERICAâ€™S
FAVORITE INDOOR
WINTER PASTIMES
Growth of Game in Alabama
and the South Has Kept
Stride Set by Eastern and
Northern States
AVERAGE OF FIFTY
TEAMS PRODUCED
IN VARIOUS STATES
Over 100 Teams Now Play
ing Under Organized
Heads as Compared With
Ten in 1906
My FRED BODEKER
The remarkable popularity of bas
ketball during the past 10 years has
elevated the game to the position of
one of the foremast in American sports.
The past decade has witnessed a seem
ingly impossible growth In the basket
game and even experts are puzzled over
the problem.
Basketball has proven itself to be
one of the best sports in every way
that help the American people to
amuse themselvefe in,the gymnasium.
Basketball makes no uncertain de
mands on heart and lungs and on en
durance generally. Basketball is a
game. Thatâ€™s allâ€”only a game. It is
not a combat nor a battle nor a fight*
as some people would term it. It is
just a game.
Authorities have often repeated the
statement that basketball does more
to form a man's character than any
other sport. The period of adolescence
is the time when basketball and sim
ilar games are played and when lifeâ€™s
habits are formed and the character
largely determined. Politics is a game
and so is almost any business, and the
people are merely players in the game.
And so is basketballâ€”it is a game and
one of the best.
DEVELOPS THE BODY
Basketball develops many parts of
the human body. It develops alertness,
gelt-control, skill, speed and brings ev
ery part of the body into action. The
game arouses the interest and enthu
siasm of every spectator. The simplic
ity and small quantity of apparatus
required, together with other chief
qualifications of the game, make it
one of the most valuable of our com
petitive games.
Basketball belongs to the large fam-
ily of games originated to amuse the
American public. It was first started
in 1891. Dr. James A. Naismtth, now
a member of the collegiate basketball
rules committee, was an instructor at
the Springfield Y. M. C. A. Training
school and undertook to devise an in
door game which would develop man
kind. Basketball was at first very sim
ple. Since then, however, the game has
undergone complete revision; but bas
ketball lovers all over the nation owe
to Dr. Naismith the honor of â€œinvent
ingâ€™â€™ the game.
Since 1891 basketball has made mar
velous strides. The game was adopted
by colleges, high schools, athletic as
sociations in all parts of the country.
The big eastern colleges first fell in
line and soon the movement spread to
the south. Beading southern colleges
and institutions quickly adopted the
game and by 1900 basketball was a
game that was beginning to be played
by all important institutions.
GROWTH IN 1906
In 1906 the game began to grow even
more popular. Athletic clubs in all parts
of the south were producing teams and
tights were being staged for the
â€¢'championships.â€ Not only in the south
was the game popular, but the middle
west and the eastern states were far
ahead. It Is roughly estimated that
something over an average of 60 teams
were being produced in every state in
the union or over 2400 teams were
playing organized basketball to say
nothing of the innumerable grammar
schools and independent teams that
numbered as many more.
But basketball did not stop its won
derful growth. The game has some un
seen power that attracted clubs, col
leges and schools to adopt it. As the
years passed the number playing the
game increased and by 1910 the num
ber playing in 1906. which was es
timated to have been over 240Â°, was
estimated to have been doubled, or
nearly 3000 teams. This does not
elude independent teams but omy
teams as high schools, athletic clubs,
colleges and other educational institu
tion
Dr. Joseph E. Raycroft. chairman of
he joint committee on basketball
ules. is quoted as saying that the
umber of teams playing basketball
I 1910 was over 7000. This, however,
considered by many to be too large,
onsidering that six men 5s ine aver
ge number of players on one team,
ver 42,000 men were playing in or
anlzed basketball in 1910.
In Alabama in 1906, the number of
tarns playing basketball was something
he 10 or less, which Included the Bir
slngham Athletic club, Birmingham
Ugh school, Mobile, Montgomery, and a
ew others. The effects of the growth
ver the nation took effect in Alabama
nd the number in 1910 jumped to nearly
3 teams. A few hight schools were
laying the game, being seriously handt
apped by the lack of an Indoor court,
phile almost every athletic club and
M. C. A. in the state was represented
y a team.
OVER 100 TEAMS
In 1*16, the beginning of the present
eason, which Is about to come to a very
uccessful close, the number playing in
his state Jumped to over 100. Over 60
igh schools are playing basketball, with
ImoBt 40 athletic clubs and other instl
utions of this kind. The game is played
y every grammar school In the larger
itles of the state, while countless teams,
.norganlzed as in the Y. M. C. A., and
lass teams of various educational ln
tltutions, are following the same exam
Not only in Alabama but in all parts
>t the country Is the game making
apld strides toward the top of the lad
ler as an indoor sport. The number
paying In the United States at the
n-esent is estimated to go over 23,000
earns, which means that about 156,600
leople are playing organized basketball
X this number Alabama can boast of
Jmoat 700 players, which, although be
nw a majority of the statee, is well in
he advanced list.
Add so it can be seen, Alabama with
ractically every other state in the' union
fast taking to basketball, and expert
rltlcs who have watched Its growth for
he past decade predict no decline In
ts power to attract the attention of
he apart loving publle.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062224/1957-12-27/ed-1/?sp=5&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.211,0.051,0.254,0.271,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Caesar Rodney School
News
Caesar Rodney School Calendar
â€”January, February and March.
Christmas vacation until January
2
Reminder: Friday, December 27,
Glee Club Dance, 8:00-11:30. Harry
Jarman's Orchestra. Semi-formal,
alumni, students, friends, guestsâ€”
90c stag, $1.50 per couple.
January
Thursday, January 2â€”8 p. m.â€”
Program as planned for December.
Sixth grade parents will serve re
freshments.
Saturday, January 4â€”8 p. m.â€”
Sophomore record dance.
Monday, January 6:9 a. m.â€”As
sembly for grades 4-5-6, "A Jour
ney Into the Forest;" 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) election
of officers and plans for the 10th
Annual Winter Band Concert.
Tuesday, January 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls at Milford; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys vs. Milford at
C. R.; 2:50 p. m.â€”High School As
sembly, "Science Barriers."
Thursday, January 9: 4-H Ban
quet in cafeteria.
Friday, January 10: 3:45 p. m.â€”
Basketball, Jr. H. S. vs. Felton at
C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
girls at Felton.
Tuesday, January 14â€”3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Laurel at
C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at Smyrna.
Friday, January 17â€”Six weeks
marking period endsâ€”report cards
due Friday, January 24; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Sud
lersville at C. R.
Tuesday, January 21: 3 p. m.â€”
Basketball. J. C. boys at Felton; 7
p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and girls
vs. Felton at C. R.
Friday, January 24: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Fel
ton at C. R..
Tuesday, January 28: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Mid
dletown at C. R.
Friday, January 31; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Smyr
na at C. R.
February
Monday, February 3: 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) in high
school office; Industrial Arts din
ner in cafeteria.
Wednesday, February 5; 8 p. m.
â€”Tenth Annual Winter Band Con
certâ€”students 50c; adults, 75c;
family, $1.00.
Thursday, February 6: 8 p. m.â€”
PTA.
Friday, February 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls and J. V. at Sea
ford; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at St. Andrews.
Monday, February 10â€”1:30 p. m.
â€”Kent County Student Council at
C. R.
Tuesday, February 11: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls at Mid
dletown.
Wednesday, February 12: 3 p. m.
â€”Assembly, for grades 5 and 6,
band concert.
Friday, February 14: 3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Harrington.
Saturday, February 15: 7:30 p. m.
â€”7-1 and 7-2 boys in cafeteria.
Tuesday, February 18: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls and J. V. vs.
Seaford at C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basket
ball, boys and J. V. at Laurel.
Friday, February 21: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Harrington
at C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys
and J. V. at Sudlersville.
Tuesday, February 25â€”3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Laurel; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys and J. V. vs.
St. Andrews at C. R.: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys at Milford; Six
Weeks Marking Period Endsâ€”Re
port cards due March 10.
March
Monday, March S: 8 p. m.â€” B. P.
c.
Tuesday, March 4: 7 p. m.â€”Bas
ketball, boys at Milford.
Wednesday, March 5; 12:45 p. m.
â€”Assembly for grades 5 and 6.
Thursday, March 6: 8 p. m.â€”PTA.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066314/1917-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.352,0.548,0.207,0.221,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TITLE IN BASKETBALL
Kansas City Team Defeats
Warrensburg in Final
Game, 62 to 27.
FAYETTE ENDS THIRD
HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL CHAMPIONS
Singer Is Individual Star
.With 24 Points Wil
liams Makes 20.
Kansas City Central .High School
won the state high school basketball
tournament by defeating Warrensburg
62 to 27, at the Rothwell Gymnasium
court last night This is Central's
third season without a defeat. Singer.
the Blue and White star forward, took
the ball after three seconds of play
and scored, the first field goal. Central
was never headed, but the game was
harder fought than the score indi
cates. The Kansas City team was easily
the superior of any of the other eight
teams and their victory was foretold
by basketball followers when they
were first seen in action. Singer was
the highest individual point scorer in
last night's game, with 24 points to
his credit, though Williams with 20
and Duvall with 14 pushed him hard
for the honor. Giltner, the Warrens
burg captain, tossed the ball through
the ring for 19 tallies. Dorland was
the only other Warrensburg man to
break into the scoring, making the
other 8 points. The score:
enirai etc; Warrenslmrs (27)
m 3lHIBIE&Vfl9Ki afllBBH
'GET BASKETBALL LETTERS
Committee oh Intercollegiate Athlet
ics Makes Awards.
The Committee on Intercollegiate
Athletics have recommended the
following men for basketball Ms:
Captain Fred Williams, Sam Shlrkey,
Harry Viner, C. H. Slusher, Kenneth
Shenard. P. B. Vogt and Jesse L.
Campbell.
The election of Jesse L. Campbell
as captain of next year's basketball
squad was approved. It was decided
to try and arrange a track meet with
Leland Stanford University, and, if
possible, to bring the meet to Colum
bia. The baseball eligibility list was
approved with the exception of four
men who were voted ineligible. Mr.
Brewer feels that these men, while
ineligible now, can later be placed in
the list of eligibles"
CAPITOL FIXTURE FUND GIYEN
faeMS U Be Use aj CeiurissteB
Bear for Seleetfeas.
E. w. Stephens, chairman of the
State Capitol Commission Board, says
that the Board has another big problem
before It In the baying of furniture
and fixtures for the new capital. The
legislature has voted an appropriation
of 300,000 for that purpose, but states
that selections must be made by mem-
bers of the board and not by
tenor decorator or advisor.
Fam Machiaery Class Tries Tntf
The farm machinery class was g
en some experience in plowing Tesfej
day when Prof. E. W. Lehmana'tiiJtC
out one of the University tractors f"
the field west of the poultry grwaay';.
Each man was permitted to handle'tfct
tractor and gang plows by Mmtrctc,
Five acres were plowed by the
dents.
Plant peonies and Iris now.
bia Floral Co., phone 920.
Colum-C-179
FREE
Development of
Films purchased
Tn&Kri Sfore
all
at
Top Row, Left to Bight: Coach C. CHornaday; Williams, Center;. Coach
J. -U. Young. Bottom Row: DuTal, Bight Forward; Sanders, Left Guard;
Singer, Left Forward and Bamsar, Right Guard, Who Did Sot Make the
Trip to Columbia.
filth, Charleston;
Singer, If
Duval, rf
Williams, c
rg, Herm. Smith. Hankln
Webster Groves;
sixth, Sedalia.
Central will be awarded a large
bronze wall .placque and the other
teams smaller placques.
Kansas City Central and Warrens
burg qualified for the finals Satur
day morning by defeating Fayette
and Webster Groves, D scores of 51
to 7 and 24 to 14 respectively.
Charleston defeated Hannibal 2S to
Charleston at the hands of Warrens
imrg, 25 to 14. The work of Spencer
and Lincoln for Webster Groves In the
first conflict is worthy of mention,
their combined efforts netting 29 of the
35 tallies for the victors. Dorland
Hanna and Giltner starred for War
rensburg in the second game.
ALL-STATE TEAMS SELECTED
cTllerb. smith10 ln tne first consolation game played
j rf.nanna Saturday morning. Sedalia defeated
Uaskets from floor Sinrpr s Tin mi r I the Fairfax fivfl 27 in 14
"imams, ju, sanaers Dorland 4. Gilt-
Sanders, Is
isnrte. rg
ner 5. Baskets on free triali Sincer a
Giltner 9. Free trials misled Singer 4,
uiuuer i. x ouis called un Singer 3,
Duvall 3, Williams 2, Sanders 4. Burke 1,
Dorland 3, Hanna 3. Herb. Smith 2. Gilt
ner 2. Herm. Smith 3, Bankin 2.- Referee
Bryant (Missouri).
In the finals of the consolation se
ries Charleston defeated Sedalia IS
to 11. This placed Charleston in fifth
place and gave the cellar position to
Sedalia.
Third place was won by Fayette
who defeated Webster Groves, 20 to
7 in the most hotly contested game of
the series. The placing of the first
six team's in the series follows: First,
Kansas City Central; second, War
rensburg; third. Fayette; fourth.
The games Friday night brought
four learns to the semifinals in the se
ries. Kansas City Central had qual
ified for this round in the Friday aft
ernon games by defeating Fairfax In
a one-sided game, 50 to 11. Fayette1
also defeated Xeosha in the afternoon,
but was forced to beat the Sedalia five,
which had a bye in the first round,
before gding to the semifinals. This
was the last of the Friday night games.
These two teams were the leaders of
the Central District and fought a hard
game, 25 to 17.
The other games Friday night re
sulted in a victory forsWebster Groves
over Hannibal, 35 to 4, and a defeat of
3 Members of Victorious Central High
Team on First Squad.
The five officials of the state high
school basketball tournament, Fred
Williams. George Bryant and John F.
Miller, referees; Anton Stankowski,
scorekeeper; and Samuel Church.
timekeeper, have picked the following
all-state high school teams:
First Teas
Forward Singer, Central (captain)
Forward Dorland, Warrensburg.
Center Williams, Central.
Guard Sanders, Central.
Guard Giltner, Warrensburg.
Second Team
Forward Duval, Central (captain)
Forward Spencer, Webster Groves.
Center Skillman, Fayette.
Guard Burke, Central.
flnarA VTnrlo Wnhstor Clrrrrna T T
..u. W,V.J.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020422/1954-02-04/ed-1/?sp=9&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.192,0.483,0.176,0.188,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>SCHOOL
REPORTER


On Wednesday, January 20, af
ter two practices, the Smyrna
F. F. A. basketball teams met with
Caesar Rodney, Milford, Harring
ton and Felton teams at Caesar
Rodney for the first tournament of
the season. The tournament con
sisted of having three gamesâ€”two,
varsity and one J. V.â€”played at
the same time until eventually all j
were eliminated but one in each
division, Milford w i n n i ng the j
championship for both Varsity and
J. V. Smyrna's varsity was beaten!
F. F. A. Basketball

by Caesar Rodney. The Smyrna
J.V. played against Milford for theâ– 
final round. Refreshments were
served by the Caesar Rodney
Chapter.
February Calendar of Events
February 2, Basketball game at
home with Wilmington Friends, I
3:30.
February 3, Basketball game at
home with Chestertown, 7:00.
j
February 4, 1st Semester Report
Cards.
February 5, Basketball game at
home with Caesar Rodney, 7:00.
February 9, Personnel Club As
sembly 1:25.
February 9, Basketball game at
home with Harrington, 7:00.
February 11, P.T.A. meeting
high school cafeteria, 8:00.
February 12, Basketball game at
Dover, 7:00.
February 13, Kent County Queen
of Hearts Dance at Harrington
High School, 8:00.
February 16, Basketball game at
St. Andrews, 3:30.
February 19, Basketball game at
home with Middletown, 7:00.
February 22, Yearbook material
to be sent to publisher.
February 23, Basketball game at
Chestertown, 7:00.
February 26, Basketball game at
home with Milford, 7:00.
The Smyrna High School Eagles 1
basketball team will play its next
three games on the home c o u r t
which should prove advantageous
to the Red and White. The Eagles
Basketball
will play host to the Caesar Rod
ney team tomorrow night. In the*r
previous game the Riders beat the
Eagles by ten points, but Coach
Homey expects a reversal of form
on the home court.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>




  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

            <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>





  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
