<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport&st=text&r=0.137,0.75,0.143,0.152,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
>a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.
se metpractice is required to learn it and there
6, no incident roughness if the rules are
stictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr.
deyce is try to have other teams formed in the
symmasisme in the city and to have regular
entestn between them. It eomameade itself in
s it can be played in almost any sized room
den any had of lot. whether it be large or
mail, and that the number of player. need
only be limt. I b the size of the ground. It
bkings into play all maseles of the body. thus
being a healthy exercise, and at the same time
te a ws incidens to moet sports are want
1. The only apparatus neessary for the
oe to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball
mnd re half-bushel baskets.
movwr rT PL 6TD.
Theegh she courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Stan
aoprter witnessed a game of basket ball played
M the Carrer Institute on one of the evenings
of this week. The two baskets are attached to
th =anig strack at the opposite ends of the
gymmsam and U.s object of the game is to
Shen e heU in the opponent'e basket. The
uame consist of mine men each. made up of a
gaiheeper. two backs to assist him. a center, a
eight and left henter, two forward and a home
ma. They are arranged in this order from
Oe gnal whica they are defending. It is not
asessmry that the players thou!d remain in
teir glaces. but they should move in such a
way as to gie the forward player an oppo:
baesy Is gee a good tos at the goal or the
baecks to keep theer opponents from obtaining
so mmm by taking it from thea when they are
ghbntsto throw. It is the luty of the goal
ba~to beep the ball away fromi the vicinity.
etgoal. end it is more often neessary for
hi to bat the bail with his had tha for
e~er meambers of the seama to do so.
L. Serim. 3. leeward
4.ame.. eae...
4. Sm. .a.5
en.. ...s-....e.
The game is started by the teems lining up
ba their respseutve positions and then the
safeae tomes the ballian the air, It must not be
te.-d antal it strikes the ground. Thea the
players ean catch it. and the object of the one
who obtains it isto pass istso one of the players
ahis own sidec.who either passes itto inotherwho
msay be in a favorable position to tom f~ar goal
or else attempts to auake a goal himself. To
bee a foot bal into a basket euasiended ten feet
a cen SsA.av
beG airani eiasest lags en~t. held it.ie
net en eas messean means, end thee.
thanmy ethe at guat are madebut
as t ase -s eemtl, and e sensty
ohB~in meds. esnammty, an the
qshad esty. The haDeam be aoma
an ists with -n or beth --a-~
In bM the sesm s e 40 -a -e
e be h ss:
asmmmS he es h the det er hased
A e esms e with te hasb mUs
am thmm... ..a. a. he
Gotas o ben shile rmaI and Mas to stop
The har maw be held in ds baud The arms
Iee or bod soat not be used for blding it.
If h lb is beld for any length of time th
referee tess it into the air. as in the baegtnmg
of theam
o the5 ein, holding, J~n .trp, n
or striking b allowed. The t iafringem m
'f this rule eosnts a foal and a second dis
q"mli= a player, but, as in foot ball, a substi
tats may take his place.
IN TaN BAsKET. C
When a ball goes out of bounds it is put in
play in the same way as in a foot ball game.
The game consists of two halft of twenty
minutes each or such time as the captains may
decide on. and time is taken out for delays.
A goal counts three points and a foul one
point for the opponent. and a majority of the
points decides the game.
There are a referee and umpire, whose duties
are the same respectively as the same officials
in a foot ball game.
Any player has a right to get the ball at any
time while it is in the field of play. provided
that he handles only the ball and not the op
ponent.
ADVANTAGEs OF THE GAME.
To an observer the game seemed to be one
that will solve the problem, which has been a
knotty one for some time, of introdncing a
game which will meet the excitement incident
to most outdoor sports and at the same time
be suitable for indoor play. At present when
the outdoor season closes most of the athletes
drop tbe sports in which they have been in
terested and the benefits thev derived from
them are lost. This game is one that requires
skill and agility. but strength is not one of the
necessary factors. and, consequently. men of
all physical conditions can take part in it. It
has also been found to have been a useful
sport for girls and women, as it is especially
APTEn THE FALL.
adapted to securing good health without having
the nervous strain caused by some of the
sports now indulged in.
In its principli. it is a combination of foot
ball and lacrosse. It resembles foot ball in
most of the rulings, but in the method to be
pursued to obtain a goal the game more closely
resembles lacrosse. Although at first glance it
would hardly seem possible to have any amount
of team play in the game, still it is only by the
concerted action that a team can play to the
beet advantage. A novice in the game inva
riably feels disposed when he obtains the ball
to make a shot for the goal, which could not be
made from any distance one time in a hundred,
as in order that the ball should remain in the
basket it has to be skillfully and easily tossed,
not thrown. A good player will. when he has
the ball, quickly look for one of his own team
who is in an uncovered position to whom he
can tos it. In this way a well-drilled team
could almost entirely keep the ball from the
hands of a team made up of new men. Quick
ness of eye, hand and foot is one of the first
requisites for a good player, and he also must
keep his head about him. A moment's hesita
tion or a wrong pass may give considerable
advantage to the other side.
If an umpire is chosen who strictly follows
the rules of the game there is little chance for
any roughness, as running with the ball is
prohibited, and thus the injuries coming from
sharp tackling in foot bal are done away with.
The attention of the player is fastened on the
ball and personal feeling in the matter is lost
sight of. The object of each player when one
of his side obtains the ball is to place himself
in an uncovered position so that one of his own
team can pays it to him, while the opponents
should in this eae stick closely to the men
with whom they are paired so that a pass to
them would gave an equal opportunity for each
to catch the ball. It is in this respect that
cool-beadedt.euand quickness count. Idi
vidlual play on the part of one man will destroy
all the good work that the rest of the team may
do. If the game in played indoors in a gym
naisium the passee should be more of a toes
rather than hard straight throw.
As the game has apparently obtained a good
foothold in this city and as it is a healthful and
at the same times exciting sport it is to be
hoped that the efforts of Mr. Joyce to make the
game a popular one in this city will meet with
success, Some of the men under him are bo
conming quite proficient and before long he will
have a iirst-class team,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86088296/1893-06-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Indoor</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GAME OF BASKET BALL.
Interesting and Exciting Sport For Thos
Not Able to Exercise Kegularly.
The unnounceinent that at a woman's
educational institution not far from this
city tho students played a close and ex
citing game of "basket ball" wasperhaia
the first item which attracted public at
tention to a sport that is rapidly becom
ing very popular in this country among
those who have neither the physique nor
the taste for baseball or football. The
rules of the new sport are comparatively
simple, and the ease with which the
fundamental laws of the game can be
acquired in a few minutes' practice have
served to make it popular wherever it
has been introduced, while its freedom
from much of the roughness and intri
cacy of football has also tended to make
the devotees of basket ball enthusiastic
in their praise of its merits.
The name "basket ball" is derived from
the fact that scores are made not by car
rying the ball across the goal lines or
kicking it over the goal bar as in foot
ball, but by throwing the spheroid into I
a moderately small basket, which is hung
about 10 feet above the ground or floor.
To accomplish Buch a feat usually re
quires much practice, and as a rule tho
try at goals are far more numerous than
tho scores. Either hand or both hands
can be used in holding the ball, and it
must either he thrown or be batted with
tho open hand a punch with the fist or
arm, or a kick, constituting a foul.
The game differs from football also in
tho fact that no player is allowed to run
with the ball, but must stand where it is
caught, and a fair catch can be made
only with the hands. If the ball is held
for an unnecessarily long time, the um
pire takes possession of it and puts it
"ia play" by throwing it in the air, no
player being allowed to touch it in such
an event until it has struck the ground.
If a ball goes out of bounds, it is put in
play as in football, and no player is "off
sido," but every player has the right to
touch the ball anywhere or everywhere
in the game, provided the ball is in play.
No pushing, tripping, 6hoving or tac
kling is allowed, and every such offense
constitutes a foul, which gives one point
to the opposing nine. As a goal counts
but threo points and a foul one. there is
every incentive to avoid rough play. The
players advance the ball by tossing it to
some member of their own nine, and
there is the best opportunity for success
in personal skill combined with good
team play. The "forwards" and "cen
ters" usually toss the ball forward, but
when it gets dangerously near his own
goal, the goalkeeper often bats it with
tho open palm.
Ono advantago which basket ball has
over many other forms of popular sport
lies in tho fact that, while it allows 18
players to participate, it can be pursued
tho year round in tho open air during
tho warmer months and in the gymna
sium whilo cold weather prevails. Again,
basket ball can be played by persons
whose physique is not of tho most robust
type, although many athletes also have
found, in it a healthful form of exercise.
It has pypved of great value In furnish
ing exercise for business men, women
and children, as wpll as brawny students,
and from the general success it has al
ready attained wherever it has been in
troduced there is every probability that
basket ball will soon become a very popu
lar and widespread form of outdoor and
indoor sport. Boston Advertiser.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1894-11-25/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Sport+Game+Indoor+Outdoor&st=text&r=0.17,0.243,0.165,0.175,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text><BASKET BALL
JTHAMChGIVIXO GAlE 31ETWEEX
oPlioUORES AXD IRESllJIE
3 Iopular and Graceful Game bat
Has Foiinil Great Favor AnioiiK
Girls Some of the Rules nUll HeK
iilations Observed in PlajinK1 It
Basket ball is to tie womens col
lege what football is to the mens
The Bryn Mawr girls are particu
larly enthusiastic over this sport and
the Smith college students are in train
ing for a match game some day
Thanksgiving week
A picked nine from the sophomore
class will be pitted against a picked
nine from the freshmen class The
Smith college girl is immensely inter I
ested in basket ball which she also
calls cradle ball
1
I j
I
r
r
j
1DiUikct For IIKIOOM
Daslcct Vac Outdoor
L At Bryn Mar the students are
equally as devoted to this game in
deed their interebt in it is tremendous
and vies with 5 oclock teas and the
atricals in mitigating the ennui l of var
sity life The freshman and sopho
more classes are particularly alive to
this sport Miss Elsa Bowman is the
captain or the sophomores nine while
Miss Corlnne Putnam is the leader of
the freshman
WHY THE GAME IS POPULAR
The beauty of tne gameor one of I
I its beauties for it has manyis that II
it can be played by any number and
the more he merrier it is usually i
J
J voted The ideal number however is
nine on each side There is a goal I
keeper two backs to assist a center
a right and left center two forwards I
and a home man I e a woman in this
c1 TJ y
Tire accompanying diagram shows
the positions of the players
The end and aim of the game is to
toss a ball which is the size of a small
football into one of the two large bas
kets suspended at each end of the field
The winning side is the one that lands
the ball in the opponents basket The
basket is placed about ten feet high
When the game is played in the
gymnasium the basket Is bracketed to
tb side of the wall For outdoor use
it is supported at the same height by
au upright post The price of the bas
Jets or goals is 15 per pair for in 1
door use when supplied with a pipe
or post for outdoors the cost is some
what more The balls which are cov
ered with Jeather and about twenty
A four inches in circumference cost
about 3 each a rubbercoated ball
J can be purchased for 115 1
Basket ball can be played in a gym I
nasium in a large room or a small
b 1 HeW 01 a large field if in the latter I I
as many as thirty or fifty players may I
take part I
APPROPRIATED BY WOMEN I
The man who originated the game j
01 invented it or whatever the proper
word may be did not intend it merely
for amusement his idea was to pro i
vide a good allaround physical exer
cise and as such it cannot be im
P oyed upon combining as it does run
ning jumping bending pnd twisting
nearly every muscle and joint in the
body is brought into exercise
Mr James Naismith of Springfield i
Mass originated basket ball about
I
three years ago As soon as it became
known among the gymnasiums it
spread like an fclHdenfie Primarily
intended for young men for whom
most of the good things of life are in
tended it was soon taken up by young
women who declared that If there
was anything good in the game they
would like io become acquainted with
itThe
The girl forthwith bought a book of
rules which they masteredin very
brief order donned their gymnasium
ostumes and began playing at once
The fine points of the game however
Were only acquired by practice
I RULES OBSERVED
j The three players ivho are designat
ilL ed as forwards occupy the third of
the ground nearest the opponents
pwal the centers occupy the middle
third and the backs the defensive
third of the ground The forwards
of one team stand near the backs of
the other
Out of doors with plenty of room
the field may be 150 feet long the goal
lines running through the baskets per
pendicular to the length of the field i
the side boundaries 100 feet apart
The ball is put in play IJ by the icferee 1
throwing it up in the middle of the
field this is done at the commence
ment of the game at the beginning of
the second half after each goal and J
when a foul has been made The time
of play is two halves of twenty min I
utes each I
A goal is made when the ball is I
Yf thrown or batted from the ground into
the basket provided it stays in It is
a foul if the ball Is struck with the
I fijts or kicked
The ball must be held by the hands
fl
0
i
the arms or body may not be used for
I holding it
No pushing tripping shouldering or
striking is allowed infringements of
this rule count as a foul
The score is counted by points A
goal counts three points a foul one
point for the opponents A majority of
points decides the game/text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023253/1895-01-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Games+Sport+Baskets&r=0.354%2C0.788%2C0.735%2C0.391%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL.
Those who were interested in the
basket ball games played last winter
will be pleased to learn that the town
and school boys are tohaveonemore
battle for the supremacy. A word
about the game which has become so
popular in the past few years will
be interesting to those who enjoy
good honest sport.
Basket ball was invented in 1889 by
ames Nuismith, teacher in the interna
tional training school, Springfield. Dur
ing its first season it wasnot particularly
popular hut has gained in favor and may
now be called quite as important sport in
the Y. M. C. A. world as football and
baseball, but it is essentially an indoor
game and the interest that is excited in
an exercise confined to the gymnasium
can perhaps never equal the zest which is
thrown into a game like football, played
under the blue of heaven, in the fresh out
door atmosphere and sun's rays that seem
to penetrate the muscles ot the athlete
and impart added vivacity. However,
at the season when football bruises have
long ago healed and conquests on the
gridiron are matters for rumination, he
who sighs for the pigskin can find much
satisfaction in basket ball, it possessing
all the elements of football but, if rules
are enforced, lacking the excessive rough
ness. The ball used is perlcctly round,
made of a rubber bladder, covered with
leather and is about a foot in diameter.
Briefly outlined the game according to
official rules for 1805, is played as follows:
baskets especially constructed tor the
purpose, are placed in a vertical position
with the mouth ten feetlrom the ground,
one at each end of the field (gymnasium),
occupying much the same position in re
lation to the players as do football goals.
i ne competitive teams tane positions on
the field as in football, save that there is
no line-up, The teams are composed of
five men when the playing space is less
than 1800 square feet, seven when it is
more than 1800 and less than 3600 and
nine men when over 3600. The referee,
with a player from each side, takes posi
tion in the center. He puts the ball in
play by throwing it up. Which side has
first ball depends on which center man
secures it. The ball is not kicked or
struck with the fists but thrown or batted
with the flat of the hand and the object
is, to get it into the basket, doing which
scores a goal. On the number of goals
secured depends the victory. The net
work of rules which govern the action of
the game is quite as elaborate as football
and will not be given here. Suffice it to
say that spectators easily comprehend
its action. The putting of a ball into the
basket may seem a veryeasv thing to do
but as a matter of fact it is very difficult
to acomplish with the floor empty and,
of course, much more so when two teams
are at strife. One of the rules says that
the ball shall always be kept in motion.
Two twenty-minute halves are played
with a rest of ten minutes between "the
halves. This is the time of actual play.
Each side has itscaptain while position
is the same as in baseball. The referee is
judge of the ball. He is the superior offi
cer ot the game and decides all questions
uul ucuimciy lulling on me umpire, i lie
umpire is judge of the men, calls all fouls,
notifies the offenders and has power to
disqualify men.
The game which was to be played
on Thursdayevening of this week has
been postponed until Saturday even
ing. The two teams have been prac
tising faithfully and will be able to
play a very interesting game. It is
hoped that the public will turn out
and encourage the gymnasts, as all
the proceeds over and above the ex
penses are to go towards much need
ed new apparatus for thegymnasium.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-04-02/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Co-eds+Basket+Ball+Match+Basketball+Basket-ball+Teams+Team&st=text&r=0.651,0.558,0.294,0.313,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CO-EDS AT BASKET BALL
Secret Practice at Berkeley for
the Great Match on
Saturday.
Greek Letter Fraternities to Present
Plays Paul Revere Lodge
Was Honored.
BERKELEY, Cal., April I.â€” The Berke
ley Co-ed basket-ball team are ready for
their battle with the Stanford nine next
I Saturday. They have gone into secret
practice and are devoting their time and i
i attention to signal work and to giving
their muscles the hnal course of ex
ercise before they stand up against
the wearers of the cardinal. They
are ail on the gui vive, as are
j the other women athletes of the
i university, for the contest on Saturday
will be t*e first contest they have entered
for honors. "We have the reputation and
the athletic prestige of the university to
uphold," said one of the fairest members
of the team to-day, "and we are going into
1 the struggle with* the purpose of coming
i out victors. We realize the odds we will
have to contend against in not being in as
I good training as we might, and then the
Stanford girls are much more experienced
than we. At any rate we will do our best,
J since we have accepted Stanford's chal
i lenge."
Two or three of the young women have
the appearance of being overtrained,
judging from their pallid faces and worn
expression. This may be due, however, to
anxiety over the result of the came. Tlieir
new costumes consist of white sweaters
and blue bloomers with gold trimmings.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-12-18/ed-1/?sp=18&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+K+U+Naismith+Sport+Team&r=0.599%2C1.081%2C0.403%2C0.214%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL AT I U.
XKW BAJIE I.. CHKlT FA VII IX IX TUB
CLASSIC SHADES OF LA1VIIEACU.
How It I Plajeil The Tennis That
Ilnie Hern Formed The Fncnlty
Eiijoj- Ihe Game Clinncellur
Snow a. Crack Plnjer.
LAWRENCE. KAS.. Dec. 17.-(SpeciaU
The basket ball "fever" has broken out
In Its most violent form among Kansas
university people. Dr. Naismith. the new
physical director, brought the germs with
him, and that they were healthy specimens
is evidenced by their activity.
At first only a few of the students siw
in basket ball the diversion. But the dis
ease spread rapidly. Not only doe- eai h
class already possess its basket ball team,
but the literary and the scientific men of
the faculty are backing their "crack fives.
Eve-ry evening the gymnasium is filled with
a scrambling mass of humanity, and the
spectators who can recognlz. a friend or
acquaintance In the melee must be gifterd
with second sight.
Five men compose a team at basket ball.
The floor Is divided into three parts. Tho
center men of the plaving teams oe-upy a
space chalked off in the middle, am, the
other four dispose themselves In various
graceful attitudes in the end sections. The
referee tosses up the ball just above the
heads of the centers, who are standing
face to face. Each makes a jump and en
deavors to hit the hall, knocking it over
to his own men and toward his goal. Then,
the scramble begins. The accomplished,
and gentlemanly contortionist in the pat
ent medicine show could not rival basket
ball players In the way of tying French
knots in their corporal systems. The ma.-s
of writhing humanity turns over and over
in kaleidoscopic fashion, suddenly un
winds itself and is again resolved Into
parts. A man goes diving after the ball
and comos triumphantly up out of the
fray with his arms full of another man's
head! The aim In playing basket ball, so
it Is claimed. Is to throw the ball Into tho
round baskets, suspended at each end ot
the field, a greater number of times than
the opposing players. In reality, however,
it would seem that the cherls-hed object of
each plajer was to make as large and
choice collection of hruises as possible.
But that is basket ball from the specta
tor's point of view. To the players It Is
an all absorbing sport. Some of them
even have the audacity to assert that It Isi
a "gentle game, don't you know." Gentle,
indeed! One might as appropriately speak
of a bucking broncho as "well-mannered."
When the field Is not divided into sec
tions the game is reallr rough, but If thi
chalk lines are drawn, and fouls are faith
fully called whenever a man over-teps.
his boundaries, the bruise hunter adds to
Ills collection more slowly. It Is amusing:
to watch the players trying to remember
to have the proper respect for the bound
aries. Indeed It is truly pathetic to sej
what limitations of power a simple chalk
line can put on thee great, strong athletes.
In actual agony they har.g over the edge
and reach out helpless, longing arms to
ward the ball. Now and then an unruly
foot goes across the line, and then the
sharp whistle of the referee Is heard. A
foul entitles the players ort the otht.r side
a chance at throwing goal.
The game consists of two halves of
twenty minutes each. A twenty minute
rest is given between, and a new- team
put on to utilize the rest time. Each time
the ball goes Into the basket two points
are scored for the side whose goal Is
thrown As In baseball, a small score
Indicates a good game.
The Inventor of Ilnsket Hnll.
Dr. James Naismith Is the inventor of
basket ball. Unlike most of our games It
Is not the development of some medieval
sport. It was worked out on scientific
principles to meet a long felt want. Dr.
Naismith was physical director of a Y.
31. C. A. training school at Springfield.
Mass.. where the problem of supplying thlsj
need was brought to him for solution.
Busket ball was the result. It was In the
winter of 9I-52 that the game was intro
duced. The rules were made out and hung
In the "gym" fdr the inspection of playerj
before the game was ever tried. The men
were a little skeptical "at first about it.
but after the; ball was once thrown up no
coaxing was needed to Induce them to
Play. Basket ball came Into general favor
first through the Y. M. C. A. Having been
Introduced through the association it was
natural that it should spread through that
medium. Before long, however, colleges be
gan to investigate and adopt the game, ami
In the short .-pace of seven yeirs It has
gaimd a wide iopuhirlty. In the Eastern
colleges, both for men anil for womn.
basket ball Is the reigning favorite among
sports. The rules are not changed for tho
young women players, though doubtless the
game is played with a bit more tenderness.
Though at first sight the game appears
to be a free for all scramble. It soon be
comes evident that a number of sclentiilr?
,1'laya are iossibIe. Unfailing good judg
ment, anu goon muscular control are the
first requisites for a good player. The treat
ment of the ball Is the subject of several
rules. It can be tossed, rolled on Ihe floor
and pushed around, but must never In
kicked. There are no signals, and a play
lasts until the ball Is passed Into the basket.
Tennis In the 1'iilverslt jr.
The Kansas university men are going to
be great basket ball enthusiasts. Each
class has a picked team, and places on thei
teams are as much sought as on the var
sity eleven. Among faculty members thero
are two teams the Snow hall and tho
Frazer hall, representing the scientists and
the literary men. On the former team
Dr. WHHston. Marshall Barber. Clarenco
McClung. A. H. Clark and Dr. Naismith
hold positions. Their opponents are A.
G. Cantield. AY. H. Carruth. E. M. Hop
kins. M. W. Sterling and Archie Hogg.
On Tuesdays and Thursdays at 3 p. m. thesj
distinguished individuals lay aside their
dignity and their collars, don sweaters anil
pugilistic airs, and come forth into the
arena to dw battle. With a grace that
is acciuired only through long years of
bending over desks and laboratory tables,
they scamiier now here, now there, after
the elusive canvas sphere.
When the faculty teams met for their
last practice. Chancellor Snow- appeared.
He was Immediately besieged to play. The
chancellor protested that he was too green,
but such fetching invitations could never
be turned dotvn. The head of the universi
ty disappeared Into a dressing room, and
In a few moments, he emerged In a cos
tume of which the most noticeable feat
ures were- white canvas shoes, a seraphic:
grin, and a neutral tinted sweater. With
characteristic vigor he attacked the game,
and before long he was the champion play
er. There is nothing slow about the chan
cellor when he gets into action.
Tournament in January.
On January 13 an Indoor tournament will
be given. Basket hall will be the chief
feature of the c-xhihltlon. The old skat
ing rink on Kentucky street will probably
be rented for the occasion. Dr. Naismltii
says he enjoys working with college men
far better than with others. He believes
there is no artificiality whatever about e-ol-Iege
students. "If a man is a man they
will respect him and his endeavors in their
behalf." he says, "but they won t Stan. I
trilling a minute. When I find it yo'ing
fellow who kicks on the referee's decision-..
I just ask him n call fouls for a few mo
ments. After he has called a few and other
men have kicked on his rulings, h,. never
kicks again."
Pr. Naismith has much influence t
the young men in his charge. In Mrs. Cora
McColli,m Smith he has an able colleague.
The revolution In feeling which a few yearn
have brought about among the physical
culture students Is remarkable. When the
training was first Introduced about four
years ago and the girls lirst donned their
suits, the presence of a man within a ra
dius of three blocks wrought the most
awful consternation. Now men pass back
and forth throuch the r-vm to and from
the laboratory during the girls" cla.-aes and
ni'liing is thought ot it. Before long :hi
g.rls will trv basket ball. too. Equal suf
frage in ainietirs is one oi me cnarms of
Kansas university. Visitors to Lan-rem-o
must get a basket ball guide beforehand and
lecrn tne nngo. it tney wis.i to dd able to
converse intelligently with university peo
nle. for that is the all absorbing rnnle re
the day. It may not be a great while. Judg-
i hi; iruiii uiijjemuiii e ueioic processors
will be whistling students down in their
recitations and -allInc "foul" when thir
make mistakes in their translations, so
jreai is cue iiiuiience oi iiaoit</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92053934/1904-11-19/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Rules+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Dribble&st=text&r=0.506,0.568,0.197,0.21,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW RULES ON BASKETBALL
Changed Conditions For Championship
Contests.
Up to the present the basketball
rules have been amended each season
by additions and omissions in various
places. This year, however, the rules
have been rearranged and many rules
bear different numbers and are not
found in the same successive order.
An advantage in the new rule book
also is that at the top of the page i3
the page, so that it is no longer neccs-
indicated the rule number printed on
that page, so that it is no longer ne
cessary to turn back or forth to ascer
tain which rule is being read.
The first new feature is that the
rules became effective Nov. 1, 1904.
This settled a fixed time for everywhere
and did not leave it open for teams to
play old Ule3 because "they did not
have the new book and there is noth
ing in the rules saying when they be
come effective," In referring to the
basket, the word "basket" is not used
in contradiction to "goal."
The minimum size of playing space
(2,400 square feet) is omitted in rule 1.
section 1. Rule 3, section 1, requires
a background of wood at least three
quarters of an inch thick for the bas
kets. Screens are no longer permitted.
The paying of the officials expenses in
serial championship games is no longer
mandatory.
An important change in rule 11, sec
tion 10. prohibits more than one player
of each team from tackling the ball at
the same time. A "dribble" is now
only counted such when the player ad
vances more than two steps wtiile roll-
UDUDDDDGBD
You can eat anything, digest it and
enjoy it if you give your stomach a
thorough course of treatment with
Dr. laber's Pbpsin lompouna.
Perhaps your stomach is over
worked and accumulates undigest
ed matter whici ferments and up
sets the entire system, causing
belching and bloating, bad breath,
a languid, weary feeling, sleep
lessness, etc.
T&ESER'SIEEEMMlGOrJlFOUnD
cleans out the refuse, heals the irritated secretive linings of the stomach, stim
ulates an activity of the digestive fluids and tones up the entire tract. Blood is
pure when digestion is complete. Dr. Taber's Pepsin Compound produces
perfect, healthy digestion. 9
TABLETS, 10c, 25c, 50c. at drug stores. Uquld Form, 50c. and $1.
KTKZPMTK? To prove its merits, we will send sample
m mmwtmmm package by mail. Free, to any address.
DR. TABER MFG. CO., Poorto, Ills.
ing or bouncing the ball.
The rule that in a dribble both hands
shall not be used simultaneously more
than once is still effective. Under rule
11, section 17, a man is not out of
bounds if only one foot is outside.
Players may be changed at any time
during the game (new rule 1, section
26). Last year's rules as well as the
new rules authorizes the referee to
award one point to the man fouled by
an opponent while trying for goal.
There was some doubt formerly as to
whether the team whose player was
fouled should also have a free throw
for goal.
The uew rules add that "this shall
noi interfere with a free throw for goal
from foul line," thus making It pos
sible to secure four points on this olio
play, if while being fouled the player
throws the goal, two points are scored,
oue point is awarded by the nfere
aud the ilayer is allowed an additional
free throw for the foul giving him uu
opiiortunity of scoring one point moro
if he throws the foul goal.
Under the old rules if a player threw
for goal from outside and missed thu
basket the ball went to the center,
while under the new rules the ball con
tinues to play. r
Under rule 12, section 1 and 4. tho
referee is required to promptly dis
qualify any player using profane or
abusive language.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble&st=text&r=-0.198,-0.266,1.395,1.395,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOO MANY fOijl Fo1ftjj l
IN BASKET BASKETPresent 1 1Present
Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
l
BY ELWOOD S
BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
r
bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
etEd ujxi np
entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
cs
ginger s and In i inn
general Generl makes the thean ui uin
an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
rather than good team work l lluther
luther tem a aacular
tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
I Iblame
or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
fou
opponents opponent much more than is nee
Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
are called caled for holding tripping A
tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
fnc
offenses but tepresnt preSfnt ytm o t
ing i ng a foul on someone somenp Eo V er TV tini tinimen tn
men i touch each other evry fr tltneTj Hme tln
moves an Inch and Vnn l
every timf time timearm 1m 1marm m marm
arm arm gets part way around an uppcEeni I
dead ded wrong and Is spoiling spiing th UPJt gas ga b
gl
loge lee rules rule permit permi a great deal more f
teal moe
dom of play pIn than do the A A f TL TLto i aD
The college dribble rule
colege permitting a
to throw the ball In the th pritn air or roll k i I t tthe
the floor take ta1t any number numbfr of steps stei rol t
catch it and try for or a baskft bkft i i is isone steP M I f JM1 JM1one
one The A A I r rules rul s make it a I dl
for a man to take more than two tw i vl t i
in a dribble In regard resrd t to the therule pror
rule rle a man running at full ful speed p us r rnecessarily l lnecessariy
necessarily necessariy take an extra step spe or orand uj i1 r rand
and his momentum usually usual bring brjn brjnar bringsarm jjr
arm ar in contact contct with wih his opponent L P Pspite
spite of the fact fac that tht the opponet rules rule saylL sy say
lowance Jownce shall shal be made md for a man mancatches r rcatches
catches the ball while whie on the run ru runare f fare Etj Etjcatches e eare
are invariably called caUe If a man eve evemuch t evemuch r
much as takes a small smal extra step stepCauses 1 1much t t tt tCauses
Causes Many Fouls FoulsAnother fra fraAnother
Ie IeAnother
Another rule that causes cU trouble Sa is Iiwhich SMJ bb bbhic
1i
which hic says sas putting puthI one ant or both bothabout i1 if ifthis
about an opponent cnsttutes constitutes arc arcThe a 1
The strIct Interpretton interpretation now OW applir i
apPl
this rule Ie causes c es more fouls tojle tojlew to be bethan bethan
than other and th the
any makfS g gslow 1 1s10w
slow w and uninteresting uninteretng M Mhave Many Tfn rnet g
have been suggested suggeste by different diftrfnt b bbal bat DSL
ball bal authorities authortes and there therp is i no douWt5 doub dOUbfethat
that the next rule book bok will wi show showeffect how howffcct T1 T1effect
effect of this agitation agItaton Manager Managtr OTT OTTT O T
the Crescents suggests that in ordf ordfsave orrf orrfsave r t
save time and in order to maka the post postwon por porwon
won on fouls a less los Important Imprtant fartc fartcdeciding faC faetrdeciding p
deciding a game that a man fouled fouledhe fou1e fouledtry
tr try a tree throw ge from tht the spot on w whe t the
he was fouled arguing arging that there therebe w i I Iplayer f
be no running to a certain lne line th tbx tbxplayer tU
player would have less chance to toa ri ria 1
a free throw that the throws wouW wouWquently woWdquently
wou
quently quenty be long ones one and that this thiswould ts tswould thuwould
would lend a spectacular clement Clement ta tagame Iigame
J
game I do not favor this rule rule bK bKwhen 1wJ b bwhen
when a guard gard was fouled foulEd under IB IBponents b bi bironents
ponents onen1s basket he would ould bfi so far is isMs t this
Ms hI own basket that a successful succesful tt ttwould t ttiitz ttiitzwould 2
would be almost impossible Impslblp an4 an4would ad an anwould f3i 1 1would
would encourage forwards forwads to foul foulguards fou f fguards
guards with impunity impunityNeutral impunityNeutral impunityNeutral
Neutral Men for Officials OfclS OfficMlsThe I IThe
The Canadians Cnadians have a system irtkj irtkjsatisfactory wt0 wt0satisfactory b
satisfactory satsfactory providing the officials officialsneutral oWc iU iUneutral
neutral which is not very ver of ofen often tenths te the OH OHIn t tt ttIn
In Canada the instant a man is A Athe t iit iitthe 1
the referee blows his wnistlP wnlst tM tMkeeper t tI t tkeeper
keeper awards one point to tho oifesei oifeseiteam oKftteam
team and without further delay dela on tb t w wIs Jt JtIs t tis
Is thrown up between the te two B Ilt10opponents i iopponents ot
opponents and the game gae goes on onscheme on onscheme o oscheme
scheme would ould be good with absoBM absoBMneutral abot abotneutrl abeOneutral
neutral neutrl officials oftclals but under this systts systtsan z syltean et
an official was the uner least l ot bit bi partial partialcould partiatlo partiatlocould
to pUO pUOcould
could swing a a close game either vrtft vrtftI m s1lth s1lthI ti
swng
I favor a rule which gmo provides that thatneutral trhp trhpevery thaJb thaJbevery
every match game the oficia officials sh S1ItdS S1ItdSneutral Uls Ulsneutral
neutral men and gme shall sQl be speciflcaDrs speciflcaDrsstructed speccUS specIflcaU3tructed f
structed to use their judgment judget as aswhether 8 83whether
whether or not the foul was wa wasintentIonally comm cr t tintentionally d T TIntentionnlv
intentionally Intentionnlv This I think tink would wuld wouldthe 5T 5Tthe rthe
Tl
the situation sltuat n The T1e trouble doesnt doet doesntmuch t tmuch 1 n nmuch
much in tho rules themselves themselvCB nUb alt nUbsome r rsome 11 11some
some of them th m are too tight tght bat ba in I1ttl I1ttlpresent 11 11present t tt ttpresent
present close interpretation Interpretaton and a andgeneral it itgeneral r rgeneral
general rule rlo cose was a inserted allowing aUowmgclals e eCJUIS Ccials
clals CJUIS a a ltte little 11LUW more 1UUIO use not u of thfir their fcii ii iiment own 3 3ment
ment and providing always that OW tHJi tHJiabsolutely thtf thtfabsolutely
absolutely h neutral neutrl men the game gamebe TT TTwithout
absolut be greaty greatly ben bencfited fited I It Is impos imposplay 1mposshb 1mposshbplay go r
play a gae game as fast a as bket baskethd1 baskethd1In
in such 3 a Umled limited space 2f as 0 a gn gnwithout gynin gyninwithout
without having scores score of foulsfinato1 foulsfinato1der touls mflI mflIder
der the strict stict interpretation Interretion of mht tha thaUUl t a abut r r rbut
officials would refrain fm fromIng
but UUl 11 It uUbiaio oficials refrn w III 1 1Ing
ing fouls which in iio io o way IirJurtv IirJurtvchances h1u in1urO in1urOchances
chances for either team tem for scoriTig Bcong Bcongwould scofl8would w5 w5would
would bo dono to elmnate eliminate toul troubl</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1908-12-06/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Strategy&r=-0.02%2C0.466%2C0.631%2C0.336%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket Bail JBailStrategy Baili all allStrategy
i Strategy StrategyBy
i
By DR DRJMiES JAMES NAISMITH NAISMITHFather
Father of the Game GameCopyright GameICoprlght190S Gameicopyright
Copyright ICoprlght190S 190S bi Joseoh B IL Bowles1NEW Bowles Bowles1NEW
1 1NEW NEW ELEMENT S IN THE GAME
I was AI ar forded rded the honor of ofth ofth ofng
t
th game of basketball ba ketbal1 some somears somen somerar5 me mering
n ng
elements elementsicn
many new
ring ago
were remotest in my m mind mindno mindowr
y ten icn
owr nr into no the winter pastime PMtUnea
g field ld for effort If IfJtassarhusetts ItfrIends IfE Ifyllass
new ne
CD a
E Jtassarhusetts yllass yllassa rice friends t then had told toldien toldhe
hen he that a quarter of o a a century centuryatuetes centurati1etes centurye
atuetes would be planning planningand er erlt eft e
lt t manners of attack and on defense defenseconceiving defenseonceiV se seconceiving
conceiving onceiV ng schemes schemes of play lay to toHer toIder
Her and hoodwink opponents I Ihave It
d t have doubted but such suchcome events eventst eventscom
t come com to pass Year by year ear the theor
or for plays of new variety Is Isbring IslIng
bring stronger and the thee mortel more In Ine InIe
Ie e the better liked d by b coaches coachesI
I have pet et about aboutes to tell you youPS youhave
PS S fans and players alike alikee alll lr lrt
e f t center your our efforts how to tost tot tost
st t your plays to the best ad adage adedurlng ads
age during s the progress of plan plays playswhere plaRwhen
where to direct your our attack attackscience in ingame 10J1me
game where strategy and science scienceUidoing scienceJwiClln se sei
Uidoing i themselves themselvesthe thEmS lves lvesthe
the spectator tator who watches basketplay basket basketplay basketpIa
play pIa for the privilege of Indulging Indulgingcsasies Indulgingrstasles Indulgingrstasies
csasies over the wild movements movementsermoving movementsermoln movementsermoving
ermoving legs arms and Indoor Indoored
ed muscles the science n of f abth the theie th the e ee
ie e oustltutes itself in scoring sco scoarcuracy 1e leather leatherre abil abilarcuracy abllaNuracy
arcuracy In lodging the leather leatherre
re within the net nete
e Till 111 endeavor to demonstrate demonstrater
r t c science of this game gameability lies in inutility inabIJit
utility abIJit o M th tho guards forwards ana anaer
er to nork up to a highly em emit effipdnt e epclnt
it pcnt m the movementsede movements which whichIe
tde Ie the hl efforts at goals goalsese
ese irtKlfs lrt df les on Basketball Strat Strattherefore Stratthenfore Strattherefore
therefore will deal eal with the thea
a of the players about the floor floorsslng fioorsslng floorasing
sslng of the ball and the most mostre mostt7e mosttse
re manner of puzzling oppo oppoby oppoby oppuby
by a series of plays To start starttake starts
as s take the play which has has2e ha hae
2e e known as left forward to toforward toforwar toforward
forward In left forwards posl postof poslOf poslOf
Of course your our team must musta
a set of signals which are easily easilyed ea l1y l1yl
ed l They may be number signals signalsed
ed to the players by b the captain captainhe
he 11 e team or they the may ma be silentq silent silentjr
jr q In the rase tEl of number slg s1gtie slgtlie sl slthe
the same course Is I pursued as asused asused II IIUed
used In football For Instance Instancethe
the accompanying diagram Sup Supthat Supthat Supthat
that the series of numbers whlcn whlcnthe whlcnthe whichthe
the direction of the play Is the thed
d ottered by b your our captain Tour Touril
il I for the play pia left forward to toforward tof toforward
forward f in left forwards pos poswould poslwould post postwould
would be b 26 312 88 The cen cennamber cennumber cennumber
number being 3 the ball leaves leavesto leaveto
to go to the left forward whose whosen
n rat Is I while the last player to tove tovs
ve 1 the ball before the shot at the theIs
Is attempted Is the right forwardla forward
la o a2 a2ou 2
roJ ou may rea use us a movement of the thec th thc
c foot to Indicate n w certain play playnrtr pia playthe
nrtr 1 the th man who gives the 81 stdgnil e elsnal 81R1
lsnal R1 1 must give It unconcernedly unconcernedlyat
at It t nay 113 not be noted by b op oprts opt oprtt
rts rtt t and arc Dr made use u e of to advantage advantage1s
aftl aftlIs aftela
1s e placing of players imme immefly
fly 11 after the completion of the theKbJh thehl1 thevLh
KbJh proves especially effective effectiveIts
Its h accompanying diagram the theare theare theare
are idle Idl If the center of the therepresented tllorepresented therepresented
represented as the aggressor aggressortie o
tie t e jump on his opponent and ands
it t s the ball in the direction hull indiby Indlb hullby
by b the captains signal In this thishft thishe thisthe
the centef slaps the sphere to toeft toeft toe
e eft t Fide where the th left forward forwardes
jves es It and shoots It back to the theforward thefonard theforward
forward who ho In the mean meanhas meanhas meanhas
has taken up a position to the theff ther
ff r the basket from which he tries trlesn triesgoal
goal goaln 011
n 1 the truly tml scientific part of the theimation theinaUon theination
imation takes place The center centerJumping centerjumping
Jumping spurts for a position to togh
IgM gh side of the basket while the theoarl1 theorward
forward having handled the ball balla ballthe ballthe
a the goal tosser secured it iti it itI
i a bee line for a point directly directlysnt directl directlJnt
ant of the basket basketstudying basketstudying basketstudying
studying the accompanying dta dtayou dla1Cu dtayou
you can readily see what an ex exit
it t defense f this makes providing provldlnrlg
right rlg t forward falls In his hi effort effortii
ii the ball within the net You Toucovered YouQered YouCowered
covered every point toward which whichaU
HI uay bound as it caroms away awa
the goal It Is then up to your OU
to 0 leap into the air and again at atR atn
n R goal go L it is a noticeable fea feajjnat
jjnat that in this or any an other play for for2rertne forltter
2rertne ltter the plan Is for every ee play p1nrlose
lose his opponent and to do 110
mast aromplish a ompllsh his part partof of the thein
Ina inatlon J2A0rn Ion from a point T lnt otl other er than
in n which
he places himself at the
m the referee to tosses les es the sphere
the centers at the start of theId the thepostnjr held
ld tie e OPposing oPPOsi postnjr renter leap Into Intothan
higher than your our center thus thust t11UI t11Uthe
g the ball
toward the opponents opponrntst opponrntsItmalnl s
I it
t t mains ln for y your our ur guards flrtls to toi tosphere toSphE
the
i sphere SphE IE and follow out Ute UteI UteslgnajEd tlioEvery
as slgnajEd
Every move must mustId
I e VitI itJi the
utmost
celerity elerlt The
Id to revive rl rerelve hE the ball from the theBtinrt
Btinrt must takE ke It on n the run and the
I under thn
basket should do the theSll00t
aid shoot hoot for the goal ool before beforer b rOrp
r cress n L 1 baR R st stopped PPed and the pnr pnru pnrth pl1redgunrd i w
edgunrd guan of th the opposing team teamte
ed Wm to u
te block his hl s pass passBm past pasdiagram ar arthe s
t diagram Bm to the thear richt isthe Is Isthhe s stje
thhe the play pla ay reversed rever red that isthri Is IsIn
In thri the e right ght forward orw to left for
right gri
forwards poMtlop poMtlopcoverlnsr JJn tlo The
1es naes for covering th the bound of
i 1
following a nol THMwlbl tfbl faUiirc falllJTII
Pan pa of the
I jroalshootine for fornbseri
ree also Iso nbseri obsenet the th poMMon M c Hons of ofthe q qI qmEn
mEn used beln r l
I erte er erWI
tinat WI Jt hive f Cn cousidemi ld th the
w nho
wa srn rt the first trijght to
t at a t the t r
nt opening enln of each fac lCll CPaco RSn RSni RSnPnrnnr t
i nraTnr to ail 11 M 1 the ther pinvrr I ht
InS n
r J1ni s sfrr l11r
for a tMII rritePln Uln
ba bai 111 thr fIt T 1 e a ctrrs 111 e t1
career a TPer ends wi retn t th tht
eaylslte alslt alsltI p anti thlO
I IAltnot 11 n oy
n and 1In other I tl
1P1 manner thsn th n ht
i se nO for 1r
I L v pehns h nII 1Itt1 t u uon ts
r11tt It I
lefro Pcr H
Trio mstrlt t11 t11bap qm qmwind
bap wind n hsnt 1 env tI NJul NJulII r
season aon on onaccp t tra
bar coact
II an 1 1p 1fn n
season fn is I t
p ha5kethol thU thUntlnT1 1
ParHrlpntlnn ntlnT1 t
r en t tu
al alt6 aids In
n pot
t6 hr at t1 r
Tl d
t rsieal si a 1 rott en ait v h hn t ti rl
rhhh l hI
1 i npCIo t t to toar hr hro n
o I mAnn of t tIftlatJ
ar T t n
IftlatJ rOI11 onr plA plAaCCount
accp aCCount nt for this by b de
daring Iarin that different lffer nt sports bring dif different dtferent dlfferent
ferent sets of muscles into play pll and inconsequence In Inconsequence Inconsequenco
consequence the start of the basket
ball season finds some parts of th thplayers tile tlieplayers tilepl1ers e
players machinery maclilne weakened lay bymonths laymonths b bmonths
months of Inactivity But basketball basketballuses
uses every 6VC1 muscle of the body bod anrt anrtthat anr1that an anthat
that continuously Hence the lunsjc lunsjcand lunljand lunyand
and heart have a heavier hea Ier part to play plaIn piain k t
In purifying the blood and building up uii uiithese tr trthese
these unused muscles AX s soon u uthe aM aMthe uthe
the athlete ath etc begins to get into basket basketball baskctball basketball
ball trim these muscles are strengthened strength strengthened strengthened
ened he breathes easier when dashln dashingabout dashlnabout dashlnabout h
about the basketball floor and con constant constant constant
stant exercise puts him In shape for forhard u uhard ahard
hard season seasonThe seasonThe ea80nThe
The basketball player also needs needsa 5
a stomach which is not susceptible susceptibleto
to hard Jolts That Is a xequisttwhich requisite requisitewhich requisitewhich e
which cannot be neglected If the play player pla plaor
or intends to put forth his best ener energies ln s sgies r rgles
gies Sweet stuffs coffee alcoholic alcoholicbeverages alcol101lcbevcrages alcohollbeverages c
beverages tobacco pastry I1ast and late latehours latehours lathours e
hours must necessarily be blacklisted blacklistedAlo
Also before practice and games the theathlete theathlete th thathlete
athlete should eat lightly and of food foodswhich foodwhkh foodwhisk
which contain the largest I amount o onourishment or ornourishment ornourishment f
nourishment In the smallest buk bukIn bukIn bulkIn
In future articles we shall outline outlinemore outlinemore outlinmore P
more plays which arc absolutely es essential e eentinJ ersentiaL
sential and when len these are Impressed Impressedwill impressewill
will add what coaches recognize rcc gnlze a afeature ni nifeature aifeature
feature plays that is combinations combinationsout 5
out of the ordinary run which added addedto add lt ltto t tto
to the repertoire of teams Rive a va varied vavied n nrled
vied and complicated style of attacand attack attackand attackand k
and defense</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1913-11-30/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Basket-ball+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Code+Amended+Sport+Game+Intercollegiate&st=text&r=0.219,0.33,0.279,0.297,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET-BALL
Dr. Sharp e Takes Side of
Player at Intercollegiate
Meeting.
LEAVE OUT ROUGHNESS
Too Many Tecnnicsfities It Claim of
Coaches and Players New
Role Affects Centers.
New York, Nov. 29. Exception to the
trend of collegiate Icglsla ion was voiced
In no uncertain terms at the annual inter
pretation .neetlng of the Intercollegiate
basket-ball rules committee at the Hotel
Astor yesterday afternoon Dr. A. II.
Sharpe, coach of the Cornell football,
basket-ball, and baseball teams, took the
side cf the plajer and coach against the
rules committee, which, he said, was con
cerning itself more with ruling on tech
nicalities than on the practical issues of
the game.
The discussion arose when Dr. Joseph
E. Ray croft chairman of the rules com
mittee, and the presiding officer, called
for the consideration of Rule 11, which Is
designed to penalize blocking. The rule
had been amended over summer so that it
read: "A player is entitled to take any
position on the court but if in taking a
position he faces an opponent or makes
bodily contact with an opponent so as to
interfere with the latter's progress he
Is blocking."
Dr. Raycrott said that the change had
been made In the rule 'as part of the
general plan of the rulemakers to elim
inate all unnecessary roughness and com
pel the plajers to "play the ball and not
the man." By this rule, said Dr. Ray
croft all Illegal Interference with a play
er by his opponent resulting from the
close guarding of pla, would be deemed
a foul and penalized as such.
Dr. Sharpe carried his point because.
when the discussion had been concluded
and a vote taken on the Interpretation of
the rule Dr. It ay croft and Ralph Mor
gan, of the University of Pennsylvania,
secretary of the committee, agreed to
permit an editorial correction which sub
stituted an "and" for the "or" in the
rule in question, making it mean that
only by direct bodily contact can a player
block his opponent
The most important changes In the rules
forthe coming year have to do with the
"Jump" ball and the ball when It goes
out of bounds. In order to eliminate the
fouling that so frequently happened under
the old Jump rule, the players Jumping
for the ball now, either In the center or
on any part of the floor will have to
Jump with one hands behind the back.
The meeting ruled that b behind the
back was meant behind any part V the
back below the shoulder, with the hand
touchihg the back, rather than the strict
working of the section, which compelled
the player to have on hand behind the
back at the waistline.
The other rule regarding the Jump ball
was aimed to do away with a great many
of the "Jumps" along the sideline after
the ball has been out of bounds by giv
ing it to the opponent of the man last
touched by It The rules relating to
dribbling were also discussed, but no rul
ing was made.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1930-12-28/ed-1/?sp=6&q=basketball&r=0.095%2C0.51%2C0.774%2C0.412%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> BASKETBALL
_ PlAVS^ PLAYLPS
Fine Gyms Make Basketball Second Only To
Football In Popularity
BY EVERETT S. DEAN
Basketball ('each. Indiana l'.
Basketball is recognized in most
of the country as the second major
sport. Its progress has come about
solely on its merits. Proximity of
the crowd to the players lias made
it possible for the crowd to experi
ence thrills which go with speedy
action more than in any other
j sport.
Pine gymnasiums and field houses
in many states are real testimony
I to the popularity of basketball. De
mand for seating space has led
larger towns to build gymnasiums
With seating capacities of 4000 to
5000. F.ne field houses with seat
1 ing capacity from 8000 to 15.000
have been built to meet the college
demand. Outstanding basketball
plants of the country are the
I Palestra at the University of
Pennsylvania, and most of the field
houses of Big Ten schools. The
Indiana State High School Basket
ball Tournament is played each
i year before 20.000 fans and offers
a great spectacle to sportdom.
Schedule making and tournament
f play in high shools have been
regulated by state athletic asso
ciations to the extent that high
school basketball is on a sounder
basis than ever before. Schedules
once consisted of 35 games, which
were too many for the high school
boy. In some states 18 to 20 games
now make up the schedules. The
strain of long tournaments has
been avoided by spreading tourn
aments over a period of three weeks
j instead of two.

Uniform officiating is another
sign indicating progress. Officiating
I
North, South
Elevens Will
Meet Sunday

NEW YORK. Dec. 27â€” Dâ€” The
latest football game on record for
j an eastern field is scheduled to
be played tomorrow when all star
teams from the north and south
1 clash for the benefit of charity.
After many vicissitudes. Jack
McBride and Stumpy Thomason of
the Brooklyn Dodgers professional
team, former luminaries from
Syracuse and Georgia Tech res
pectively, have carried their plans
through to the point where their
teams are all assembled and a
waiting the kickoff at Ebbetts
Field tomorrow afternoon.
The question of just what charity
is to benefit has been in doubt
ever since the Knights of Colum
bus. original sponsors of the game
withdrew, but it is certain there
will be some beneficiary.
Chinese are taking a fanev to
hard candy, which is sold at the rate
of six large sticks for a cent.
Mrs M Swaine. Australian oldest1
colonist, died recently at Adelaide
at the age of 10&. 1
is on a higher plane now than ever
before. Basketball is the hardest
game of all to officiate for officials
have helped to standardize offi
ciating.
Basketball has gone through dif
ferent evolutionary stages and with
each succeeding one the game is
becoming more scientific.
Few people are aware of how
universally the game Is played.
During the last few' weeks I have
received requests for basketball
lessons from the following coun
tries: Alaska. Porto Rico. Mexico.
Guam, and France Our service
teams have no doubt been the
greatest medium of spreading the
game.

Basketball is played In the fol-
lowing countries that we know of:
Alaska, Canadian Provinces, Hawaii.1
China. Japan. Porto Rico and oth
er South American countries, Cuba.
Panama. San Salvador. Spain.
Greece, Persia. Guam. England, j
France, Mexico and others.
In many of these countries the
game is played outside due mostly
to the warm climate. However,
playing facilities are increasing
with the popularity of the games
as manifested by an order received
from the Mexican government bv
the Nurre Plate Glass Company of
Bloomington. Ind., for four com
plete sets of glass bank boards.
Mexico sent a team to tour the
mid-west last year and it surprised
everyone with its ability.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2023271000/1944-09-22/ed-1/?sp=7&q=basketball&r=-0.292%2C0.134%2C1.281%2C0.682%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Specialists in Each
Barracks Plan
Fall Sports Program
k
Individual, Group Sports
Begin in Barracks;
Tourneys Planned
Complete Program of Fall and Winter Sports Planned for Enlisted Men
fan ana winter sports are being planned in a big way for
enlisted men on the Depot.
Under the leadership of Lt. (jg) Rov I. Carriker, recre
ation and welfare officer, and Lt. (jg) J. C. Hickey, officer
in charge of Naval Barracks recreation, a group of
and recreation specialists are working out the details
plan, which will provide recreational opportunities
fields.
athletic
for their
in many
Specialists Arrange
Nine Tournaments, 12
Other Activities Begin
Athletic specialists and recrea
tional directors in the various bar
racks are organizing tournaments
in nine different activities.
They are bowling, pocket bil
liards, touch football, horseshoes,
table tennis, volley ball, shuffle
board, badminton and boxing.
Barracks and Depot champions
will be decided through these
tournaments, and awards will be
given to the winners.
Refinishing of the gym floor in
the temporary recreation building
is the only thing holding up the
starting of 12 activities to be held
there.
Through instructions by athletic
specialists, the following activities
will begin:
Basketball, badminton, volley
ball, shuffleboard, tumbling, box
ing, bat ball, wrestling, combative
judo, weight lifting, table tennis
and calisthenics.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1916-02-27/ed-1/?sp=15&q=basketball&st=text&r=-0.294,-0.23,1.172,1.172,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKETBALL NOW
ONE OF AMERICAâ€™S
FAVORITE INDOOR
WINTER PASTIMES
Growth of Game in Alabama
and the South Has Kept
Stride Set by Eastern and
Northern States
AVERAGE OF FIFTY
TEAMS PRODUCED
IN VARIOUS STATES
Over 100 Teams Now Play
ing Under Organized
Heads as Compared With
Ten in 1906
My FRED BODEKER
The remarkable popularity of bas
ketball during the past 10 years has
elevated the game to the position of
one of the foremast in American sports.
The past decade has witnessed a seem
ingly impossible growth In the basket
game and even experts are puzzled over
the problem.
Basketball has proven itself to be
one of the best sports in every way
that help the American people to
amuse themselvefe in,the gymnasium.
Basketball makes no uncertain de
mands on heart and lungs and on en
durance generally. Basketball is a
game. Thatâ€™s allâ€”only a game. It is
not a combat nor a battle nor a fight*
as some people would term it. It is
just a game.
Authorities have often repeated the
statement that basketball does more
to form a man's character than any
other sport. The period of adolescence
is the time when basketball and sim
ilar games are played and when lifeâ€™s
habits are formed and the character
largely determined. Politics is a game
and so is almost any business, and the
people are merely players in the game.
And so is basketballâ€”it is a game and
one of the best.
DEVELOPS THE BODY
Basketball develops many parts of
the human body. It develops alertness,
gelt-control, skill, speed and brings ev
ery part of the body into action. The
game arouses the interest and enthu
siasm of every spectator. The simplic
ity and small quantity of apparatus
required, together with other chief
qualifications of the game, make it
one of the most valuable of our com
petitive games.
Basketball belongs to the large fam-
ily of games originated to amuse the
American public. It was first started
in 1891. Dr. James A. Naismtth, now
a member of the collegiate basketball
rules committee, was an instructor at
the Springfield Y. M. C. A. Training
school and undertook to devise an in
door game which would develop man
kind. Basketball was at first very sim
ple. Since then, however, the game has
undergone complete revision; but bas
ketball lovers all over the nation owe
to Dr. Naismith the honor of â€œinvent
ingâ€™â€™ the game.
Since 1891 basketball has made mar
velous strides. The game was adopted
by colleges, high schools, athletic as
sociations in all parts of the country.
The big eastern colleges first fell in
line and soon the movement spread to
the south. Beading southern colleges
and institutions quickly adopted the
game and by 1900 basketball was a
game that was beginning to be played
by all important institutions.
GROWTH IN 1906
In 1906 the game began to grow even
more popular. Athletic clubs in all parts
of the south were producing teams and
tights were being staged for the
â€¢'championships.â€ Not only in the south
was the game popular, but the middle
west and the eastern states were far
ahead. It Is roughly estimated that
something over an average of 60 teams
were being produced in every state in
the union or over 2400 teams were
playing organized basketball to say
nothing of the innumerable grammar
schools and independent teams that
numbered as many more.
But basketball did not stop its won
derful growth. The game has some un
seen power that attracted clubs, col
leges and schools to adopt it. As the
years passed the number playing the
game increased and by 1910 the num
ber playing in 1906. which was es
timated to have been over 240Â°, was
estimated to have been doubled, or
nearly 3000 teams. This does not
elude independent teams but omy
teams as high schools, athletic clubs,
colleges and other educational institu
tion
Dr. Joseph E. Raycroft. chairman of
he joint committee on basketball
ules. is quoted as saying that the
umber of teams playing basketball
I 1910 was over 7000. This, however,
considered by many to be too large,
onsidering that six men 5s ine aver
ge number of players on one team,
ver 42,000 men were playing in or
anlzed basketball in 1910.
In Alabama in 1906, the number of
tarns playing basketball was something
he 10 or less, which Included the Bir
slngham Athletic club, Birmingham
Ugh school, Mobile, Montgomery, and a
ew others. The effects of the growth
ver the nation took effect in Alabama
nd the number in 1910 jumped to nearly
3 teams. A few hight schools were
laying the game, being seriously handt
apped by the lack of an Indoor court,
phile almost every athletic club and
M. C. A. in the state was represented
y a team.
OVER 100 TEAMS
In 1*16, the beginning of the present
eason, which Is about to come to a very
uccessful close, the number playing in
his state Jumped to over 100. Over 60
igh schools are playing basketball, with
ImoBt 40 athletic clubs and other instl
utions of this kind. The game is played
y every grammar school In the larger
itles of the state, while countless teams,
.norganlzed as in the Y. M. C. A., and
lass teams of various educational ln
tltutions, are following the same exam
Not only in Alabama but in all parts
>t the country Is the game making
apld strides toward the top of the lad
ler as an indoor sport. The number
paying In the United States at the
n-esent is estimated to go over 23,000
earns, which means that about 156,600
leople are playing organized basketball
X this number Alabama can boast of
Jmoat 700 players, which, although be
nw a majority of the statee, is well in
he advanced list.
Add so it can be seen, Alabama with
ractically every other state in the' union
fast taking to basketball, and expert
rltlcs who have watched Its growth for
he past decade predict no decline In
ts power to attract the attention of
he apart loving publle.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062224/1957-12-27/ed-1/?sp=5&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.211,0.051,0.254,0.271,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Caesar Rodney School
News
Caesar Rodney School Calendar
â€”January, February and March.
Christmas vacation until January
2
Reminder: Friday, December 27,
Glee Club Dance, 8:00-11:30. Harry
Jarman's Orchestra. Semi-formal,
alumni, students, friends, guestsâ€”
90c stag, $1.50 per couple.
January
Thursday, January 2â€”8 p. m.â€”
Program as planned for December.
Sixth grade parents will serve re
freshments.
Saturday, January 4â€”8 p. m.â€”
Sophomore record dance.
Monday, January 6:9 a. m.â€”As
sembly for grades 4-5-6, "A Jour
ney Into the Forest;" 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) election
of officers and plans for the 10th
Annual Winter Band Concert.
Tuesday, January 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls at Milford; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys vs. Milford at
C. R.; 2:50 p. m.â€”High School As
sembly, "Science Barriers."
Thursday, January 9: 4-H Ban
quet in cafeteria.
Friday, January 10: 3:45 p. m.â€”
Basketball, Jr. H. S. vs. Felton at
C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
girls at Felton.
Tuesday, January 14â€”3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Laurel at
C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at Smyrna.
Friday, January 17â€”Six weeks
marking period endsâ€”report cards
due Friday, January 24; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Sud
lersville at C. R.
Tuesday, January 21: 3 p. m.â€”
Basketball. J. C. boys at Felton; 7
p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and girls
vs. Felton at C. R.
Friday, January 24: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Fel
ton at C. R..
Tuesday, January 28: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls vs. Mid
dletown at C. R.
Friday, January 31; 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and J. V. vs. Smyr
na at C. R.
February
Monday, February 3: 8 p. m.â€”B.
P. C. (Band Parents Club) in high
school office; Industrial Arts din
ner in cafeteria.
Wednesday, February 5; 8 p. m.
â€”Tenth Annual Winter Band Con
certâ€”students 50c; adults, 75c;
family, $1.00.
Thursday, February 6: 8 p. m.â€”
PTA.
Friday, February 7: 3:30 p. m.â€”
Basketball, girls and J. V. at Sea
ford; 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys and
J. V. at St. Andrews.
Monday, February 10â€”1:30 p. m.
â€”Kent County Student Council at
C. R.
Tuesday, February 11: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys and girls at Mid
dletown.
Wednesday, February 12: 3 p. m.
â€”Assembly, for grades 5 and 6,
band concert.
Friday, February 14: 3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Harrington.
Saturday, February 15: 7:30 p. m.
â€”7-1 and 7-2 boys in cafeteria.
Tuesday, February 18: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls and J. V. vs.
Seaford at C. R.; 7 p. m.â€”Basket
ball, boys and J. V. at Laurel.
Friday, February 21: 3:45 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls vs. Harrington
at C. R. 7 p. m.â€”Basketball, boys
and J. V. at Sudlersville.
Tuesday, February 25â€”3:30 p. m.
â€”Basketball, girls at Laurel; 7 p.
m.â€”Basketball, boys and J. V. vs.
St. Andrews at C. R.: 7 p. m.â€”
Basketball, boys at Milford; Six
Weeks Marking Period Endsâ€”Re
port cards due March 10.
March
Monday, March S: 8 p. m.â€” B. P.
c.
Tuesday, March 4: 7 p. m.â€”Bas
ketball, boys at Milford.
Wednesday, March 5; 12:45 p. m.
â€”Assembly for grades 5 and 6.
Thursday, March 6: 8 p. m.â€”PTA.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066314/1917-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.352,0.548,0.207,0.221,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TITLE IN BASKETBALL
Kansas City Team Defeats
Warrensburg in Final
Game, 62 to 27.
FAYETTE ENDS THIRD
HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL CHAMPIONS
Singer Is Individual Star
.With 24 Points Wil
liams Makes 20.
Kansas City Central .High School
won the state high school basketball
tournament by defeating Warrensburg
62 to 27, at the Rothwell Gymnasium
court last night This is Central's
third season without a defeat. Singer.
the Blue and White star forward, took
the ball after three seconds of play
and scored, the first field goal. Central
was never headed, but the game was
harder fought than the score indi
cates. The Kansas City team was easily
the superior of any of the other eight
teams and their victory was foretold
by basketball followers when they
were first seen in action. Singer was
the highest individual point scorer in
last night's game, with 24 points to
his credit, though Williams with 20
and Duvall with 14 pushed him hard
for the honor. Giltner, the Warrens
burg captain, tossed the ball through
the ring for 19 tallies. Dorland was
the only other Warrensburg man to
break into the scoring, making the
other 8 points. The score:
enirai etc; Warrenslmrs (27)
m 3lHIBIE&Vfl9Ki afllBBH
'GET BASKETBALL LETTERS
Committee oh Intercollegiate Athlet
ics Makes Awards.
The Committee on Intercollegiate
Athletics have recommended the
following men for basketball Ms:
Captain Fred Williams, Sam Shlrkey,
Harry Viner, C. H. Slusher, Kenneth
Shenard. P. B. Vogt and Jesse L.
Campbell.
The election of Jesse L. Campbell
as captain of next year's basketball
squad was approved. It was decided
to try and arrange a track meet with
Leland Stanford University, and, if
possible, to bring the meet to Colum
bia. The baseball eligibility list was
approved with the exception of four
men who were voted ineligible. Mr.
Brewer feels that these men, while
ineligible now, can later be placed in
the list of eligibles"
CAPITOL FIXTURE FUND GIYEN
faeMS U Be Use aj CeiurissteB
Bear for Seleetfeas.
E. w. Stephens, chairman of the
State Capitol Commission Board, says
that the Board has another big problem
before It In the baying of furniture
and fixtures for the new capital. The
legislature has voted an appropriation
of 300,000 for that purpose, but states
that selections must be made by mem-
bers of the board and not by
tenor decorator or advisor.
Fam Machiaery Class Tries Tntf
The farm machinery class was g
en some experience in plowing Tesfej
day when Prof. E. W. Lehmana'tiiJtC
out one of the University tractors f"
the field west of the poultry grwaay';.
Each man was permitted to handle'tfct
tractor and gang plows by Mmtrctc,
Five acres were plowed by the
dents.
Plant peonies and Iris now.
bia Floral Co., phone 920.
Colum-C-179
FREE
Development of
Films purchased
Tn&Kri Sfore
all
at
Top Row, Left to Bight: Coach C. CHornaday; Williams, Center;. Coach
J. -U. Young. Bottom Row: DuTal, Bight Forward; Sanders, Left Guard;
Singer, Left Forward and Bamsar, Right Guard, Who Did Sot Make the
Trip to Columbia.
filth, Charleston;
Singer, If
Duval, rf
Williams, c
rg, Herm. Smith. Hankln
Webster Groves;
sixth, Sedalia.
Central will be awarded a large
bronze wall .placque and the other
teams smaller placques.
Kansas City Central and Warrens
burg qualified for the finals Satur
day morning by defeating Fayette
and Webster Groves, D scores of 51
to 7 and 24 to 14 respectively.
Charleston defeated Hannibal 2S to
Charleston at the hands of Warrens
imrg, 25 to 14. The work of Spencer
and Lincoln for Webster Groves In the
first conflict is worthy of mention,
their combined efforts netting 29 of the
35 tallies for the victors. Dorland
Hanna and Giltner starred for War
rensburg in the second game.
ALL-STATE TEAMS SELECTED
cTllerb. smith10 ln tne first consolation game played
j rf.nanna Saturday morning. Sedalia defeated
Uaskets from floor Sinrpr s Tin mi r I the Fairfax fivfl 27 in 14
"imams, ju, sanaers Dorland 4. Gilt-
Sanders, Is
isnrte. rg
ner 5. Baskets on free triali Sincer a
Giltner 9. Free trials misled Singer 4,
uiuuer i. x ouis called un Singer 3,
Duvall 3, Williams 2, Sanders 4. Burke 1,
Dorland 3, Hanna 3. Herb. Smith 2. Gilt
ner 2. Herm. Smith 3, Bankin 2.- Referee
Bryant (Missouri).
In the finals of the consolation se
ries Charleston defeated Sedalia IS
to 11. This placed Charleston in fifth
place and gave the cellar position to
Sedalia.
Third place was won by Fayette
who defeated Webster Groves, 20 to
7 in the most hotly contested game of
the series. The placing of the first
six team's in the series follows: First,
Kansas City Central; second, War
rensburg; third. Fayette; fourth.
The games Friday night brought
four learns to the semifinals in the se
ries. Kansas City Central had qual
ified for this round in the Friday aft
ernon games by defeating Fairfax In
a one-sided game, 50 to 11. Fayette1
also defeated Xeosha in the afternoon,
but was forced to beat the Sedalia five,
which had a bye in the first round,
before gding to the semifinals. This
was the last of the Friday night games.
These two teams were the leaders of
the Central District and fought a hard
game, 25 to 17.
The other games Friday night re
sulted in a victory forsWebster Groves
over Hannibal, 35 to 4, and a defeat of
3 Members of Victorious Central High
Team on First Squad.
The five officials of the state high
school basketball tournament, Fred
Williams. George Bryant and John F.
Miller, referees; Anton Stankowski,
scorekeeper; and Samuel Church.
timekeeper, have picked the following
all-state high school teams:
First Teas
Forward Singer, Central (captain)
Forward Dorland, Warrensburg.
Center Williams, Central.
Guard Sanders, Central.
Guard Giltner, Warrensburg.
Second Team
Forward Duval, Central (captain)
Forward Spencer, Webster Groves.
Center Skillman, Fayette.
Guard Burke, Central.
flnarA VTnrlo Wnhstor Clrrrrna T T
..u. W,V.J.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020422/1954-02-04/ed-1/?sp=9&q=basketball&st=text&r=0.192,0.483,0.176,0.188,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>SCHOOL
REPORTER


On Wednesday, January 20, af
ter two practices, the Smyrna
F. F. A. basketball teams met with
Caesar Rodney, Milford, Harring
ton and Felton teams at Caesar
Rodney for the first tournament of
the season. The tournament con
sisted of having three gamesâ€”two,
varsity and one J. V.â€”played at
the same time until eventually all j
were eliminated but one in each
division, Milford w i n n i ng the j
championship for both Varsity and
J. V. Smyrna's varsity was beaten!
F. F. A. Basketball

by Caesar Rodney. The Smyrna
J.V. played against Milford for theâ– 
final round. Refreshments were
served by the Caesar Rodney
Chapter.
February Calendar of Events
February 2, Basketball game at
home with Wilmington Friends, I
3:30.
February 3, Basketball game at
home with Chestertown, 7:00.
j
February 4, 1st Semester Report
Cards.
February 5, Basketball game at
home with Caesar Rodney, 7:00.
February 9, Personnel Club As
sembly 1:25.
February 9, Basketball game at
home with Harrington, 7:00.
February 11, P.T.A. meeting
high school cafeteria, 8:00.
February 12, Basketball game at
Dover, 7:00.
February 13, Kent County Queen
of Hearts Dance at Harrington
High School, 8:00.
February 16, Basketball game at
St. Andrews, 3:30.
February 19, Basketball game at
home with Middletown, 7:00.
February 22, Yearbook material
to be sent to publisher.
February 23, Basketball game at
Chestertown, 7:00.
February 26, Basketball game at
home with Milford, 7:00.
The Smyrna High School Eagles 1
basketball team will play its next
three games on the home c o u r t
which should prove advantageous
to the Red and White. The Eagles
Basketball
will play host to the Caesar Rod
ney team tomorrow night. In the*r
previous game the Riders beat the
Eagles by ten points, but Coach
Homey expects a reversal of form
on the home court.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>




  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-badminton</id>
    <results>

      <result>
	<id>/https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1886-04-04/ed-1/?sp=12&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How the Young People of New York
ltclux Strict Formality at
Badminton*
The Way in Which n Howlinjj swell
Getsilimsell Ip for the Ilariu
less Game.
New York Letter: 1 have read a heap
within a month in the society columns ot
our city dailies and weeklies, as well as in
out-of-town letters, concerning one Noa
Don. who seems to be accepted as the
spring-tide belle of Fifth avenue. Non
sense! This is too big a town, and even the
limits of the most pretentious society are
too spacious, to permit any single girl to
pet unquestioned supremacy. I have seen
this precious creature, moreover, and 1 am
telling you Cor keeps that she is no such
thing as the accounts make her out. I'm
not denying her all the wit at repartee to
iredited to her. She truly has touguc as
iliarp and quick as ever 1 heard: but what
I am impressing on you this minute- is that
a Queen of Swelldom, if we ever do crown
one. will be perfection as to dress.
Now. Noa Don is merely a traveled
and educated gill, who has been round the
world to pick up conceits that startle and
amuse us; who has come into New York
with family connections that give her en
trance to the charmed circles of wealth, and
Â«he makes her witty commentsâ€” as
nave been so extensively reported with
considerable cleverness; but when 1 have
described her as she presented herself at
the Academy of Music the other evening
yon will understand why I won't concede
that she ought to be elevated into public
view as supremely fine. She ought to huve
been arrayed in fashionable evening
costume, of course, because she sat in a box
along with women so dressed. But she ap
parently aimed to be
DISTISCTIVKLY ODD.
Her hair was loose and fluffy, and the
only ornamentation or attempt at coiifure
was a curious Bori of gilded thing not un
like a crown -set on the top of her head.
Her dress was pale amber >atm, and its cut
was not unlike that of the current morning
gown. Her anus wene completely covered
by sleeves and gloves, but her nmiapn was
law 111 a Bquariah shape, outlined by a
Btand-up frill of lace, as little in the fashion
cf Queen Elizabeth. No. no; Noa Don
can not be officially admired, no matter
how smart her sayings, until she robes her
self in accordance with strict fashiou's
rules.
What a jolly row Miss Cleveland has
been kicking up. by the way. about low
corsages. Still, she is awfully right in con
demning some of the nudity, and
you will remember that 1 have been
doing the same missionary sort of
work for several seasons. i*he makes
n special point of it that the line of bareness
shall bo high enough bo cover all of the dis
tinct feminity. He* Idea is that bare amis,
an. l so much Of the breast as happens to be
flat, are not an immodest exposure: but as I
looked up from the perusal of her letterâ€” it
was just before Starting tor B recent ion. and
a bevy of tirls were randy to goâ€” and my
eyes fell on a maiden of exceeding meager
nests in curvatures, I said to myself:
'â€¢Where would the line be dra*vn across
that creature if it were lowered in obedience
to .Miss Cleveland's proposition?''
BOUBKHOLO AIM l( I.LS
are so frequently asked about by a*ycor
respondents that I here give, by general
way of answer, a number of points. Pil
low-shams arc used in preference to fancy
trimmed slip overs. Lace curtains never
go out of fashion. They I.re used for
parlors, reception and dlning-rooma,
bedrooms, and. in fact, for all the
rooms of a houso. if preferred to the many
novelties in what is called .Madras lace.
really a muslin brocbe curtain, in various
colors to suit the furnitures of the room for
which they are intended. The moat htfh*
[onablc watch chain worn is a short fob
chain, with a ball at the end. which inavbe
plain, chased or set with Jewels. We did
not know that they were called Queen
Anne watch-chains, but that is probably
the name by which they arc known to some
fashion writers and to jewelers. Grena
dines are BOperceded by canvas or etamine
fabrics nowadays, but are still worn by a
few conservative ladies. Great variety in
form and color of upholstery, draperies and
all the pieces of furniture in a room is per
mitted by fashion at present. In fact, what
is called by some writers the eloctric room
that is. a room furnished with choice
furniture representing various modern or
medieval periods of art furnishings, and
harmoniously combining several subdued
colors with one prevailing tint or tone is
considered the height of taste. But it re
quires
OHKA.T JUDGMENT
in selecting the pieces of furniture, the cur
tains, carpets, decorations and ornaments
of such a room. There is danger of mak
ing it look like a furniture dealer's collec
tion. The rage for decorated china, or
delft, is on the wane, but when plain white
is used it is selected of the finest ware, and
is sometimes made decorative in the fluting
or waving of the pieces in dotting, scallop
hie. denting or flagreting the edges, the
handles and borders of the cups, dishes,
sauces, plates and side pieces. The most
exquisite and fanciful shapes of antique,
niediseval and modern pottery are chosen,
all done in white. Then, if color is de
manded on the table, it is supplied by flow
ers, all one color if possible, by fancy col
ored glass and open drawn work lines in
the tablecloth, showing the bright color
of the fine flannel cloth placed under
the white one. Sometime a long mat
of velvet or plush of the color of the
flowers and glass on the table is placed
down the center of the same, and on this
are placed the eperjoie, a central glass etna
for tlowers and lruit, and the little bisque.
j tiuures holding btekete t;dl of bon-bons,
candied fruits and motto ptpan, the fancy
glass tlowor receivers and flower-!
and choice pieces of silver. For a toilet set.
decorated china, or. lu'tter still, fancy cut
glass, is the correct thing.
I'Koi'i.i: Mo !maÂ».im;
that the fMMR men and women of Xew
York society are stiil and formal in their
Manners would have been somewhat sur
prised at the ciowdot vonng peoplt who
gathered before 1 O*deek feeteVdajf after
noon to play bidminton in a Â«|iucr little
Fourth avenue buildinK- Nobody wn> v,.|,.
(>us for an instant, and chaff seeniol to Ik>
tbeorderof the hour. Over in one corner
sat four maids as upricht as dolls
and as solemn as East [pitta fakirs.
The? conversed in low tones and seemed
utterly oblivious to the tfume. .So d;d
mo>t of the others for that matter, and it
didn't take a voiy shrewd observer to dis
cover that bandminton. as played" in New
York, consists ni conversation*; to a very
large extent. Interspersed with a few cur
sor, bits of hit and mi-play with the
racquets. There were no chaperones at all
at this RUM, and it amounted to a merry
tort ot frolic Cor two hours bj the middle
of the day. li wm MMuing to Hstento
the talk, tor the Kugiish accent, which bj
affeoted so laboriously by some of the so
ciety people, m picked an and dropped
pieci-Â«'ly as fancy dictated by the gor
geously attired people who made badmin
ton an excuse lor Betting without
being oppressed by the pres
ence of chaperone dnenneti Hut just
let me show \ou how superior bolles are to
beans when it comes to sightliness at play.
Tbe biggest swell of the dandies arrived an
hour before time. He was a small man
w ith prominent teeth, rather a pallid face,
and a pah* ol shadowy side whiskers. He
penneed up to the door of the liiuisy frame
structure, and nodded carelessly to a stolid
Englishman who stood by the dÂ«Â»or with a
straw in his mouth and his hands in his
pm fcete.
"Good mawnin". Fowbes." said the new-
Coiiier. screwing* a elng inlO one of
bb) weak ejea, and glaring hard at t lie at
tendant; "is any one beahf
â€¢â€¢Not yet. sir, "'^liuilK' attendant, respect
fully.
"Aw." muttered the fOUg man compla
en ly; "1 am the tirst one then."' Baring
arrived at this deep and logical conclusion,
after
AX KI.AnonATH COl*Rhe east a and transparent smile at
Forbes, and drifted through the doorway
into the barn-like structure. Here he cast
a critical view at a net which extended
across the Moor, went to one of a series of
small lockers, and took therefrom a rac
quet. Then he ascended the small >uir
way to the gallery, where there were I few
dressing- rooms, and presently emerged in
all the glory ol white llaunel knickerbock-
ers and shirt, with long red stockings, a
blue nnd white silk Norfolk jacket, and a
blue worsted Tarn O'Shanter cap perched
artfully upon his rather peculiar-looking
head. Around one of his slim wrists there
was a broad leather band clasped with four
buckles a scheme by which champion
badminton aud tennis players strengthen
wrists that have been strained by overplay.
The single glass now hung over his breast.
He danced about fora moment to limber up
his legs, and then, stepping out in the iu
closure across which the net was placed,
he slipped oflE his little cube into which was inserted a rim
of feathers and tossed it in the air. When
it came diving downward, with bullet-like
directness he caught it deftly on the end of
bin racquet and sent it into the air agate.
building and imparted the Still 1
km look to it that a conservators
midsummer. Occasionally the .in.,
car bell could be heard but nobody luliruiutl
into the Badminton club. The only signs
<Â»f life were supplied by the nimble young
swell who danced carelessly about in the
sunshine, batting the feathered toy up to
ward the roof. With the rich colors of his
costume and his nimbleness he might have
been tnistaden by a buloonist peering from
above for a huge tropical bird of some cay
but gawky sort disporting itself grotesquely
in the sun.
THE SOLITARY
young; badminton player who was romping
so joyously was a howling swell of a very
high order. He didn't look like a man of
pint importance, but socially his position 1
is enviable. A man who at the age of j
twenty-eiirht can boast of membership in
the Summerset club, of Boston; the Savage
club, of London; the Jockey club of Paris,
and the Union. Knickerbocker and Union
League clubs, of New York: has a racing
â– table of his own and spends SGO.OOO a
year without earning the reputation of
being a spendthrift or a fool, must neces
sarily amount to something in the woild of
society. lie seemed as happy as a clam at
high tide, batting away there skillfully,
when a brougham drove up to the door and
a young woman and her maid bustled in he
gave a yell of meeting that was quite un
dignified, and reminded one strongly of a
street Arab.
â€¢â€¢Late again. Miss Agatha," he chirped,
happily. "Ton me soul it is quite heart
rending for a man of my conscientiousness
and t lustful nature to receive these disap
pointments every play-day."
''Indeed, you are a paragon,"' said the
jrirl. smiling brightly, and aoastaglsÃŸf wraps
t" the maid. "It was the fault of mamma
Ibis morning. She was desperately blue
when she irot out of bed, and so she climbed
bark in again. Then she insisted upon my
rending to her until she felt more composed,
and there you are."
She had scarcely finished speaking when
there was a great chatter and bustle about,
and half a dozen people hurried in. Two
of the guls were in full tennis rig. and
when one of the men slipped off his long
ulster he revealed the fact that he. too. had
put on his play-day togs before suiting
from home.
WHAT STRUCK ME HARDEST.
However, was the fact that the belles
were so much more shapely and graceful
than the beaux. More than one bony fellow
had on what 1 believe actors call "Mats."
That is to Kay, their legs were artificially
enlarged and straightened by padding. No
till was jruilty of such deceit. But 1 don't
mind telling you just what girl; do in their
One when costuming for badminton or ten
nis. The fashion is to wear soft woolen
skirts retelling to the ankles, and presuma
bly with no petticoats underneath. The in
tention is to leave the legs clear for the ex
erciseâ€”also distinctly outlined as part of
the mend symmetry that constitutes so
much of the pleasant sightliness of the
â– port. Well, every player of good sense
puts on exactly as many flannel skirts as
will produce the desired bulk. No speota
toi can tell whether there be one or six lay
ers of the soft fabric; but anyhow he never
sees the protuberance of a knee-pan or the
sharpness of a shinboue. Clara Belle in
Cincinnati Enquirer.
AVliy a Bottton Woman Wept.
Bostou Budget.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047239/1886-10-13/ed-1/?sp=5&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PLAYING BADMINTON
A TWO HOJRS FROLIC FOR NEW
YORKS SOCIETY YOUNG FOLKS
Arrlrnl of the UlcucstHwolI of tlio Dun
silo Aflor nil ISlnbornte Cniirne of
Thought Sixty Thtinsnnil u Ycnr nutl
i llio ltesiilta Thormf
People wlio lnmglno tlmt tlio young men
and women of Now York society tiro still
mul formal In tholr manners would have
been somewhat surprised at tlio crowd of
young pcoplo who met together ono
nftornoon to play badminton In a queer
little Fourth avenue building
It didnt take a very shrowd obsorvcr
to discover that badminton as played In
Now York consists of conversation to a
very largo extent Interspersed with n fow
cursory bits of hit nnd rclsplay with tho
racquets Tlicro wore no chnperones at
nil at this gamo nnd it amounted to a
merry sort of a frolic for two hours In tho
middle of tho day It was amusing to
listen to the talk for tho English accent
which Is affected so laboriously by soino
of tho aocloty people was picked up nnd
dropped precisely as fancy dictated by tho
gorgeously attired pooplo who made bad
minton an excuse for meeting without
being oppressed by tho presence of chnpur
one duennas
A DKEP AND LOCIICAL CONCLUSION
Tlio biggest swel of tho dandlos arrived
an hour before time Ho was a small man
with prominent teeth rather n pallid face
and a pair of shadowy sldo whiskers Ho
pranced up to the door of tho flimsy frame
structure and nodded carelessly to a stolid
Englishman who stood by the door with n
straw In his mouth and his hands in his
pockets
Good mnwnln Fowbes said tho now
comcr screwing a slnglo glass Into ono of
his weak eyes and glaring hard at the at
tendant Is any ono heahf
Not yet sir said tho attendant re
spectfully
Aw muttered tho young man otm
plncently I am tho llrst ono thon Hav
ing arrived at this deep nnd logical con
clusion after an elaborate course of
thought ho cost n ghostly and transparent
sinllo at Forbes mid drifted through tho
doorway Into the burn liko structure
Hero he cast a critical view at a not which
extended across the floor went to ono
of a sorlos of small lockors and took
therefrom a racquet Then he ascended
the smidl stairway to a gallery vhoro
there were a fow dressing rooms and pres
ently emerged In all tho glory of whlto
flannel knickerbockers and shirt with long
red stockings a blue nnd whlto silk Nor
folk Jacket nnd a blue worsted Tom
OShantcr cap perched artfnlly upon his
rather peculiar looking head I Around one
of his slim wrists there was a broad leathor
band clasped with four buckles a scheme
by which champion badminton nnd tenuis
players strengthen wrists that have been
strained by overplay Tho single glass
now hung over his breast Ho dnnccd
about for a moment to limber up his legs
and then stepping out into tho Inclosuro
across which tho net was placed ho
slipped off his silk jacket produced n llttlo
cube into which was inserted a rim of
feathers and tossed it in tho air When it
came diving forward with bullet llko
directness ho caught It deftly on the end
of his racquot and scut it Into tho air
again
A HOWLINO SWELL OK IIIOII OllDCB
Tho solitary young badminton player
who was romping so joyously was a howl
ing swell of a very high order Ho didnt
look llko a man of great Importance but
socially his position Is enviable A man
who at tho agtuf 23 spends ftWOOO a year
without earning the reputation of being a
spendthrift or n fool must necessarily
amount to something in the world of
society Ho seemed as happy ns a clam at
high tldo batting away there skillfully
when a brougham drove up to tho door
and a young woman nnd her maid bustled
v in ho gave n yell of greeting that was quite
undignified nnd reminded ono strongly of
a street Arab
Late again Miss Agatha ho chirped
happily Ton me soul It is quite heart
rending for n man of my conscientious nnd
trustful nature to recolvo theso disap
pointments every plny dny
Indeed you are a paragon said tho
girl smiling brightly and tossing her
wraps to tho maid It was tho fault of
mamma tlis morning Sho was desper
ately bluo when sho got out of bed and so
she climbed back ngnln Then sho In
sisted upon my reading to her uutll sho
felt moro composed and there you nre
She had scarcely finished speaking when
thero was a great chatter and bustle about
und n halt dozen people hurried In Two
of tho girls were In full tennis rig and
when ono of tho men slipped off his long
ulster he revealed tho fact that he too
had put on his play day togs before start</text>
      </result>

            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1890-03-09/ed-1/?sp=18&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  PLAYERS OF BADMINTON.
JWO CLUBS WHER1- THE WRDS" ILV >VEB
THE NETS.
A DESCRIfTION Of THE GAJfE-IT- POPTJIiAltlTT
AS A I.KNTl-V AMUSEMI \T >*a
pkople wi llesown is
The pame of badminton, "f nli games "t akill. is
pcrhaps loast kti .wa by iho publle i.t large. It
is ncarly as mueh a game "i egilitj and quick
ncss as iciinis, and, altho igb the Mercite required
is not Tlolent, thecnjoymenl experlenced i.y tbe
playcrs in a cloaely oontested game la Jui
kcen as m tho more wldely known -istor game.
lat nn Indlfferenl player badminton i- much the
r.etter form nt sp-'M. and iho women w o go io
lor it are mdre entbuBlaatic iu it* supporl than
the most eonfirmed playcra -.i tennia The
liko it becauae it givea them an nppetite. and iu
this it nevei f.ii!-*. Cocktalla ire i t. to I c com
jiaicl with H- Sherry and bitters hecomes na
aotbing, nnd ;i good dinnei preceded bj badniin
tBadminton may be played either <-'i the lawn
or ladoors. ln Ita Indoor fonn it is. and is likely
to renniin. Sew-York'a fashionable L??nten paatime
aml n- auch ii certainly deservcs praise.
'Ih.' game aa now played i-- nol ..t greal i??
tlquity, oi il ll la, there ia no deflnlte reoord of
the lni't, lt ia "I Anglo-Indlan origln, and baa
been siii.o 1E. i u favorite with -.ngllab oJheera i"
India. The form ol game played ln Sew-York
ri..es not diffei materlallj fr..m thal played bj
tho Aiiin.ilai'i'l Badminton Club In India. and the
rulA* now adopted ure pructically tlie -ainc
Tho BBaterlala for badminton aro differcnl
iboee uaed for tei igb the gai
mlghl appeai simil r n e net la from two feel
to two feel si_ ii cl es in bre idth, ai I ln_t<
N-i.'i- sei upon tlu ng poles
nnd ia 1 ung al a distam c ol from Hve i"
j et to six fe 1 from tbe surfa. e oi Ihe court.
Inste i-l ol balls, sli ittlecocka, or bir la," oa they
nrc teehnlcally c lled, are used. Tlie racq cts
nr b it* with which l aboul are
rencrally ol a Lighter weighl and souiewli kl smaller
than the ordinory tennis i icque.,
tennla ruc<] et can be For in
door pl ig a i ird" wei ;1 i incc is
iiaed, bul oui or?, un ac. wind, i ce
weighliLg. an ounce and three-eeTered with rubber to prevenl uu urj from nio__t
urc, is I'.-fi-.
Vl_vr>'
Cil's OF THE "BIRDS
In dreaa ry for
pla- ii Iminlon. Tbe exei bi*. nol
lent. tennla Hannels cuu l*e and
even U nnis shoes re d. lf ln\v
aro woi feli aoles should bc
ctiosen. Women should wear lo"s<- t sligl tly
.liortcr tharj the invc tional aa i
af aome aofl Bes tuaterial thal will nol Intei
fciv wll "ii.
l s of the court musl be Ln a
tneas ;rc delermlned by the lize ol the Boor oi
la\\;i npon to lie 1 dd out. Oue1 w
elghl U"il ki i md twenty feel broad
but the ed by the
N< xx- ork I'
nn elevatl :i "i Iee1 it answers thi
is as geod aa ui I 11 iu.ir .--i
aat carefully with chalk lines, oi lf _
Mr::,. i and I.
Frn::i one to i ir peraona play <>n a aiie, and
t!.e ahuttlee. k or bird^ niuM in
Beturaed on a "volley" or before lo
court Burface. The "blrds" are sei ed and re
t i
cepi that if the shuttlecock falla to the eourl
gorface it ia ni <1 a nii__ to I plnyei
laila to return il and lo bia aiile. Tbe servicc is
from t!. i c ia, 1 lie
pl;iV,T bi fe within u section
?i i two i.-i t und sx, ineliea from the
earaer. Th* divisiona f the eourt* nr.- onlj oh
Berve.l on the aerve, aml the playera can Btand
wliere tliey plea>e on tbeir own si ;'ft?i it
Tlie Bhuttk I ser ed a tlu lt falla
Wlthln the lines i I cn ice c< url as in teiuiia,
0n,l ele r of tlu c! ropea and poata I tlie et
it touelied in tbe gervice and the "I'nd" falla
ovor. the Btroke ia ealled a, "lot" and docs not
connt -.r- ki er.
Iii p|ay, b< wi vi i tbe touchintj ol the :i<-i by the
glitiitlri tt g ea over counta aa a o -1
ati.. II the i ichi I I tlie racqui
nel with
tbeir racqueta, tlie st
JVo i..nli. p U hand out, and in all
?birdB lallin- upon boundary linea re re
?arded as faulta, both iu acrvice and in play.
fifteen point* eonatitnte the game. No over
liain! -i:. ia all iwcd ii the eervice. ln ja-l_
Ing wbether pl yei I re i ied over the net,
it is ajwi noticcd il the bird ia st: ick be
lote ii haa eroaaed Ihe nel aml merel> been foi
lowcl over by the raequel <>f player. Iu
this eaae il li i t ud stroke, bul il the racquet
itsolt tou il ea the nei tbe pl ia cotinti i a miss
The game ol b dmini >u introdu ed In thia
country .luiin. the xx.i.t.-r 1-1- b I'.y
ar.l t larke aad E. Langiton Wilks, and ihe nu
eleua ot the Im New-York liudunniou Club w_?
then formed.
THE OEEST OF THE CI.l'B.
The Badminton Clah was 1I10 pioneer. nnd its
luoeess has iicn much greatei than Ife
Ciarke aad Wll** dared h-iix- when they in1r>>
duced the pamo and began to Interesl othera ln
lt. The menilK-ishii) in 187*. was forty, and tho
flret gamos wcic played in the aruioiy buildin*.
nt Thii'iv-'iftl. st. and Broadway. Intereai m
the game eteadily Increased, and the memberablp
crew until 1884, when il numbered 100.
Tbe lub then disbanded, and in I tner*
was no playing. In I8S- ibe elub was
i/,-il with seventy-flve memtiers, thal nu mber
hcing the limit. The club waa governed ?y
eommittee until 18.7. when n was tbougiu au
visable to i and an executive eommit?
tee This waa done. tbe membership Umil waa
,hMt,,;,,',> veiimi,
ization haa had a regular club e-.v.-m
W en the 71si Reg.?nt nioved to _?*??
Fort\ ftfth-ftl and Broadwa
n n.oved with lt, aml th en- by game I
itional facilities for succe__.uUy playing i w
game.
  </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065075/1891-06-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A GAME FOR ALL SEASONS.
It Is Called "liadiulnton" ud Cuuie From
England.
Badminton was invented, or origin
ated, whichever you please, in England,
but owes its present rules to the Ah
medabad Badminton club of India,
Which has practically revived the sport.
It is a modification of lawn tennis, with
some important differences, as will be
seen further on, and has the advantage
that it can be, and generally is, played
in-doors. This make3 it both a suramet
and winter game.
Tho dimensions of the court must be
decided in a great measure by the capa
bilities of the room in which the game
is played. Tho best size Is one twenty
eight feet long by twenty feet broad.
The courts should bo marked off by
means of pegs and strings, or better,
when possible, by white chalk lines oe
the floor, and divided in the following
way: At each end ol the ground are
two courts, ten feet square, while the
center is formed by a piece of neutral
ground eight feet broad by twenty feet
long. On each of these outer lines of
the neutral ground and in the center
are placed tho posts which support tho
net The net, which is two feet to two
feet six inches deep, is suspended at a
height of six feet from the ground, and
firmly held by guy ropes attached to
posts.
The racquets used in Badminton, to
be easily and quickly Wielded, should
be lighter than those used in lawn ten
nis, and consequently smaller. A shut
tlecock is used instead of a ball, and
may be large or small, according to tho
wish of the players.
In its general line, Badminton is a
game played in the same fashion as
lawn tennis, with tho exception that
from one to four persons may play on a
side, and that tho shuttlecock must be
returned on the volley. Tho shuttle
cock is served and returned under tho
same provisions, except that, of course,
if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
it Is counted as a miss to the player
missing it, and to his side. The servico
shall be from the "service-corner," tho
server and receiver each standing with
both feet within their respective quad
rants until the shuttlecock is struck.
The divisions of the respective courts
are only observed in the serve or first
hit; after that, the partners may stand
where they please, on their side of tha
net The shuttlecock must be served
in such a way that it falls clear over the
net, without touching the net, ropes or
posts, and falls inside the lines of the
service-court If the net Is touched in
service and tho shuttlecock falls over,
the stroke is considered as a "let," and
does not count as a fault against the
person serving. In play, however, the
touching of the net by the shuttlecock,
when it falls over, is counted as good
stroke. If the net is touched by the
racquets of the players, or if they reach
over the net with their racquets, tho
stroke counts against them. Two faults
puts "hand out" In all cases a shuttle
Cock falling on any of the boundary
lines Is regarded as a fault, as if it had
fallen outside Of the boundary lines,
both in service and play.
Iifteen points constitute the game.
In service no overhand stroke is allow
ed. The shuttlecock is judged by where
it strikes and not by where it lies after
striking. In judging whether a player
has reached over tho net, the umpire
should bo careful to note if the shuttle
cock Is struck before it has crossed the
net and not by the racquet of the play
or, which is naturally carried forward
by the impetus of the stroke and which
might arrive at a slight angle over the
net, although the shuttlecock itself was
struck on the correct side. If, however,
the net is touched by the racquet the
stroke counts against the player, wheth
er the shuttlecock was struck on the
right side of the net or not
As will be seen from the description,
Badminton requires agility and a quick
eye, rather than great strength, and it
will be found to be a game at which
girls can play with pleasure and profit
Golden Days.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045604/1891-05-31/ed-1/?sp=9&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IrHE NET AND RACKET.
badminton Has Not Driven
Tennis From Favor.
BOSSIP OF THE CHAMPIONS.
I y Mabel Cahill, the John L. Sullivan
â€¢f the Xew York Club, and Other
i Great Flayers.
1
i jriw YORK. May 25.â€”[Special Corre
jpoodence.Jâ€”The tennis season of 1891 has
fairly begun, and from present appear
ances it will be the liveliest one that has
aver been known in this country. There
was a prospect earlier in the season that
badminton might supplant the older game
in favor, but every one concerned now
scouts the possibility of such a result. No
one, naturally, takes a keener interest in
the question than the makers of tennis
goods, and they report the largest advance
tale* on record. It is one of the not to be
forgotten consequences of the popularity
of lawn tennis that the manufacture and
nleof neta, rackets, lawn markers, shoes
and uniforms has become a great industry.
It is only a few years since all these goods
were imported from England, the home of
fee game; now they are practically all
Bade here, and thÂ» business amounts to
something like $10,000,000 a year to the
trade. This is looking at the other side of
the sport, but the point of view is not an
unimportant one.
The clubs in and about New York are in
nnmfctr almost legion, and they are pre
paring busily for championship events,
mcticaliy the season begins with Decora
tion day, the month of fine weather before
that date being given np to practice play
ing. Of course, play begins earlier South.
The Washington City tournament for the
championship of the Southern states was
held in the middle of May. Tomorrow
the New York Tennis Club will hold its
spring games, and from now to the end of
the season in October there will be a
tournament every dayâ€”for not a summer
hotel of any size is without its tennis
courts, the smaJlest villages have their
clubs, and matches and return matches
t are shrewdly relied upon to keep up the
interest in the game.
Undoubtedly the success of tennis is
OLLIE CA MPBELL.
largely due to the fact that men and
women can play it together. For flirta
tion purposes it may not quite eoual the
sedate and sluggish game of croquet,
but for a judicious combination of
sport and opportunities for tete-a-tetes
its equal has never been invented.
Indeed, tennis is the ideal ladies' game.
As it requires agility rather than strength
to play tennis, there is no reason why
women should not play quite as well as
men, if it were not for the perpetual haudi
cap ot skirts. As it is, an active young
woman is about a match for a stout and
middle-aped man, with equal practice, and
some of the l>est women players can hold
their own with any but the very best men.
i his is a test not to be recommended,how
ever, as the practice of playing with one of
the other sex rather tends to break a man
up. as he is divided between his gallantry
and his desire to excel. Thus it may easily
happen that a man will show tip in better
form at the end of a season with compara
tively little practice with men than if he
had considerable careless playing with
women. Championship games are, of
course, always between players of the
â€¢tne sex.
â€¢Since Scars, of Boston, who was an ex
fi.>rdinary tennis player, met with a dis
cing accident, the honors of the game
Jwe rested with the Brooklyn players
Henry \V. Stocum, jr., son of General ll!
W. Slocum, the champion of iw>, and Oli
"Ollie" Campbell, the present
bolder ot the championship, both having
park in past years,
though Mr. Slocum is ;IOR a member of
P:. George's Club, of New York. There is
perhaps no place in the country where bet
ter provision is made for tennis playing on
large scale than at Prospect park, and
there are few days in spring or summer
when a considerable number of games are
lot going on there simultaneously.
The frequency of va ant lots in the resU
yace sections of Brooklyn rather favors
KINKY W. STOCFM. *R
information of small neighborhood clubs,
Asocial amusement rather than tine
**y the result.
Jill!! orlt Vf 3 the younc woman
fÂ«g l f rather expected to win chief chain-
honors this summer. This is
Mabel K. Oahiil, of the Net York
lennis Club. Miss Cahill is an
woman ami won lame in the old
nir\ at tennis tournaments before com
lhl* Bhe is a vigorous, aihletic
younp woman, with merry, iaugh
yes, ana quick, viÂ« -rous movements.
It4mlv r^ Sen 10 ,^r woman's cham-
I P**nn P h 3 K Will not
withom
t n l her s:s!
amp iÂ° nfhll> for <*oubks. Miss
VA probabiy play in double# wiU\
SIXTEEN PAGES.
Miw Ballantine, of the New York club.
Miss Robinson, of Staten Island,
Mrs Morgan, of Short Hill*. N. J.,
the Misses Kiting. Frazer and Temple, of
Westchester county, and Miss Colby, of
Orange, N. J., are among the famous play
ers who may contert for the honors with
Miss< ah:i! and the Roosevelt sisters. Of
course, there will be dark horses, too, who
at the last moment mav appear to wrest
the leadership away from the well-known
plavers. It is always more difficult to
predict women's piaying than men's.
They have more time for practice, they
are quite as numerous, if not more so. and
they are far less likely to enter champion
ship contests than men, even if quite pro
ficient. Thus local pride may almost at
any time force to the front some splendid
player before unheard of outside of her
county. It is the peculiarity of the plav
ers of both sexes that they are at their
best while quite young and do jiotlong
retain their supremacy.
Badminton came to the front last winter
as an indoors game, for which it was well
adapted by the smallness of the court re
quired. A tennis court is 78 feet by 27
wider than an ordinary city lot and nearly
as deep. The badminton court is only 44
feet by 20, and can be recommended for a
home game where spare is verv limited.
The net is shorter and higher. The short
service line is 6 feet 6 inches from the net.
The base line is 15 feet t> inches farther
back on either side. The net itself is 16
feet long and 5 feet high in the middle.
In the play a shuttlecock is used in
stead of the white ball used in ten
nis. This is made of rubber and
feathered to steady its (light. Ordinary
tennis rackets are used instead of the ola
faehioned "battledores." The game is, in
fact, a sort of cross between lawn tennis
and the older game, and is said to be the
invention of an English officer in India,
who found the climate too hot for ten
nis. Perhaps that is the reason why old
tennis players call badminton a lazy peo-
Sle's When such sturdy at hletes as
[amihon Cary and .Stanley Mortimer and
such clever tennis experts as Miss Annie
Webb, Miss Turnure, Miss Minturn and
Miss Elsie Mitchell play and enjoy thgame, however, it can safely he assumed
that, there is plenty of exercise in it.
The rules of badminton are so simple
that they can be summarized in a para
graph. There is no authoritative Ameri
can body like the National Tennis Associ
ation, but the English rules are used:
The sides toss for choiceof ends or service
before the first game of a match, and change
to the other sideof the netafter each game.
The single-handed and double-handed
game consists of fifteen ares. At "13 all,"
the side which first reaches thirteen has
the option of "setting^'five; at 14 all, of
setting three. In three-handed or four-
handed jrames the game consists of twenty
one aces. First set is at 19 all; second at
20 all. A fault made by a player whose
I side is in puts a baud out; if made by a
j player whose side is out it counts an afe to
i the in side. It is a fault if the service is
I "overhand"; if the rirs-t part of the path of
the shuttlecock is inclined downward ;if the
service falls into the wrong court; if the ser
vice falls short of the service line or outside
the bounding line; unless both the server's
teet are in his own court; if the shuttle
cock falls outside the bounds of the court;
if the shuttlecock does not pass between
the posts, or if it pass under or through
tiie net or touch anything except the bat
of the striker, or the top of the net if the
shuttlecock !>e hit twice intentionally by
tiie same player; if the shuttlecock be
struck before it crosses the striker's side of
i the net; if the striker touch the net or its
supports with his racket or otherwise,
i The player in the right-hand court com
mencea the game by serving to the plaver
in the adverse right-hand oourt; if tfiat
leaver return the shuttlecock, it must be
hit ack by the in side and then returned
by the out side till a fault is made by one
j side or the other. The game is continued
in this manner, count being chanced after
j each ace ;s made. The service lines nre
disregarded alter the serve is returned,
j Iho innings always begin with the player
j in the right-hand court, and serves arc
i made alternately from each court into the
one d. t.; iia.lv opposite. In two. three
and tour-handed games, the side begin
ning a game has only one hand in its nrst
innings if there are two a side, and only
two hands if there are three a side. Inatwo
h and el game only the ptrson served to may
take a serve; not so in a three or four
handed game. The service must not begin
till the opponent is ready, but any attempt
to return is taken to indicate readiness.
Any unforseen or accidental hindrance
may be given by a "let" bv the umpire on
appeal from either side "before the next
service commences or before the players
have changed sides at the end of a game.
A "let" cannot be claimed it" an attempt
I ha* been made to strike the shuttlecock
Pitiably the next winter there will be a
badminton association iu this country r or
the new game may he taken under the
l government of the tennis association.
Magistrate (severely^â€”Why 'id
drive through the crowded thu fhfarea
at the rate of t:!teen miles an htur? I>o
you tlunk that the streets belong o you?
Culprit (earnestly protesting >-B_it,yg(Ur
honor, 1 drm a beer wagon.
PLAN OF A BADMINTON OOt'P.T.
A GAME OF BADMINTON</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-10-04/ed-1/?sp=8&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Champion Badanlatoa Tennla Playara,
Th Badminton lawn tennla axpert yesterday mo
eeeded In capturing both of the sterling silver trophies
In th recently formed Inter-Club Tennis Association of
King county. The scoresi
Gentlemen' Single Flnt round: B, IV Booecek,
Knickerbocker Field Club, forfeited to A. 8. Mertam,
Badminton Tennis Club; Dr. W.N. Fraser. King County
Tennis Club, beat B. 8. Ueltcamp, Altlora" Tennis Club,
e 8, ft 0; E. L. Heltrarap, Altlora T. C, beat A. Fransl
ola, Knickerbocker Field: Club, 82, 84: C. E. Mao
Mabon, Badminton T. C, beat A. G. McGowan. King
County T. C, 84. 80; A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T.
C, beat Dr. B.O. Fraser, Kings County T. C, 03, 08,
78.
Second Round K. L. Ileltkatnp, Altlora T. 0, beat O.
E. MacMabon. Badminton, T. O. 76. 88: A. 8. Mer
lam, Badminton. T. C, beat Dr. B, 0, Fraxer, Kings
County T. C tt-4, 68. 7-6.
Final Round A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T. C, defeated
L. lleltkamp. Alt.ora T. C. 0-0. 7-6, 82.
Gentlemen' Double, First Round E. H. Payne and
H. E. McGowan, King County T. C. beat E. L. llelt
kamp and H. B. lleltkamp. ARortaT. C, 8-8, 6-3: A.
8. Merlam and C. E. MarMahon. Badminton T. C. beat
K.H.Lou and Harry Wall. Knickerbocker Field Club,
fl 01; Harry rranclola and William Boocock.
Knickerbocker Field Club, beat J. 8, Jones and John U.
Rollins, Altlora T. C..H-0. 68,81; Dr. R.O. Prater
and F. M, Pendrelgh. Kings County T. C beat Dr. V. A.
Griffiths and O. N. Hchmtdt, BadmlntonT. C, 8-2, 8-0.
Heeond Round E. M. Payne and II. E. McOowan.
Kings County T. C were beaten by A. S. Merlam and C,
R. MacMabon. Badminton T.C., O 2. 2-fl, 0-4: Harry
Pransclola and William Boocock, Knickerbocker Field
Club, were defeated by Dr. W. N. Fraser and F, M. Pen
drelgh, Kings County T. C, 8-8, rt-O.
Final Round Dr. Prater and F. M. Fendrelgb. King
County T. c., were beaten by A. 8. Merlam and c E.
MacMabon, Badmldton T. C 13-11. 810, 67, 0-1,
68.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-10/ed-1/?sp=45&q=Badminton&st=text&r=-0.397,-0.047,1.795,1.795,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GAME OF BADMINTON
I Copyright by James Elver son
ITTS^~ ADAITNTON was invented,' or orig
|J Ij inatcd, whichever you please, in
I !*â€¢"*_ England, but owes its present rules
RtjlSSSfj to the Ahmedabad Badminton Club,
Mvlfilr" o f India, which has practically re
vived the sport. It is a modification
of lawn tennis, with some important differ
ences, as will be seen further on, and has the
advantage that it can be,- and generally is,
played indoors. This makes it both a sum
mer and winter game.
The dimensions of the court Imuit be de
cided in a grjfat measure by the j capabilities
of the room in, which the game lis played.
The best size ii one 28 feet long- by 20 feet
broad. The courts should be marked off by
means of pegs and strings, 'or better, when,
possible, by white chalk lines jon j the floor,
and divided in the following way: At each
end of the ground axe two courts. L jlO feet
square, while the centre is formed by a piece
of neutral ground 8 feet broad by 20 feet long.
On each of the outer lines of the neutral
I ground and in the centre are placed the posts
which support the net. .C-
The net, which is 2 feet to 2l2 l feet 6 inches
deep, is suspended at a height of 6 feet from
the ground, and firmly held by. guy ropes at
i tached to posts. ,y L
1 The racquets used in Badminton, to be easily
and quickly wielded, should be lighter than
those used in lawn tennis, and consequently
smaller. A shuttlecock is used instead of a
ball, and may be large or small, accorum" to
the 'wish of the players. .7 .1
In its general; line, Badminton is a game
played in the same fashion': as lawn tenni*,
with the exception that from one to four
persons may play on a side, and that the shut
tlecock must be returned on the volley. -_â€¢
The shuttlecock is served and returned
under the same provisions, except that, of
i course if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
it is counted as a miss to. the player missing
it and to his side." The service shall be from
the "service-corner," the server I and receiver
each standing with both feet within their
respective quadrants until the shuttlecock v
struck.
The divisions of the respective courts are
only observed in the serve or first hit; after
that the partners may 1 stand where they
please, on their side of the Â¦net....
The shuttlecock must be served in Mich a
wav that it falls clear over the net. without
touching the net, ropes or posts, and falls in
ide the lines of the service court.
If the net is touched m service and the
shuttlecock falls over, the stroke is oonsid
i BOYS AND GIRLS MAGAZINE SECTION
At tltc first tfelfOi 'crawAe&6>r J fyr/ffÂ£ Jttf/a /}&3&7ered 38 a "let," and does not count us a fault
against tbe person serving.
In play, however, the touching of the net
by the shuttlecock, when it falls over, is
counted as good stroke.
If the net is touched by the racquets of the
players, or if they reach over the neÂ£_ with
their racquets, the stroke counts against
them.
Two faultf puts "hand out." In all cases
a shuttlecock falling on any of the boundary
lines is regarded as a fault, as if it had fallen
outside of the boundary lines, both in service
and play.
Fifteen points constitute the game. In ser
vice no overhand stroke is allowed.
The shuttlecock is judged by where it strikes
and not by where it lies after striking.
In judging whether a player has reached
ever the net, the umpire should be careful to
note if the shuttlecock is struck before it
has crossed the net and not by the racquet of
the player, which is naturally carried forward
by the impetus of the stroke and which might
arrive at a slight angle over the net. although
the -shuttlecock itself was struck fairly on the
correct side.
If, however, the net is touched by the
racquet the stroke counts against the player,
whether the shuttlecock was struck on the
right side of the net or not.
As will be st%n from the description, Bad
minton requires agility and a quick eye, rather
than great strength, and it will be found to
be a game at which girls can play with pleas
ure and profit.
DIGNITY AMD IMPITDPNCe'</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-05-23/ed-1/?sp=29&q=badminton&r=-0.006%2C0.051%2C1.367%2C0.728%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BADMINTON TENNIS CLUB
HOLDS FIRST DAY'S PLAY
SANTA MONICA, May 22.â€”The
newly formed Badminton Tennis club
held its Brit play today on the Third
street courts. The club is the offshoot
of the Badminton dub, which held
sway last season, and Includes some
of the best racquet wlelders of South
ern California.
Among thus,- who will bi seen on
id, i club (milts this season are Mrs.
i; i,. Warring, the Mlssea Archer,
Miss Ryan, Miss Marshall, Miss Rower,
lliss Nettleshlp and Mrs. Bruce.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-03-28/ed-1/?sp=23&q=badminton&r=0.397,0.692,0.549,0.292,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Will Boom Badminton
j The Badminton Club, of New York,
an organization established in 1878,
I which has continuously since that time
I tried to foster and develop the game of
I badminton in this city, will hold 07;
I Saturday, March 27, an intercity tour?
nament with Caines Badminton Club.
I of Boston. There will be four matches
of men's singles, three women's sin-j
gles, two men's doubles, one women's
doubles and three mixed doubles. I
Ford-ham Nine
To Open Season
Next Thursday
Infield Presents Only Seri?
ons Problem for Coach;
Strong Pitching Staff</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1902-06-09/ed-1/?sp=6&q=badminton&r=-0.021,0.278,1.034,0.551,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Badminton Threatens
Ping Pongâ€™s VoQiie j
Badminton Is coming Into vogue again
In a way that promises to lay ping pong
on the shelf as a society game. English
social lights, which took so devotedly to
ping pong have begun to serve notice that
Badminton is in better taste, and a so
cial organ says of the game, â€œBadminton
can be played out of doors, on a lawn or
on a carriage drive, or indoors in a
large room. Two, three, four, six or
eight may play at once. The best game,
however, is six, when there are two wom
en up at each side of the net while a
man keeps back behind them. The game, j
as might be expected, derived its name
from the fact that it was first introduced j
in England by a member of a house par- j
ty at Badminton in the time of the late I
Duke of Beaufort.
Sober tennis players who had scorned
ping pong as something immeasurably
less than tennis may incline toward Bad
minton, though it, too, may be reduced
to indoor quarters. For. with the excep
tion of the balls used. Badminton is ten
nis. its plays and scores being observed
according to the same rules, and only
the lack of the rebounding quality in the
bails differing from tennis.
The ball used is the shuttlecock that
goes with the game of battledore. It is a
ball of cork, weighted with lead, or it
may be hard rubber, and in either case
it is winged with feathers, which causes
the ball to revolve, at the same time
flying swiftly, guided by the feather
wings. As the ball will not rebound when
striking the earth or floor, it must be
â€œvolleyed," and each failure to return
the ball is counted against the player
who misses.
For playing Badminton the best court 1
is 28 feet long and 20 feet wide, with the; j
service line ten feet from the base line.
A net one foot deep is stretchd across
the court five and a half feet above the
ground.
Only in the fact that these hard balls j
are winged, do not rebound, and have to I
be â€œvolleyed,â€ does the game differ from
tennis. In this volleying, however, is the
tension and strained interest for both
player and spectator, and as a rival for
ping pong it looks as if society needed
only to pass the word to effect the
change.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020645/1902-06-12/ed-1/?sp=10&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>CITY LEAGUE BALL OPENS
IN EARNEST SATURDAY
__
Falcons and Independents Will Line Up for a Re
cord-breaking Game of Ball on That
Bay-Sporting Melange.
When Ed Mahoney calls "play ball
Saturday afternoon the Inaugural game
of the new City League, an organUatim
that promises to be the most Â»uccewful
of the hind Montgomery has ever haa.
Will be on. The indication* arc that
there will bo a record breaWng crowd
for. aside from the fact that It is the
first of the league games the two teams,
the Falcons and Independents, are both
verv popular with a large following, both
making great reputations in the baseball
line last summer.
The patrons of the game will find
grounds, grand stand and bleachers n
as sehlpshape order as if professional nail
was being played. Yesterday a set of reg
ulation basts and a regulation rubber
borne plate were received. U
few people are aware of thefaettbat
the 190- home plate is responsible for the
phenomenal games being put up' W
pitchers in the different professional
leagues. The plate this season, instead
Iff being S'tuare is a kind of a triangle
and instead of a 12-inch front faring the
pin her It is 17 inches. I his gives the
pitcher five inches more play and he haa
all aorta of chances to cut the corners, a
great advantage to the man in the box
and a corresponding disadvantage to the
batter.
The street railway company yesterday
morning sent a big roller and mower out
to the grounds and President. Screws
had the infield thoroughly rolled and
packed and the grass in the outfield cu%
out. The street railway people are re
pairing the fences, wire-netting in the
grandstand and everything else that
needs repairs. They say that they will
have all the cars needed to take any kind
of crowd out to the games and bring
them home comfortably. A substantial
stand was being built yesterday for the
Infirmary Aid and will he ready by Sat
urday's game
One hour's hard practice a day has been
put in all this week by the Falcons and
Independents, and when they get on the
field Saturday both teams will be in the
pink of condition. After Saturday s game
the next league game will probably be
between the Gersts and Millers, the game
to be played for the benefit of the Confed
erate Soldiers' Home at Mountain Creek,
he President will be glad to heard from
ensacola. Columbus and any of the out
f-town teams.
The Memphis Commercial-Appeal has
the following:
Those who invested in the future pay
or play betting on the American Derby,
bai king Abo Frank. G. C. Bennettâ€™s colt
to win that classic, had just as well make
up their minds to part with the amounts
they wagered. Abe Frank has raced in a
manner since leaving Memphis to cause
a majority of those who backed him at
long odds during the winter to abandon
inv idea of cashing their bets for the
American Derby. There are still a few.
however, that cling to the adage of
"where there is life there is hope.
A letter received here yesterday from
G. C .Bennett says that Abe Frank has
started in his last IVrhy. He will not be
imong the field that faces the starter
n the American Derby a week from next
Saturday, and he will never be sent after
mother Derby. Mr. Bennett draws the
line on Derbies now and will go after :i
ear-old stakes, which are not featured
is Derbies.
The determination of Bennett to keep
Abe Frank out of the American Derby
will cause much tearing of tickets It:
Memphis. The colt received a liberal
,(Mount Â«Â»f backing during the wintei
when Hi odds wore offered at 10 to 1
Mr. Bennett holds tickets aggregatinj
Jl.oOft. which are now nothing but sum
mcr souvenirs of the winter Americai
Derby favorite.
Two big races will be run Saturday. th<
Suburban Handicap it Sheepshead pa;
md the St. Louis Derby.
This ear's St. Louis Derby will b<
one of the m Â»"t valuable year-old stake
decided Â«>n the American turf this sea
sou with thÂ®. exception of the Lawrenc
Realisation and the American Derby. The
Iaiwrenee Realisation, which is run at
Coney Island. *s worth about $30,000. while
the American Dert>y at Washington Park
has $20,000 added. The at. Louis Derby
will be worth about $15,000. This makes
It more valuable than either the Brook
lyn or Suburban handicaps. The 8t. Louis
Derby is a tjfie-honorcd classic with an
exceedingly Interesting history. It was
established in 1882. the year the present
Fair Grounds track was thrown open to
the public. B. C. Pate's Monogram won
the first St. Louis Derby, which was
worth $1,975 to the winner. In 1892 the
stake was abolished, but in 1896 was re
vived again under a different name, being
known as the National Derby. Prince
Lief won the stake in 1896. It had a
guaranteed value of $20,000 that year. In
1897 the stake was rechristened the St.
Louis Derby. It was worth $10,000 and
was captured by Ornament. John W.
Schorr has taken the last two Derbies,
with Sam Phillips in 1900 and Silverdale
in 1901. He will not have a starter this
year.
An Eastern tipster whose system is
"play the long shots.â€ advises against
the first choices by calling attention to
the downfall of favorites In 1901 and 1902
as follows:
In 1901:
Metropolitan. Starbright, 2 to 1. Lost.
Brooklyn Handicap. Banaster. 8 to 5,
Nit.
Suburban Handicap. Ethelbert, 7 to 6.
Trut.
Brighton Handicap, Alceds. 2 to 1,
Foozeled.
Futurity. Nasturtium. 2 to 1. No score.
Realization. Commando, 1 to 10. Got
the rinky-dink.
In 1902:
Carter Handicap, Himself, 7 to 5.
Dumped.
Metropolitan, Herbert. Down and out.
Withers. 0*4 Epgland. 2 to 1. Didnâ€™t.
Belmont, Compute, 2 to 1. Flung high
and dry.
Jockey Club Stakes, Heno, 7 to 10.
Went wrong.
Brooklyn Handicap. Advance Guard, 2
to 1. Hard luck.
English Derby, Scepter, 7 to 2. Too
much touting.
Badminton is coming Into vogue again
in a way that promises to lay ping pong
on the shelf air a society game. English
social lights, which took so devotedly to
ping pong, have begun to serve notice
that Badminton is in better taste, and a
social organ says of the game: â€œBad
minton can be played out of doors, on
a lawn or on a carriage drive, and in
doors in a large room. Two. three, four,
six or eight may play at once. The game,
however, is six. when there are two wo
men up at each side of the net while a
man keeps back behind them. The game,
as might be expected, derived its name
from the fart that it was first intro
duced in England by a member of a
house,.party at Badminton in the time
of the late Duke of Beaufort.â€
Sober tennis players who have scorned
ping pong as sometimes immeasurably
less than tennis may incline towards
Badminton, though it. too, nay he re
duced to indoor quirters. For. with the
exception of the balls used. Badminton is
tennis. Its plays and scores being oh
served according to the same rules, an-1
only the lack of the rebounding quality
in the balls differing from tennis.
The ball used is the shuttlecock that
goes with the gamr of battledore. It is a
ball of cork, weighted with lead, or it
may he hard robber, and in either case it
is winged with feathers, which causes
the hall to revolve, at the same time
flying swiftly, guided by, th$ feather
wings. As the ball will not rebound when
striking the earth or floor, it must be
â€œvolleyed.â€ and each failure to return
the ball is counted against the player
who misses.
Only in the fact that these hard halls
are winged, do not rebound, and have to
be "volleyed.â€ does the game dffTer from
tennis. Tn this volleying, however, is the
tension and strained interest for both
played and spectator, and as a rival for
ping pong it looks as 1f society needed
only to pass the word to effect the
change.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84027524/1950-01-27/ed-1/?sp=8&q=badminton&r=-0.028%2C-0.044%2C1.215%2C0.647%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Wants State Badminton
Association Revived
Interested in a state badminton
association is the Sunburst Bad
minton club.
Objective of the association
would be to promote and develop
the game, assist in the organiza
tion of clubs, conduct a state tour
nament and assist junior clubs and
school clubs.
There was a state badminton as
sociation before the war. The last
state tournament was held in Lew
istown in 1943.
The Sunburst Badminton club is
holding their 15th annual tourna
ment February 19. Persons inter
ested in either the tournament, the
state association or the game
should notify Jim Greer, Sunburst.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92073229/1940-03-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=badminton&r=0.363%2C0.836%2C0.865%2C0.46%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Badminton Chief
N. B. Adam* Elected President of
New Sports Organisation
N. B. Adams, professor of
Spanish in the University, was
elected president of the Chapel
Hill Badminton Club Monday
evening at a meeting at the Caro
lina Sport Shop. Other officers
elected were Mrs. P. S. Randolph,
vice-president; D. P. Henry, sec
retary and G. T. Goebbel, treas
urer.
About 30 persons attended the
meeting, and many more have in
quired about the plans of the
new c)ub.
It wad decided to hold matches
from 7 to 9:80 every Tuesday
and Thursday evenings in the
gymnasium at the elementary
school. Everybody interested in
playing badminton is myited to
take part.
Mr. Henry said yesterday that
facilities for badminton in the
school gymnasium are among the
best in the state.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1940-07-05/ed-1/?sp=7&q=badminton&st=text&r=-0.403,0.543,1.805,1.805,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Iftiday, July S' 1940
m
B,y E FREEMAN COMING
V tennis champ
I Last week we told you some-
B |rr 0 f the 19-year-old Jewish
player from the Coast who
being groomed as a forthcom-
M Davis Cup Star. Weâ€™ve more
K lay on the line for you today
â– onceming the technique and abi-
K v 0 f this Pomona College soph-
Kore who ranked twenty-second
Hjthe national listings last sea
ion and who looms as another
Kne Lacoste. (Lacoste, you will
â– ecall, has been the only Jewish
Bonis player on any Davis Cup
HFreeman reached the tennis
Bourts through a thoroughly nat-
Bral route. His rapid rise to fame
Brngresses from ping pong to bad-
Binton to tennis in six short
Bears. At the age of 13 he won a
â– ew small trophies as a table ten-
Bis menace. By the time he was
Seventeen, only two years ago, he
B-as garnering gold and silver tro-
Bhies. He has more than a hun-
Bed cups.
I But table tennis was childâ€™s
Blay and Dave turned to badmin-
Bon as more strenuous fare. (If
Bouâ€™ve never played this sportâ€”
Bhich is rapidly becoming a fav-
Brite winter indoor pastimeâ€”get
Bt out of your heads that itâ€™s a sis-
Byâ€™s game. It's strenuous, fast,
Bad requires plenty of skilL Some
Bonsider it more arduous than ten-
Bb.)
kl And it was only two years ago
Bhat Dave came out of the West
Bn unknown quantity at this game
MYRTLE AVENUE
LUMBER CO.
Lumber and Building
Supplies
Myrtle Ave. at Elm St
Phene 5-4260
BONO
CLEANERS Mid DYERS
WE CALL AND DELIVER
til Garments Fully Protected
By Insurance
Phone 3-9254 1005 Forest St.
SANDWICH INN
MAIN AT 27TH
PARK AT GILMORE
MIAMI ROAD IN
SO. JACKSONVILLE
Ride Safety With Safety
Safetp Cabo, Inc.
6-7890 X IOC
Authorized and Bonded
_ BAGGAGE TRANSFER
I! CAN. BE DONE
\g&
A "o WE CAN DO IT
There will be no repaired
appearance to your shoes.
A neat, smooth job from
toe to heeL
u Modem methods plus
Steerhead" Sole Leather
do the trick.
Let us prove it
LÂ°msSHOE SHOP
028 Pearl St. Phone 5-2986
We Appreciate your Patronage
POWELLâ€™S LITTLE FOLK* FURNITURE
â€œBABY FIRST*'
827 LAURA STREET
WE FEATURE THE LAY-AWAY FLAN
JEWS IN
SPORTS
ly Morris Weiner
and a kid who was beginning to
show an aptitude with the tennis
racket. At that time, in tourna
ments in Philadalphia, those who
watched him closely were con
vinced that they saw symptoms of
excellence.
Last year, while still a junior
performer, this Pasadena young
ster returned to New York. On
that occasion there was no un
certainty about his high-geared
play at badminton. He had ironed
out the rough spots, profiting by
his knowledge that tennis had
yielded him in the National junior
championships at Culver, Indiana.
He won the junior title two years
ago and last year was succeeded
by his chief rival on the Pacific
Coast, Ted Shroeder.
No other American performer
with the tennis racket and bad
minton bat has ever scaled the
heights Freeman has attained. He
was a star of the first magnitude
in the national badminton cham
pionships in New York last year.
His blend of tennis and badmin
ton was smooth, according to the
experts, and in the recent shut
tlecock championship at Seattle
Freeman was the whole show, ta
king no fewer than three national
championships.
He is so strong at both games
that the Californian looms as the
overpowering force in any cham
pionship at either game. It is al
so interesting to observe that
Freeman trounced Hank Prusoff
at badminton in the latterâ€™s home
town, thereby retaliating for the
defeat suffered at Forest Hills
last season at the hands of the
lad who went on to rate thirteenth
in the Nationals.
....By the way, the record books
also reveal that Davis Freeman is
the first Californian who has
achieved the highest honor in this
respect. He has made a record at
badminton which few can equal
and which only one other player
in the country has been able to
equal thus far. Freeman made
grand slam in singles and doubles.
The only player to do that hith
erto was Mrs. Del Barkhuff then
of Seattle and now of Honolulu,
who did the triple victory back in
1937, when this national event
was inaugurated in Chicago.
At a recent badminton tourna
ment, Dave was awarded the top
seeding, as champion, in singles,
He took that event with scarcely
any formidable opposition, suc
cesfully defending his crown as
there was no opponent capable of
taking him into camp.
And here you have the reasons
for it. Heâ€™s amazingly fast on
his feet, quick of anticipation and
durable for a long session. Speed,
stamina and sense three prere
quisites of the tennis player.
Freeman has made it evident
that he has what it takes in bad
minton and tennis to rate as a na
tional champion and to justify his
sponsorâ€™s predictions that in him
we have a future Davis Cup play
er and what is more the first Jew
ish Davis Cup player in America.
Judge Hardy, former interna
tional Davis Cup team captain,
who is pushing Daveâ€™s tennis as
pirations wrote in the U. S. Lawn
Tennis Journal only last month:
â€œFreeman has shown remark
able ability to round out his ten
nis stronkes. This makes him par
ticularly dangerous in the fore
court, repeatedly turning defen-</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025812/1931-11-13/ed-1/?sp=12&q=badminton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Badminton'* Origin
The game of badminton, in crA
form, wns first played in India.w
was called poonit after th* t0l|
In which It originated. It
brought to England in 1S72 l?y?w.
lsh army officers and in 1ST.
Darned badminton in honor o'.t^
duke of Beaufort, at whose
Badminton, the game wns form*
Introduced.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78002169/1942-05-28/ed-1/?sp=3&q=badminton&r=0.032%2C0.108%2C0.92%2C0.49%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Game Of Badminton
Takes Camp Davis
Personnel By Storm
Badminton, originated by British
army officers in India 98 years
ago, has taken Camp Davis by
storm. Scores of soldiers are play
ing the game every night in the
week, making use of the courts at
Farnsworth Hall.
The craze has gained such im
petus that it has been necessary
to move the bleachers in the sports
arena to make room for additional
courts.
The athletic office loans out
rackets and sells the birds, or shut,
tlecocks at cost to the players.
Similar to tennis, badminton is
played with lighter rackets and in
stead of a ball the shuttlecock is
used.
The shuttlecock is made of feath
ers inserted and cemented in a
half sphere of cork. Object of the
game is to keep the â€œbirdâ€ in
the air. Nets, higher than those
used in tennis, are strung across
the badminton courts.
Among the officers of Camp Da
vis who can be classed (more or
less) as experts at badminton are
Major J. B. Yost; Lieut. R. F.
Bailey, and Lieut H. A. Johnson.</text>
      </result>


    </results>
  </topic>





  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
